<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://www.data-is-plural.com</id>
  <title>Data Is Plural</title>
  <updated>2021-12-22T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Singer-Vine</name>
    <email>jsvine@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://www.data-is-plural.com" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-12-22</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.12.22 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-12-22T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Tobacco habits, working hours, COVID-19 in European prisons, California water wells, and toothbrushing.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tobacco habits.</strong> Every few years since 1992, the <a href="https://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/">National Cancer Institute</a> has sponsored the <a href="https://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/brp/tcrb/tus-cps">Tobacco Use Supplement to the Current Population Survey</a>, <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/cps/about/supplemental-surveys.html">administered by the US Census Bureau</a>. In addition to extensive demographic information, the supplement asks about historical tobacco usage (“Have you smoked at least 100 cigarettes in your entire life?”), preferences (“Do you usually smoke menthol or non-menthol cigarettes?”), purchasing habits, e-cigarettes, and much more. Anonymized responses and documentation <a href="https://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/brp/tcrb/tus-cps/questionnaires-data">are available</a> for all survey waves through 2018–19. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="http://www.cdc.gov/brfss/">The CDC’s Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2016-09-14-edition/">DIP 2016.09.14</a>). [h/t <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34644338/">Christian Gunadi et al.</a> + <a href="https://www.nationalaffairs.com/blog/detail/findings-a-daily-roundup/unhealthy-lifestyles">Kevin Lewis</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Working hours.</strong> Political scientist <a href="https://www.magnusbrasmussen.com/">Magnus Bergli Rasmussen</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/RasmussenMagnus/status/1465629029982158848">compiled data</a> on the regulation of laborers’ total work hours in nearly every country since 1789, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ie1zvkr7iht2i1j/public_workingtimedata.dta?dl=0">available as a Stata file</a>. For each year and territory, the dataset indicates whether such laws existed, the “normal” number of contractually-obligated weekly hours, the maximum number of hours allowed, and increases in pay for overtime. <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/356063579_The_Great_Standardization_Working_Hours_around_the_World">The Great Standardization: Working Hours Around the World</a>,” in which Rasmussen describes the dataset’s construction.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 in European prisons.</strong> A collaboration coordinated by <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/data/t-43091100">Deutsche Welle</a> and the <a href="https://www.europeandatajournalism.eu/eng/News/Data-news/How-Europe-s-prisons-have-fared-in-the-Covid-19-pandemic">European Data Journalism Network</a> has <a href="https://github.com/dw-data/covid-prisons">gathered data</a> on <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/covid-how-europes-prisons-have-fared-in-the-pandemic/a-60006262">the pandemic’s impact on prisoners and prison staff in dozens of European countries</a>, including the number of COVID-19 tests, cases, and deaths over time. The data also note the types of preventative measures and vaccine policies in place. <strong>Previously</strong>: US prison COVID-19 data from the <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/COVID_prison_data">Marshall Project and AP</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2020-05-06-edition/">DIP 2020.05.06</a>) and the <a href="https://github.com/nytimes/covid-19-data/tree/master/prisons">New York Times</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-04-21-edition/">DIP 2021.04.21</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/lorferr">Lorenzo Ferrari</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>California water wells.</strong> Domestic wells in the San Joaquin Valley “are drying up at an alarming pace” amid “a frenzy of new well construction and heavy agricultural pumping,” according to a <a href="https://www.latimes.com/projects/california-farms-water-wells-drought/">Los Angeles Times article last week</a>. Data reporter <a href="https://twitter.com/lamarr_lemee">Gabrielle LaMarr LeMee</a>’s <a href="https://github.com/datadesk/groundwater-analysis">analysis</a> provides the quantitative backbone, drawing on three state datasets: <a href="https://data.cnra.ca.gov/dataset/well-completion-reports">well completion reports</a> and <a href="https://data.cnra.ca.gov/dataset/periodic-groundwater-level-measurements">periodic groundwater level measurements</a>, both of which go back more than a century, and <a href="https://data.ca.gov/dataset/household-water-supply-shortage-reporting-system-data">household water supply shortage reports</a> since 2013.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Toothbrushing.</strong> <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340921005321">Zawar Hussain et al.</a> recorded data from 120 electric and manual toothbrushing sessions, using sensors attached to the brush handle and brusher’s wrist. Each session’s <a href="https://data.mendeley.com/datasets/hx5kkkbr3j/">data files</a> trace the sensors’ positions over time and indicate the brush type, participant’s gender, age, and handedness, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send dentist-approved feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-12-22-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Tobacco habits, working hours, COVID-19 in European prisons, California water wells, and toothbrushing.</summary>
    <published>2021-12-22T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-12-15</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.12.15 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-12-15T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Faster-turnaround mortality data, zero-day exploits, reproductive assistance in the EU, country leaders’ birthplaces, and 1 million Bandcamp sales.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Faster-turnaround mortality data.</strong> Last week, the CDC began publishing <a href="https://wonder.cdc.gov/mcd-icd10-provisional.html">provisional US mortality statistics for 2018 to the near-present</a>. The data are <a href="https://wonder.cdc.gov/wonder/help/mcd-provisional.html">based on death certificates</a> and can be queried by location, timing, demographics, and causes of death. They’re similar to the CDC’s <a href="https://wonder.cdc.gov/mcd.html">non-provisional statistics for earlier years</a>, but “with a lag of just a few weeks” instead of more than a year, <a href="https://coviddatadispatch.com/2021/12/12/new-cdc-mortality-data-real-time-public-health-surveillance-at-a-highly-granular-level/">writes</a> the <a href="https://coviddatadispatch.com/">COVID-19 Data Dispatch</a>’s <a href="https://betsyladyzhets.com/">Betsy Ladyzhets</a>. <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://www.muckrock.com/news/archives/2021/dec/09/the-cdc-just-released-new-data-on-deaths-in-the-us/">Researchers say the US is undercounting COVID deaths. Now we have a tool to figure out why</a>,” an article by Ladyzhets and other members of <a href="https://documentingcovid19.io/about">Documenting COVID-19</a>, who are <a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_PxEsCSn9SeqkFn-xQu37DA">hosting a webinar</a> about the data today.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Zero-day exploits.</strong> Researchers at Google’s <a href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/p/about-project-zero.html">Project Zero</a> study “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero-day_(computing)">zero-day</a>” vulnerabilities — software flaws discovered by hackers before they can be fixed. Since 2019, the team <a href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/p/0day.html">has published</a> a <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1lkNJ0uQwbeC1ZTRrxdtuPLCIl7mlUreoKfSIgajnSyY/view#gid=0">spreadsheet of known zero-day exploits</a> “in the wild.” The spreadsheet’s 200 entries go back to 2014 and note the software product, its vendor, the flaw’s type and description, date discovered, date patched, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://cve.mitre.org/">The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures list</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-12-12-edition/">DIP 2018.12.12</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/09/23/1036140/2021-record-zero-day-hacks-reasons/">Patrick Howell O’Neill</a> + <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2021/09/the-proliferation-of-zero-days.html">Bruce Schneier</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Reproductive assistance in the EU.</strong> Reporters at <a href="https://civio.es/en/about-us/">Civio</a> have collected data on the <a href="https://datos.civio.es/dataset/acceso-a-la-reproduccion-asistida-en-europa/">access to</a>, and <a href="https://datos.civio.es/dataset/reproduccion-asistida-que-costea-la-sanidad-publica-en-europa/">availability of financial aid for</a>, in vitro fertilization and artificial insemination in 43 European countries, noting limits based on age, marital status, sexual orientation, gender identity, and other factors. <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://civio.es/medicamentalia/2021/11/02/ART-EU-access/">More than half of European countries prohibit access to assisted reproduction for lesbians and almost a third do so for single women</a>.” <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://observablehq.com/collection/@civio/619-art-eu">Civio’s visualization code in Observable notebooks</a>. [h/t <a href="https://unavezalmes.substack.com/p/agricultura-intensiva-madres-vetadas">Olaya Argüeso Pérez</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/mf_viz">Mike Freeman</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Country leaders’ birthplaces.</strong> <a href="http://www.axel-dreher.de/Spouses.pdf">Axel Dreher et al.</a>’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi%3A10.7910%2FDVN%2FYUS575">Political Leaders’ Affiliation Database</a> lists the birthplaces and ethnicities of 1,109 leaders of 177 countries between 1989 and 2020. The birthplaces are described at several levels of administrative detail and are ascribed a latitude, longitude, and an indication of those coordinates’ precision. The ethnicities are drawn from external, linked sources. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/simonhhess/status/1448388780294090756">Simon Heß</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>1 million Bandcamp sales.</strong> <a href="https://components.one/">Components</a>’ <a href="https://twitter.com/asthompson">Andrew Thompson</a> has published a <a href="https://components.one/datasets/bandcamp-sales">dataset of 1,000,000 sales</a> on the music platform <a href="https://bandcamp.com/">Bandcamp</a> during a few weeks in late 2020. For each sale, it includes the item’s description, price, and type; the buyer’s country; a timestamp; and more. It’s a slice of the data used in “<a href="https://components.one/posts/bandcamp-the-chaos-bazaar">The Chaos Bazaar: An analysis of Bandcamp sales, 9/1/2020 - 12/31/2020</a>.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send tune-vending feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-12-15-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Faster-turnaround mortality data, zero-day exploits, reproductive assistance in the EU, country leaders’ birthplaces, and 1 million Bandcamp sales.</summary>
    <published>2021-12-15T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-12-08</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.12.08 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-12-08T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Citizenship laws, overturned Supreme Court decisions, birds at the feeder, pandemic-era alcohol policies, and a map of our moon.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Citizenship laws.</strong> The <a href="https://globalcit.eu/">Global Citizenship Observatory</a>’s new <a href="https://globalcit.eu/databases/globalcit-citizenship-law-dataset/">Citizenship Law Dataset</a> “outlines, in a systematic way, 28 ways in which citizenship can be acquired and 15 ways in which citizenship can be lost.” <a href="https://twitter.com/GlobalCIT_EUI/status/1466362913019596803">Launched last week</a> and <a href="https://globalcit.eu/a-new-globalcit-citizenship-law-dataset-what-why-and-how/">building on the observatory’s previous work</a>, it covers the laws in effect in 190 countries in January 2020. For each mode of acquisition or loss in each jurisdiction, the dataset points to the legal citations, specifies the type of procedure (discretionary, automatic, etc.), and describes the relevant conditions (for instance, wedlock requirements for citizenship-by-descent). <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://macimide.maastrichtuniversity.nl/dual-cit-database/">Dual citizenship policies</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2019-01-09-edition/">DIP 2019.01.09</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/GovindYajna/status/1465668160426754050">Yajna Govind</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Overturned Supreme Court decisions.</strong> The Library of Congress’s <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/">Constitution Annotated</a> project is a “comprehensive, government-sanctioned record of the interpretations of the Constitution,” intended for a wide audience and <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/about/constitution-annotated/">in publication for more than 100 years</a>. Its resources include a table of <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/resources/decisions-overruled/">Supreme Court Decisions overruled by subsequent decisions</a>, with the names and years of the initial and overruling cases, and another of <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/resources/unconstitutional-laws/">laws held unconstitutional</a>. <strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/essay/appx-1/ALDE_00000679/">The methodologies for both tables</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://qz.com/2098152/how-often-are-supreme-court-decisions-overturned/">How often are Supreme Court decisions overturned?</a>” (Quartz).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Birds at the feeder.</strong> <a href="https://feederwatch.org/">Project FeederWatch</a> is a “November-April survey of birds that visit backyards, nature centers, community areas, and other locales in North America.” Tens of thousands of <a href="https://feederwatch.org/pfw/participants">volunteers</a> <a href="https://feederwatch.org/about/detailed-instructions/">record</a> the number and species of birds at each feeder, plus information about the surrounding environment. The results can be <a href="https://feederwatch.org/explore/">explored online</a> and <a href="https://feederwatch.org/explore/raw-dataset-requests/">downloaded in bulk</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/11/28/bird-feeder-pecking-order/">Which birds are the biggest jerks at the feeder?</a>” (Washington Post), which uses additional behavioral data <a href="https://feederwatch.org/about/detailed-instructions/#record-behavior-interactions">collected</a> by the volunteers; and a <a href="https://twitter.com/EliotITMiller/status/1465126217133219841">related Twitter thread</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jtemplon">John Templon</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pandemic-era alcohol policies.</strong> The US <a href="https://alcoholpolicy.niaaa.nih.gov/about-apis">Alcohol Policy Information System</a> has <a href="https://alcoholpolicy.niaaa.nih.gov/resource/covid-19/98">categorized the alcohol-related regulations</a> that each state (and DC) has enforced during the COVID-19 pandemic, and how they’ve changed over time. The dataset covers January 2020 to mid-September 2021; it examines restrictions on bar and restaurant capacity, serving alcohol without food, alcohol delivery, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A map of our moon.</strong> A USGS <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/astrogeology-science-center/science/mrctr-gis-lab?qt-science_center_objects=0#qt-science_center_objects">astrogeology lab</a> has built a <a href="https://astrogeology.usgs.gov/search/map/Moon/Geology/Unified_Geologic_Map_of_the_Moon_GIS_v2">1:5,000,000-scale map of Earth’s moon</a>, the “chief purpose” of which is “to summarize the current state of lunar geologic knowledge.” It marks thousands of geologic boundaries, plus “surface features” such as crater rims, “fissures, grabens, scarps, mare wrinkle ridges” and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ShijiaWendy/status/1458242744673996807">Wendy Shijia</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send cratered feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-12-08-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Citizenship laws, overturned Supreme Court decisions, birds at the feeder, pandemic-era alcohol policies, and a map of our moon.</summary>
    <published>2021-12-08T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-12-01</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.12.01 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-12-01T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>The General Index, personal income, banking-crisis interventions, Europe’s primary forests, and Michael Scott misquotes.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Language from 100 million academic articles.</strong> <a href="https://archive.org/details/GeneralIndex">The General Index</a>, a new project from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Malamud">Carl Malamud</a>’s <a href="https://public.resource.org/">Public Resource</a>, contains detailed linguistic data derived from 107,233,728 academic journal articles. The index’s main table contains all one-to-five-word sequences found in each article, and their frequencies — more than 355 billion “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N-gram">n-grams</a>” in total. A second table identifies nearly 20 billion keywords <a href="https://pypi.org/project/yake/">auto-extracted</a> from the corpus, and a third table lists the authors, title, publication date, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier">DOI</a> associated with each article. <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02142-1">The plan to mine the world’s research papers</a>” (Nature, July 2019) and “<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-02895-8">Giant, free index to world’s research papers released online</a>” (Nature, October 2021). [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29008367">webmaven</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Personal income.</strong> The US Bureau of Economic Analysis <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2021/personal-income-county-and-metropolitan-area-2020">has released</a> its latest <a href="https://www.bea.gov/data/income-saving/personal-income-county-metro-and-other-areas">county-level estimates of personal income</a>, which now cover 1969–2020. The per-capita numbers are also available by <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/metro-micro/about.html">metropolitan statistical area</a>, as well as disaggregated by income “component” (wages/salaries, income from assets, etc.) and industry. You can <a href="https://apps.bea.gov/regional/downloadzip.cfm">download the data</a> and also explore it through interactive <a href="https://apps.bea.gov/iTable/iTable.cfm?reqid=70&amp;step=1&amp;acrdn=6">tables</a> and <a href="https://apps.bea.gov/iTable/iTable.cfm?reqid=99&amp;step=1&amp;acrdn=7">maps</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://inclusivewealth.eig.org/wealthmap/">From Wealthy Enclaves to Asset Deserts</a>,” a map and report by the <a href="https://eig.org/about-us">Economic Innovation Group</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Banking-crisis interventions.</strong> Economists <a href="https://faculty.som.yale.edu/andrewmetrick/">Andrew Metrick</a> and <a href="https://www.pfschmelzing.me/">Paul Schmelzing</a> have <a href="https://som.yale.edu/faculty-research-centers/centers-initiatives/program-on-financial-stability/metrick-schmelzing-paper-and-database">compiled a database</a> of 800+ banking crises spanning the years 1257 to 2019, plus 1,800+ government attempts to mitigate them. For each crisis, the database provides the starting year, relevant country or region, a brief description, and more. It also describes the interventions, lists their dates, classifies them into 20 categories (asset guarantees, market liquidity assistance, etc.), and links them to sources and prior literature.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Europe’s primary forests.</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-00988-7">Francesco Maria Sabatini et al.</a> have combined information from <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-00988-7/tables/4">dozens of sources</a> to develop “the most comprehensive dataset” of Europe’s “primary forests” — those “where the signs of human impacts, if any, are strongly blurred due to decades without forest management.” The <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/dataset/European_Primary_Forest_Database/13194095/2">dataset</a>, which includes 18,411 patches across 33 countries, describes their names, locations, level of “naturalness,” dominant tree species, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/sdata2016123">EU-Forest</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2017-01-25-edition/">DIP 2017.01.25</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>“Early worm gets the worm.”</strong> Designer and “diehard Office superfan” <a href="https://www.williamrchase.com/">Will Chase</a> rewatched the US version of the sitcom with one goal in mind: <a href="https://buttondown.email/willchase/archive/a-new-datavizstreaming-project-all-about-the/">to document every misquote, malapropism, mispronunciation, and other verbal flub</a> by Steve Carell’s character Michael Scott. <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/13U09FgnxeW9UyCg7Xwffxj06W47ikUZJng16ukF9mQs/edit#gid=0">He found more than 200</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send Dunder Mifflinesque feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-12-01-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The General Index, personal income, banking-crisis interventions, Europe’s primary forests, and Michael Scott misquotes.</summary>
    <published>2021-12-01T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-11-17</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.11.17 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-11-17T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Carbon credits, foodborne pathogens, violence against environmental defenders, mineral production, and Werner’s Nomenclature of Colours.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Carbon credits.</strong> The <a href="https://gspp.berkeley.edu/faculty-and-impact/centers/cepp/projects/berkeley-carbon-trading-project/offsets-database">Voluntary Registry Offsets Database</a>, a collaboration between the <a href="https://gspp.berkeley.edu/faculty-and-impact/centers/cepp/projects/berkeley-carbon-trading-project">Berkeley Carbon Trading Project</a> and <a href="https://carbon-direct.com/">Carbon Direct</a>, “contains all carbon offset projects, credit issuances, and credit retirements listed globally by four major voluntary offset project registries,” accounting for “almost all of the world’s voluntary market offsets.” Updated in September with data through early May 2021, the database covers 5,000+ projects and 1.2 billion credits issued. Each credit purportedly offsets a metric tonne of CO<sub>2</sub> emissions, but the Berkeley team is skeptical: “Research performed by us and others has found that many, if not most, offset credits traded on the market today do not represent real emissions reductions.” <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://carbonpricingdashboard.worldbank.org/map_data">The World Bank’s database of carbon pricing initiatives</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Foodborne pathogens.</strong> In an <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/how-propublica-used-genomic-sequencing-data-to-track-an-ongoing-salmonella-outbreak">explainer article</a> accompanying a <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/salmonella-chicken-usda-food-safety">recent food-safety investigation</a>, ProPublica reporter <a href="https://www.propublica.org/people/irena-hwang">Irena Hwang</a> describes using her training in bioinformatics to analyze salmonella DNA data collected by the <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">National Center for Biotechnology Information</a>’s <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pathogens/">Pathogen Detection</a> initiative, which <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pathogens/faq/">aggregates genomic sequences</a> from bacteria “originating in food, environmental sources, and patients.” The initiative has <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pathogens/pathogens_help/#data-retrieval">published such data</a> for nearly 1 million samples of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pathogens/organisms/">dozens of species</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/chicken/">ProPublica’s Chicken Checker lookup tool</a>, based on the <a href="https://www.fsis.usda.gov/science-data/data-sets-visualizations/laboratory-sampling-data">results of Department of Agriculture microbiological sampling</a> conducted at processing plants.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Violence against environmental defenders.</strong> <a href="https://tierraderesistentes.com/en/">Tierra de Resistentes</a> is a “crossborder journalistic effort to investigate episodes of violence against leaders and communities in Latin America who have devoted their lives to defending the environment.” The <a href="https://tierraderesistentes.com/es/datos/">collaboration’s database</a> details 2,400+ such attacks, mostly focusing on the years 2009–2019. For each attack, it provides information about the person, organization, or community attacked, the type of violence, the resource defended, case status, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.datasketch.co/newsletter/data-journalism/issue-6-cop26-climate-change-and-biodiversity/">Juan Pablo Marín Díaz</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mineral production.</strong> The US Geological Survey’s <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/nmic">National Minerals Information Center</a> keeps tabs on “minerals and materials essential to the U.S. economy, the national security, and protection of the environment.” Its published datasets include annual statistics on <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/nmic/state-minerals-statistics-and-information">mineral production by state</a>, <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/nmic/international-minerals-statistics-and-information">by country</a>, and <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/nmic/commodity-statistics-and-information">by commodity</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.brianckeegan.com/about/">Brian C. Keegan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Werner’s Nomenclature of Colours.</strong> Data artist <a href="https://www.c82.net/">Nicholas Rougeux</a> has <a href="https://www.c82.net/werner/">digitally recreated</a> Scottish painter <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_Syme">Patrick Syme</a>’s 1821 <a href="https://archive.org/details/gri_c00033125012743312">guidebook</a> to German mineralogist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_Gottlob_Werner">Abraham Werner</a>’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Werner%27s_Nomenclature_of_Colours">color system</a>. For each of the 110 colors, such as <em>Saffron Yellow</em> and <em>Veinous Blood Red</em>, a <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/10w7UebIDqN6ChEpBwLDQmAgVZZhLtKvnrLeNnBjJmsc/edit">corresponding spreadsheet</a> contains its name, hex code, description, and more. [h/t <a href="https://buttondown.email/puntofisso/archive/444-quantum-of-sollazzo/">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send colorful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-11-17-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Carbon credits, foodborne pathogens, violence against environmental defenders, mineral production, and Werner’s Nomenclature of Colours.</summary>
    <published>2021-11-17T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-11-10</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.11.10 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-11-10T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Toxic pollution, campsite reservations, time zones, NFTs, and damn fine coffees.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Toxic pollution.</strong> Last week, ProPublica published what it’s calling “<a href="https://projects.propublica.org/toxmap/">the most detailed map of cancer-causing industrial air pollution in the U.S.</a>,” along with an <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/toxmap-poison-in-the-air">investigation</a> based on the map’s revelations. In a <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/how-we-created-the-most-detailed-map-ever-of-cancer-causing-industrial-air-pollution">methodology article</a>, reporters explain how they analyzed billions of rows of data from the Environmental Protection Agency’s <a href="https://www.epa.gov/rsei">Risk-Screening Environmental Indicators model</a>, which “takes a variety of inputs, including emissions data, weather modeling, and facility specific information, and puts out estimated concentrations of toxic chemicals in the air around industrial facilities.” The EPA <a href="https://www.epa.gov/rsei/ways-get-rsei-results">publishes the model’s output</a> as bulk downloads, in an online dashboard, and in other formats. <strong>Related</strong>: The model incorporates information from the EPA’s <a href="https://www.epa.gov/toxics-release-inventory-tri-program">Toxics Release Inventory</a>, which <a href="https://www.epa.gov/toxics-release-inventory-tri-program/find-understand-and-use-tri">publishes</a> self-reported emissions data from <a href="https://www.epa.gov/toxics-release-inventory-tri-program/tri-threshold-screening-tool">certain mandated industrial facilities</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Campsite reservations.</strong> The US government’s <a href="https://ridb.recreation.gov/">Recreation Information Database</a> “represents an authoritative source of information and services for millions of visitors to federal lands, historic sites, museums, and other attractions/resources.” It provides <a href="https://ridb.recreation.gov/download">bulk data</a> and <a href="https://ridb.recreation.gov/docs">an API</a> describing recreational areas, campgrounds, campsites, permit entrances, scheduled tours, and more. You can also download detailed historical data on individual campsite and tour reservations going back to 2006. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://westernpriorities.org/the-camping-crunch/">The Camping Crunch</a>,” published by the Center for Western Priorities, and <a href="https://westernpriorities.org/the-camping-crunch-data-and-methodology/">accompanying methodology</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/mtmagog/status/1454194628341616641">@mtmagog</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Time zones.</strong> The <a href="https://www.iana.org/time-zones">Time Zone Database</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tz_database">used extensively</a> by major operating systems and programming languages, “contains code and data that represent the history of local time for many representative locations around the globe.” Its files include detailed notes on sourcing and are “updated periodically to reflect changes made by political bodies to time zone boundaries, UTC offsets, and daylight-saving rules.” <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://blog.scottlogic.com/2021/09/14/120-years-timezone.html">Exploring 120 years of timezones</a>,” by <a href="https://colineberhardt.github.io/">Colin Eberhardt</a>. [h/t <a href="https://news.dataelixir.com/t/t-1872322AA740A2372540EF23F30FEDED">Lon Riesberg</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NFTs.</strong> A team <a href="https://github.com/bugout-dev/moonstream">developing open-source tools</a> for monitoring cryptocurrency activity has built a <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/simiotic/ethereum-nfts">dataset of 7 million transactions</a> of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-fungible_token">non-fungible tokens (NFTs)</a> on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum">Ethereum blockchain</a>. The dataset covers April to late September 2021, spans 9,000 NFT projects, and records each transaction’s sender, receiver, value, timestamp, and location in the blockchain. <strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/bugout-dev/moonstream/blob/main/datasets/nfts/papers/ethereum-nfts.pdf">The team’s analysis</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/atbeme/status/1451361968460238851">Ibrahim Ahmed</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Damn fine coffees.</strong> Earlier this year, data visualist <a href="https://juditbekker.com/">Judit Bekker</a> <a href="https://juditbekker.com/2021/05/04/live-blogging-a-new-project/">live-blogged her effort</a> to catalog and <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/judit.bekker/viz/TheCoffeesofTwinPeaks/TheCoffeesofTwinPeaks">visualize</a> every coffee consumed in all three seasons of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin_Peaks">Twin Peaks</a>. Bekker’s <a href="https://data.world/judkacag/the-coffees-of-twin-peaks">dataset</a> indicates the episode, timestamp, scene, location, circumstances of 258 coffee-drinkings, plus who drank them. [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-internal-migration-voting-restrictions-and-sand-604455">Soph Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send Lynchian feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-11-10-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Toxic pollution, campsite reservations, time zones, NFTs, and damn fine coffees.</summary>
    <published>2021-11-10T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-11-03</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.11.03 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-11-03T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Internet shutdowns, concealed carry licensing, Amazon search results, FOIA reading rooms, and spiders.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Internet shutdowns.</strong> A <a href="https://www.accessnow.org/keepiton-faq/">coalition</a> organized by <a href="https://www.accessnow.org/about-us/">Access Now</a>, a nonprofit that “defends and extends the digital rights of users at risk around the world,” has been gathering <a href="https://www.accessnow.org/keepiton/">data on intentional internet shutdowns</a>. It has identified 155 shutdowns in 2020 and 50 in January–May 2021, based on information from a range of sources, including news reports and other trackers, such as the India-focused <a href="https://internetshutdowns.in/">internetshutdowns.in</a>. The datasets indicate the type of shutdown, start and end dates, geographic scope, who ordered it, public justifications, affected networks, and more. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2021/10/15/internet-shutdowns-have-become-a-weapon-of-repressive-regimes">Internet shutdowns have become a weapon of repressive regimes</a>” (The Economist).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Concealed carry licenses.</strong> To construct his <a href="https://socsteidley.com/2021/10/13/introducing-the-concealed-carry-weapons-license-database/">Concealed Carry Weapons License Database</a>, sociologist <a href="https://socsteidley.com/">Trent Steidley</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/socsteidley/status/1448489666605240322">spent</a> “over a year collecting data from 28 states using public records requests and cleaning into a state and county-year format.” The <a href="https://www.openicpsr.org/openicpsr/project/149062/version/V1/view?path=/openicpsr/149062/fcr:versions/V1&amp;type=project">published files</a> include the raw data, cleaned data, and documentation. The details vary by state, but can include the number of licenses held, issued, denied, revoked, and/or suspended, among other statuses; in some instances, the numbers are also disaggregated by demographic. For most states, the records stretch back to the early 2000s, some even earlier.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Amazon search results.</strong> A <a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/10/14/amazon-puts-its-own-brands-first-above-better-rated-products">recent Markup investigation</a> “found that Amazon places products from its house brands and products exclusive to the site ahead of those from competitors — even competitors with higher customer ratings and more sales, judging from the volume of reviews.” Reporters <a href="https://adriannejeffries.com/">Adrianne Jeffries</a> and <a href="https://www.leonyin.org/">Leon Yin</a> published <a href="https://themarkup.org/amazons-advantage/2021/10/14/how-we-analyzed-amazons-treatment-of-its-brands-in-search-results">their methodology</a>, as well as the <a href="https://github.com/the-markup/investigation-amazon-brands">underlying code and data</a>, which includes product-placement information relating 12,000+ search queries, details about 157,000+ products, raw HTML, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>FOIA reading rooms.</strong> Data librarian <a href="https://twitter.com/ldeluca1101">Lisa DeLuca</a> has compiled a <a href="https://library.shu.edu/FOIA-Libraries">spreadsheet of 300+ Freedom of Information Act libraries</a>, the online reading rooms where federal agencies <a href="https://www.justice.gov/oip/foia-guide-2004-edition-foia-reading-rooms">must post</a> certain records, including those that “are likely to become the subject of subsequent requests for substantially the same records.” DeLuca’s spreadsheet, <a href="https://works.bepress.com/lisa_deluca/40/">originally published in 2019</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ldeluca1101/status/1453776389941960708">updated last week</a>, lists the agency’s name, its parent agency, and the portal’s name and URL. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/magiccia">Mago Torres</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Spiders.</strong> The <a href="https://wsc.nmbe.ch/">World Spider Catalog</a> is “the first fully searchable online database covering spider taxonomy,” with a <a href="https://wsc.nmbe.ch/dataresources">bulk dataset</a> that lists <a href="https://wsc.nmbe.ch/statistics/">49,000+ species</a>, their geographic distributions, and author-year citations. <a href="https://academic.oup.com/database/article/doi/10.1093/database/baab064/6397506">Stano Pekár et al.</a>’s <a href="https://spidertraits.sci.muni.cz/">World Spider Trait database</a> <a href="https://spidertraits.sci.muni.cz/about">collates</a> “individual measurements, observations, or composite characteristics,” such as body length, web diameter, and number of egg sacs produced.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send arachnoid feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-11-03-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Internet shutdowns, concealed carry licensing, Amazon search results, FOIA reading rooms, and spiders.</summary>
    <published>2021-11-03T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-10-20</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.10.20 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-10-20T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Judicial financial disclosures, wildlife death and illness reports, a decade of news articles, more parliamentary speech, and Halloween candy.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Judicial financial disclosures.</strong> US federal judges must file annual reports disclosing their investments, external income, and other potential conflicts of interest. The filings are technically available to the public, <a href="https://free.law/2021/09/28/announcing-federal-financial-disclosures">but onerous to access</a>. So the <a href="https://free.law/">Free Law Project</a> undertook an effort to obtain and <a href="https://github.com/freelawproject/disclosure-extractor">parse</a> <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/coverage/financial-disclosures/">as many of them as possible</a>, ultimately <a href="https://free.law/2021/10/15/financial-disclosures-now-available-to-all-on-courtlistener">creating a database</a> of 250,000+ pages of disclosures, which you can <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/financial-disclosures/">search online</a> or <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/api/rest-info/#financialdisclosure-endpoint">via an API</a>, including “complete coverage of every judge, justice, and magistrate between 2011 and 2018.” <strong>Read more</strong>: “<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/131-federal-judges-broke-the-law-by-hearing-cases-where-they-had-a-financial-interest-11632834421">131 Federal Judges Broke the Law by Hearing Cases Where They Had a Financial Interest</a>,” the first article in <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=site%3Awsj.com+%22Hidden+Interests%22&amp;t=h_&amp;iar=news&amp;ia=news">an ongoing series by the WSJ</a>, which had early access to the database. [h/t <a href="https://acure.info/">Tom Folkes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Wildlife death and illness reports.</strong> <a href="https://whispers.usgs.gov/home">WHISPers</a>, hosted by the USGS National Wildlife Health Center, is a “repository for sharing basic information about historic and ongoing wildlife mortality (death) and/or morbidity (illness) events,” with contributions from “hundreds of natural resource managers and stakeholders across the U.S. and beyond.” Wisconsin officials, for instance, <a href="https://whispers.usgs.gov/event/201296">reported that a bald eagle died of lead poisoning in Adams County this April</a>. You can search WHISPers by date range, county, species, diagnosis, and more — up to 500 events at a time, exportable as CSV files. [h/t <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspb.2021.0974">Terra R. Kelly et al.</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A decade of news articles.</strong> For their <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/what-analysis-6-million-articles-reveals-about-state-us-newspapers">analysis of investigative publishing trends</a>, <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/118/30/e2105155118">Eray Turkel et al.</a> gathered nearly 6 million articles published by 50 outlets (mostly local newspapers) in the 2010s, drawn from the pay-to-access <a href="https://www.newsbank.com/about-newsbank">NewsBank</a> service. The study’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/HSZ2QL">public dataset</a> includes each article’s title, date, byline, and word and sentence count, plus various linguistic metrics calculated by the researchers. <strong>Related</strong>: To examine the online news economy, the Stanford-based team is <a href="https://rally.mozilla.org/current-studies/beyond-the-paywall/index.html">seeking volunteers to have certain web-browsing tracked</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/shoshievass">Shosh Vasserman</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More parliamentary speech.</strong> PhD candidate <a href="https://twitter.com/dbrby">Daniel Braby</a>’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/VILSR8">parlCymru</a> and <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/EQ9WBE">parlScot</a> provide the text of 5 and 20+ years of spoken contributions to the Welsh and Scottish parliaments, respectively, plus speaker and circumstance metadata. German publication <a href="https://www.dekoder.org/">Dekoder</a>’s <a href="https://danilamorkovkin.blog/">Daniel Marcus</a> has <a href="https://www.discuss-data.net/dataset/fb52dac2-66e3-47a3-86c5-b2a3dadf41bf/">gathered 385,000+ transcripts</a> from 25+ years of speech in Russia’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_Duma">State Duma</a>, powering an <a href="https://duma.dekoder.org/de">interactive chart of word frequencies</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L4OAKN">Spoken contributions to nine other parliaments</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2020-04-29-edition">DIP 2020.04.29</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/fabrice_deprez">Fabrice Deprez</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Halloween candy.</strong> For FiveThirtyEight’s “<a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/videos/the-ultimate-halloween-candy-power-ranking/">Ultimate Halloween Candy Power Ranking</a>” (2017), <a href="https://walthickey.com/">Walt Hickey</a> <a href="http://walthickey.com/2017/10/18/whats-the-best-halloween-candy/">had readers vote</a> on head-to-head matchups among 85 confections. The <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/data/tree/master/candy-power-ranking">project’s dataset</a> includes each candy’s winning percentage, various categorizations (e.g., Does it contain chocolate?), relative cost, and sugariness. [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-gardner-0531aa9/">Eric Gardner</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send saccharine feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-10-20-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Judicial financial disclosures, wildlife death and illness reports, a decade of news articles, more parliamentary speech, and Halloween candy.</summary>
    <published>2021-10-20T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-10-13</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.10.13 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-10-13T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Abortion policies, hourly weather, deployment votes, mask diplomacy, and bird food.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Abortion policies.</strong> The World Health Organization’s <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/">Global Abortion Policies Database</a> is “designed to strengthen global efforts to eliminate unsafe abortion by producing an interactive open-access database and repository of current abortion laws, policies, and national standards and guidelines.” The project uses an <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/documents/data/questionnaire.pdf">extensive questionnaire</a> to categorize dozens of regulatory factors for each country; the findings can be <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/countries/">queried</a> online, or <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/documents/data/survey.xlsx">downloaded as a spreadsheet</a>. The Center for Reproductive Rights’ <a href="https://maps.reproductiverights.org/worldabortionlaws">World Abortion Laws Map</a> groups countries into five categories of restrictiveness, and also indicates the types of laws in effect. The map’s data is <a href="https://maps.reproductiverights.org/ajax/wal-map">available as a JSON file</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2021/us-abortion-laws-worldwide/">How abortion laws in the U.S. compare to those in other countries</a>” (Washington Post). [h/t <a href="https://flowingdata.com/2021/10/07/comparing-abortion-limits-in-the-u-s-against-other-countries/">Nathan Yau</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Hourly weather.</strong> NOAA’s <a href="https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/products/land-based-station/integrated-surface-database">Integrated Surface Database</a>, launched two decades ago, combines point-in-time weather observations from 100+ sources, collected at 35,000+ stations around the world, 14,000+ of which are still active. The measurements can include “wind speed and direction, wind gust, temperature, dew point, cloud data, sea level pressure, altimeter setting, station pressure, present weather, visibility, precipitation amounts for various time periods, snow depth” and more. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://observablehq.com/@observablehq/noaa-weather-data-by-major-u-s-city">An Observable notebook for previewing and downloading data from ISDLite</a>, NOAA’s simpler version of the larger database. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/enjalot">Ian Johnson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Deployment votes.</strong> The <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/">Parliamentary Deployment Votes Database</a> gathers information about national parliaments and legislatures voting on the deployment or withdrawal of military forces. It lists the date, name, and chamber of each vote; the mission name and area of deployment; the number of members voting in favor, against, and abstaining; and other details. The <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/?page_id=8">collaborative</a> project’s <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/?page_id=2">latest release</a> includes 1,000+ votes in 21 countries from 1990 to 2019, plus 5,500+ counts disaggregated by political party.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mask diplomacy.</strong> Political scientists <a href="https://twitter.com/diegotelias">Diego Telias</a> and <a href="https://www.furdinez.com/">Francisco Urdinez</a> have <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/EIAXSE">collected</a> and <a href="https://estudiosasiaticos.uc.cl/humanidades-digitales/mask-diplomacy-v-1-0">mapped</a> data on 530+ donations of face masks, respirators, COVID-19 tests, and other pandemic-related supplies from entities in China and Taiwan to 33 countries Latin America and the Caribbean in early 2020. The dataset indicates the donor, recipient, date, and equipment types, amounts, and estimated value. <strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Francisco-Urdinez/publication/344035590_China’s_Foreign_Aid_Political_Drivers_Lessons_from_a_Novel_Dataset_of_Mask_Diplomacy_in_Latin_America_During_the_COVID-19_Pandemic/links/607df952907dcf667baf42fe/Chinas-Foreign-Aid-Political-Drivers-Lessons-from-a-Novel-Dataset-of-Mask-Diplomacy-in-Latin-America-During-the-COVID-19-Pandemic.pdfa">Telias and Urdinez’s preprint analyzing the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bird food.</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-01049-9">Allen H. Hurlbert et al.</a>’s <a href="https://aviandiet.unc.edu/">Avian Diet Database</a> contains “73,075 quantitative diet data records for 759 primarily North American bird species, providing standardized information not just on the diet itself, but on the context for that diet information including the year, season, location, and habitat type of each study.” You can explore it online, <a href="https://github.com/hurlbertlab/dietdatabase">download it</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/ahhurlbert/aviandietdb">access it as an R package</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send feathered feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-10-13-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Abortion policies, hourly weather, deployment votes, mask diplomacy, and bird food.</summary>
    <published>2021-10-13T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-10-06</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.10.06 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-10-06T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Reservoir levels, Stolpersteine, parallel texts, undersea internet cables, and a graph model of the human skeleton.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Reservoir levels.</strong> The <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/main/about/mission.html">US Bureau of Reclamation</a>, a federal agency formed in 1902, is today “the nation’s largest wholesale water supplier, operating 338 reservoirs with a total storage capacity of 140 million acre-feet.” Its <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/">Reclamation Information Sharing Environment</a> (RISE) <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/newsroom/newsroomold/newsrelease/detail.cfm?RecordID=72624">launched publicly last year</a>, providing data on reservoir levels, water quality, hydropower generation, habitat monitoring, and more. You can <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/catalog">browse the data catalog</a>, <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/time-series/search?v=1">explore its time series</a> — for instance <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/catalog/4370/item/6123">daily water levels at Lake Mead</a>, the country’s largest reservoir, going back to 1935 — and <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/rise-api">query its API</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.cnn.com/interactive/2021/08/us/colorado-river-water-shortage/">The Southwest’s most important river is drying up</a>” (CNN).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Stolpersteine.</strong> German artist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunter_Demnig">Gunter Demnig</a>’s <a href="http://www.stolpersteine.eu/en/home/">Stolpersteine</a> are concrete-and-brass “stumbling stones,” each inscribed with the name of someone killed or persecuted by the Nazi regime, placed into pavement where the person last freely lived or worked. Since the mid-1990s, Demnig <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/feb/18/stumbling-stones-a-different-vision-of-holocaust-remembrance">has installed</a> <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/germany-75000th-stolperstein-for-holocaust-victims-laid/a-51827506">more than 75,000 of the stones</a>, often with the help of local groups. <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-berlin.de/en/project/koordinierungsstelle">Stolpersteine coordinators in Berlin</a> provide a <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-berlin.de/en/finding-stolpersteine">map and downloadable list of 8,500+ installations</a> in the city. Other resources include a <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-hamburg.de/en.php?MAIN_ID=7">searchable database of 6,000+ Stolpersteine in Hamburg</a> and <a href="https://stolpersteine.app/en/stolpersteine-app/">Stolpersteine.app</a>’s <a href="https://stolpersteine.app/en/stolpersteine/">map of 10,000+ installations in the Netherlands and Belgium</a>. [h/t <a href="https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/">Basile Simon</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/JenniferVEvans/status/1431304581376626688">Jennifer Evans</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/SmithHelmut/status/1431307756565405696">Helmut Smith</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Parallel texts.</strong> The <a href="https://opus.nlpl.eu/">OPUS</a> project gathers and converts texts that are freely available in multiple languages, providing <a href="https://opus.nlpl.eu/trac/index.html">various interfaces</a> for querying and downloading side-by-side translations. The dozens of sources include “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel corpora</a>” — bodies of text whose translations have already been aligned with one another, typically sentence by sentence — such as the <a href="https://conferences.unite.un.org/uncorpus">United Nations Parallel Corpus</a>, as well as those OPUS has tried to align automatically with software. [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:peerlessdeepak">u:peerlessdeepak</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Undersea internet cables.</strong> <a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/">TeleGeography</a>’s <a href="https://www.submarinecablemap.com/">Submarine Cable Map</a> lets you search and browse nearly 500 active and planned <a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/submarine-cable-faqs-frequently-asked-questions">undersea internet cables</a>, the <a href="https://www.submarinecablemap.com/submarine-cable/seamewe-3">longest of which</a> spans 39,000 kilometers and connects four continents. The map’s information, which <a href="https://github.com/telegeography/www.submarinecablemap.com#how-can-i-download-the-dataset">can also be downloaded</a>, indicates each cable’s length, landing points, completion year, owners, and suppliers. [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-beef-brexit-and-bivariate-choropleths-772476">Soph Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The _____ bone’s connected to the _____ bone.</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://twitter.com/clayheaton">Clay Heaton</a>’s <a href="https://github.com/clayheaton/human-skeleton-graph-data-model">graph model of the human skeleton</a> links all 206 adult human bones to their anatomical neighbors. The dataset also maps each bone to its general region, such as “Left Foot” or “Right Ear.” [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:arnicas/">Lynn Cherny</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ossified feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-10-06-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Reservoir levels, Stolpersteine, parallel texts, undersea internet cables, and a graph model of the human skeleton.</summary>
    <published>2021-10-06T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
