<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Is Plural</title>
    <link>https://www.data-is-plural.com</link>
    <description>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 08:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.10.13 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-10-13-edition</link>
      <description>Abortion policies, hourly weather, deployment votes, mask diplomacy, and bird food.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Abortion policies, hourly weather, deployment votes, mask diplomacy, and bird food.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Abortion policies.</strong> The World Health Organization’s <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/">Global Abortion Policies Database</a> is “designed to strengthen global efforts to eliminate unsafe abortion by producing an interactive open-access database and repository of current abortion laws, policies, and national standards and guidelines.” The project uses an <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/documents/data/questionnaire.pdf">extensive questionnaire</a> to categorize dozens of regulatory factors for each country; the findings can be <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/countries/">queried</a> online, or <a href="https://abortion-policies.srhr.org/documents/data/survey.xlsx">downloaded as a spreadsheet</a>. The Center for Reproductive Rights’ <a href="https://maps.reproductiverights.org/worldabortionlaws">World Abortion Laws Map</a> groups countries into five categories of restrictiveness, and also indicates the types of laws in effect. The map’s data is <a href="https://maps.reproductiverights.org/ajax/wal-map">available as a JSON file</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2021/us-abortion-laws-worldwide/">How abortion laws in the U.S. compare to those in other countries</a>” (Washington Post). [h/t <a href="https://flowingdata.com/2021/10/07/comparing-abortion-limits-in-the-u-s-against-other-countries/">Nathan Yau</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Hourly weather.</strong> NOAA’s <a href="https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/products/land-based-station/integrated-surface-database">Integrated Surface Database</a>, launched two decades ago, combines point-in-time weather observations from 100+ sources, collected at 35,000+ stations around the world, 14,000+ of which are still active. The measurements can include “wind speed and direction, wind gust, temperature, dew point, cloud data, sea level pressure, altimeter setting, station pressure, present weather, visibility, precipitation amounts for various time periods, snow depth” and more. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://observablehq.com/@observablehq/noaa-weather-data-by-major-u-s-city">An Observable notebook for previewing and downloading data from ISDLite</a>, NOAA’s simpler version of the larger database. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/enjalot">Ian Johnson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Deployment votes.</strong> The <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/">Parliamentary Deployment Votes Database</a> gathers information about national parliaments and legislatures voting on the deployment or withdrawal of military forces. It lists the date, name, and chamber of each vote; the mission name and area of deployment; the number of members voting in favor, against, and abstaining; and other details. The <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/?page_id=8">collaborative</a> project’s <a href="http://deploymentvotewatch.eu/?page_id=2">latest release</a> includes 1,000+ votes in 21 countries from 1990 to 2019, plus 5,500+ counts disaggregated by political party.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mask diplomacy.</strong> Political scientists <a href="https://twitter.com/diegotelias">Diego Telias</a> and <a href="https://www.furdinez.com/">Francisco Urdinez</a> have <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/EIAXSE">collected</a> and <a href="https://estudiosasiaticos.uc.cl/humanidades-digitales/mask-diplomacy-v-1-0">mapped</a> data on 530+ donations of face masks, respirators, COVID-19 tests, and other pandemic-related supplies from entities in China and Taiwan to 33 countries Latin America and the Caribbean in early 2020. The dataset indicates the donor, recipient, date, and equipment types, amounts, and estimated value. <strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Francisco-Urdinez/publication/344035590_China’s_Foreign_Aid_Political_Drivers_Lessons_from_a_Novel_Dataset_of_Mask_Diplomacy_in_Latin_America_During_the_COVID-19_Pandemic/links/607df952907dcf667baf42fe/Chinas-Foreign-Aid-Political-Drivers-Lessons-from-a-Novel-Dataset-of-Mask-Diplomacy-in-Latin-America-During-the-COVID-19-Pandemic.pdfa">Telias and Urdinez’s preprint analyzing the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bird food.</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-01049-9">Allen H. Hurlbert et al.</a>’s <a href="https://aviandiet.unc.edu/">Avian Diet Database</a> contains “73,075 quantitative diet data records for 759 primarily North American bird species, providing standardized information not just on the diet itself, but on the context for that diet information including the year, season, location, and habitat type of each study.” You can explore it online, <a href="https://github.com/hurlbertlab/dietdatabase">download it</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/ahhurlbert/aviandietdb">access it as an R package</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send feathered feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-10-13</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.10.06 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-10-06-edition</link>
      <description>Reservoir levels, Stolpersteine, parallel texts, undersea internet cables, and a graph model of the human skeleton.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Reservoir levels, Stolpersteine, parallel texts, undersea internet cables, and a graph model of the human skeleton.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Reservoir levels.</strong> The <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/main/about/mission.html">US Bureau of Reclamation</a>, a federal agency formed in 1902, is today “the nation’s largest wholesale water supplier, operating 338 reservoirs with a total storage capacity of 140 million acre-feet.” Its <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/">Reclamation Information Sharing Environment</a> (RISE) <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/newsroom/newsroomold/newsrelease/detail.cfm?RecordID=72624">launched publicly last year</a>, providing data on reservoir levels, water quality, hydropower generation, habitat monitoring, and more. You can <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/catalog">browse the data catalog</a>, <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/time-series/search?v=1">explore its time series</a> — for instance <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/catalog/4370/item/6123">daily water levels at Lake Mead</a>, the country’s largest reservoir, going back to 1935 — and <a href="https://data.usbr.gov/rise-api">query its API</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.cnn.com/interactive/2021/08/us/colorado-river-water-shortage/">The Southwest’s most important river is drying up</a>” (CNN).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Stolpersteine.</strong> German artist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunter_Demnig">Gunter Demnig</a>’s <a href="http://www.stolpersteine.eu/en/home/">Stolpersteine</a> are concrete-and-brass “stumbling stones,” each inscribed with the name of someone killed or persecuted by the Nazi regime, placed into pavement where the person last freely lived or worked. Since the mid-1990s, Demnig <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/feb/18/stumbling-stones-a-different-vision-of-holocaust-remembrance">has installed</a> <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/germany-75000th-stolperstein-for-holocaust-victims-laid/a-51827506">more than 75,000 of the stones</a>, often with the help of local groups. <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-berlin.de/en/project/koordinierungsstelle">Stolpersteine coordinators in Berlin</a> provide a <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-berlin.de/en/finding-stolpersteine">map and downloadable list of 8,500+ installations</a> in the city. Other resources include a <a href="https://www.stolpersteine-hamburg.de/en.php?MAIN_ID=7">searchable database of 6,000+ Stolpersteine in Hamburg</a> and <a href="https://stolpersteine.app/en/stolpersteine-app/">Stolpersteine.app</a>’s <a href="https://stolpersteine.app/en/stolpersteine/">map of 10,000+ installations in the Netherlands and Belgium</a>. [h/t <a href="https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/">Basile Simon</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/JenniferVEvans/status/1431304581376626688">Jennifer Evans</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/SmithHelmut/status/1431307756565405696">Helmut Smith</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Parallel texts.</strong> The <a href="https://opus.nlpl.eu/">OPUS</a> project gathers and converts texts that are freely available in multiple languages, providing <a href="https://opus.nlpl.eu/trac/index.html">various interfaces</a> for querying and downloading side-by-side translations. The dozens of sources include “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_text">parallel corpora</a>” — bodies of text whose translations have already been aligned with one another, typically sentence by sentence — such as the <a href="https://conferences.unite.un.org/uncorpus">United Nations Parallel Corpus</a>, as well as those OPUS has tried to align automatically with software. [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:peerlessdeepak">u:peerlessdeepak</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Undersea internet cables.</strong> <a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/">TeleGeography</a>’s <a href="https://www.submarinecablemap.com/">Submarine Cable Map</a> lets you search and browse nearly 500 active and planned <a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/submarine-cable-faqs-frequently-asked-questions">undersea internet cables</a>, the <a href="https://www.submarinecablemap.com/submarine-cable/seamewe-3">longest of which</a> spans 39,000 kilometers and connects four continents. The map’s information, which <a href="https://github.com/telegeography/www.submarinecablemap.com#how-can-i-download-the-dataset">can also be downloaded</a>, indicates each cable’s length, landing points, completion year, owners, and suppliers. [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-beef-brexit-and-bivariate-choropleths-772476">Soph Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The _____ bone’s connected to the _____ bone.</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://twitter.com/clayheaton">Clay Heaton</a>’s <a href="https://github.com/clayheaton/human-skeleton-graph-data-model">graph model of the human skeleton</a> links all 206 adult human bones to their anatomical neighbors. The dataset also maps each bone to its general region, such as “Left Foot” or “Right Ear.” [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:arnicas/">Lynn Cherny</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ossified feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-10-06</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.09.29 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-09-29-edition</link>
      <description>State vaccine mandates, incarceration by county, South Carolina jail deaths, marine regions, and dancing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>State vaccine mandates, incarceration by county, South Carolina jail deaths, marine regions, and dancing.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>State vaccine mandates.</strong> The <a href="https://www.immunize.org/aboutus/">Immunization Action Coalition</a> is a not-for-profit organization that “works to increase immunization rates and prevent disease by creating and distributing educational materials for healthcare professionals and the public.” Its resources include a <a href="https://www.immunize.org/laws/">series of HTML tables</a> that categorize states’ school and childcare immunization mandates for more than a dozen diseases, such as <a href="https://www.immunize.org/laws/hepa.asp">hepatitis A</a>, <a href="https://www.immunize.org/laws/polio.asp">polio</a>, and <a href="https://www.immunize.org/laws/rotavirus.asp">rotavirus</a>. The tables, although not downloadable, can be easily pasted into spreadsheet programs. The <a href="https://www.kff.org/about-us/">Kaiser Family Foundation</a>, meanwhile, is <a href="https://www.kff.org/report-section/state-covid-19-data-and-policy-actions-policy-actions/#vaccines">compiling data</a> on state vaccine mandates specific to COVID-19. [h/t <a href="https://graphics.reuters.com/HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS/BIDEN/zgpombrajpd/index.html">Minami Funakoshi</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Incarceration by county.</strong> For an <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2021/09/20/there-are-fewer-people-behind-bars-now-than-10-years-ago-will-it-last">analysis and graphics</a> that examine changes in incarceration rates over time, reporters at the Marshall Project have <a href="https://observablehq.com/@themarshallproject/adults-in-correctional-facilities-from-decennial-census">published a dataset</a> indicating the number of adults in each US county who were living in correctional facilities at the time of the Decennial Census in 2000, 2010, and 2020. Those counts, per the Census Bureau’s methodology, include a broad range of facilities, such as state prisons, military jails, halfway houses, and immigration detention centers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>South Carolina jail deaths.</strong> For an <a href="https://www.islandpacket.com/news/state/south-carolina/article252332068.html">investigation</a> into inmate deaths in South Carolina, <a href="https://twitter.com/Lucasgsl6">Lucas Smolcic Larson</a> has <a href="https://github.com/islandpacket/SCjaildeaths">compiled a dataset</a> “that aims to fill a void left by inconsistent government tracking” of these incidents. It details 253 deaths between 2009 and mid-2021, and draws from a <a href="https://github.com/islandpacket/SCjaildeaths#data-sources">range of sources</a>, including official forms, jail death data <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-graphic/">compiled by Reuters</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2020-10-21-edition/">DIP 2020.10.21</a>) <a href="https://data.huffingtonpost.com/2016/jail-deaths">and the Huffington Post</a>, local media reports, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.incarcerationtransparency.org/">Louisiana deaths behind bars</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-08-18-edition/">DIP 2021.08.18</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Sea world.</strong> <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/">Marine Regions</a>, a project managed by the <a href="https://www.vliz.be/en">Flanders Marine Institute</a>, provides names and geographic coordinates for <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/content.php">62,000+</a> sea-related places, areas, and boundaries. These <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/downloads.php">include</a> exclusive economic zones, the high seas, “internal waters,” <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/sources.php#heritage">World Marine Heritage Sites</a> and more, drawn from a <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/sources.php">wide range of sources</a>. You can also <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/eezsearch.php">search</a> and <a href="https://www.marineregions.org/eezmapper.php">explore</a> the maritime boundaries online.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Dancing.</strong> The <a href="https://aistdancedb.ongaaccel.jp/">AIST Dance Video Database</a>, from Japan’s <a href="https://www.aist.go.jp/aist_e/about_aist/">National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology</a>, “is a shared database containing original street dance videos with copyright-cleared dance music.” It <a href="https://google.github.io/aistplusplus_dataset/factsfigures.html">forms the basis</a> of Google Research’s <a href="https://google.github.io/aistplusplus_dataset/index.html">AIST++ Dance Motion Dataset</a>, which provides detailed annotations of 10 million images from the videos, plus “1,408 sequences of 3D human dance motion,” some of which <a href="https://google.github.io/aistplusplus_dataset/visualizer/index.html">explore online</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/">Robin Sloan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send danceable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-09-29</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.09.22 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-09-22-edition</link>
      <description>K-12 learning arrangements, rushing waters, voluntary union recognition, four decades of Spanish elections, and cryptic crossword clues.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>K-12 learning arrangements, rushing waters, voluntary union recognition, four decades of Spanish elections, and cryptic crossword clues.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>K-12 learning arrangements.</strong> The <a href="https://www.covidschooldatahub.com">COVID-19 School Data Hub</a>, which <a href="https://emilyoster.substack.com/p/special-edition-today-covid-19-school">launched last week</a>, is “a central database for educators, researchers, and policymakers to understand how the COVID-19 pandemic shaped students’ modes of learning in 2020-21.” The project’s team, led by economist <a href="https://emilyoster.net/">Emily Oster</a>, has gathered data on learning models (in-person, virtual, or hybrid) used by public schools and districts at various points in time, their masking policies, and reported COVID-19 cases. The datasets can be <a href="https://www.covidschooldatahub.com/for_researchers">downloaded in bulk</a> or <a href="https://www.covidschooldatahub.com/explore_by_state">by state</a>. The coverage and granularity vary by topic and state; the project’s <a href="https://www.covidschooldatahub.com/methods">documentation</a> describes the collection methods and availability.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Rushing waters.</strong> The US Geological Survey’s <a href="https://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis">National Water Information System</a> provides data on the “occurrence, quantity, quality, distribution, and movement of surface and underground waters” around the country. The <a href="https://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis/sw">surface water measurements</a> — mainly <a href="https://help.waterdata.usgs.gov/tutorials/surface-water-data/how-do-i-interpret-gage-height-and-streamflow-values">streamflow and gage height</a> — come from tens of thousands of monitoring sites. (<a href="https://waterdata.usgs.gov/monitoring-location/07378000/#parameterCode=00065&amp;startDT=2021-08-26&amp;endDT=2021-09-21">Here’s a site near Baton Rouge</a> before and after <a href="https://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/article_c06a0dba-159b-11ec-9f44-7769e5bab072.html">hurricanes Ida and Nicholas</a>.) There’s an <a href="https://waterservices.usgs.gov/">API for accessing the records</a>, including <a href="https://waterservices.usgs.gov/rest/DV-Service.html">daily summaries</a> and <a href="https://waterservices.usgs.gov/rest/IV-Service.html">real-time measurements</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://tidesandcurrents.noaa.gov/nwlon.html">NOAA’s water-level data</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2016-03-23-edition/">DIP 2016.03.23</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-allen-60287015b/">Michael Allen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Voluntary union recognition.</strong> Civic technologist <a href="https://twitter.com/forestgregg">Forest Gregg</a> has begun <a href="https://www.muckrock.com/foi/united-states-of-america-10/voluntary-recognitions-january-1-june-30-2021-116304/">filing FOIA requests</a> to the National Labor Relations Board <a href="https://github.com/labordata/nlrb-voluntary-recognitions">to collect newly-available data</a> on employers’ voluntary recognition of employee unions, drawn from agency’s <a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/sites/default/files/attachments/pages/node-195/5581_7-20.pdf">relevant notification form</a>. The <a href="https://flatgithub.com/labordata/nlrb-voluntary-recognitions/blob/main/voluntary_recognitions.csv?sort=Date%20VR%20Request%20Received%2Cdesc">records so far</a> include 70+ recognitions in late 2020 and early 2021, plus nearly 1,000 from a prior reporting program between 2007 and 2009; they list the employer, union, case number, relevant dates, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/reports/graphs-data/recent-election-results">Union election results</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-05-05-edition/">DIP 2021.05.05</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Four decades of Spanish elections.</strong> The <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-00975-y">Spanish Electoral Archive</a>, published this summer, provides detailed results of all municipal, regional, general, and European Parliament elections in Spain since the country’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_transition_to_democracy">transition to democracy</a> in the late 1970s. The <a href="http://sea.uv.es/gipeyop/sea.html">project</a>’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/SEA">datasets</a> standardize records from various official sources that, in many cases, drill down to the level of individual ballot boxes.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Hidden clue here will be!</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://www.eigenfoo.xyz/">George Ho</a> has compiled a <a href="https://cryptics.eigenfoo.xyz/">dataset of 589,000+ clues</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptic_crossword">cryptic crosswords</a>, “collected from various blogs and publicly available digital archives.” The collection, <a href="https://github.com/eigenfoo/cryptics/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">released</a> earlier this month, is available to download and also <a href="https://cryptics.eigenfoo.xyz/clues/clues">explore online</a>. (<a href="https://cryptics.eigenfoo.xyz/clues/clues?_sort=rowid&amp;clue__contains=%21&amp;answer__exact=CRYPTIC">For example</a>.) Its “<a href="https://cryptics.eigenfoo.xyz/datasheet">datasheet</a>” describes the motivation, collection process, composition, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send cryptic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-09-22</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.09.08 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-09-08-edition</link>
      <description>OpenSanctions, alternative fueling, India’s political parties, software licenses, and UK parliamentary ejections.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>OpenSanctions, alternative fueling, India’s political parties, software licenses, and UK parliamentary ejections.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Persons of interest.</strong> <a href="https://opensanctions.org/">OpenSanctions</a>, an <a href="https://github.com/pudo/opensanctions">open-source project</a> that <a href="https://twitter.com/open_sanctions/status/1432977327282171904">launched its website last week</a>, is “an international database of persons and companies of political, criminal, or economic interest.” It combines and standardizes data from <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/">20+ sources</a>, such as the US Treasury’s <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/us_ofac_sdn/">sanctions</a> <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/us_ofac_cons/">lists</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-02-21-edition/">DIP 2018.02.21</a>), <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/interpol_red_notices/">Interpol’s Red Notices</a>, <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/eu_meps/">members of EU parliament</a>, and the <a href="https://opensanctions.org/datasets/us_cia_world_leaders/">CIA’s index of world leaders</a>. The project uses a <a href="https://opensanctions.org/reference/">detailed schema</a> to represent the particulars of each entity, including aliases, known cryptocurrency wallets, aircraft registrations, sanction dates, and more. You can <a href="https://opensanctions.org/docs/usage/">download the data</a> with those detailed representations or in simpler formats. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/pudo/status/1433017697244225540">Friedrich Lindenberg</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Alternative fueling.</strong> The US Bureau of Transportation Statistics’ <a href="https://www.bts.gov/newsroom/national-transportation-atlas-database-summer-2021-adds-alternative-fuel-corridors-dataset">summer update</a> to its <a href="https://www.bts.gov/ntad">National Transportation Atlas Database</a> adds a <a href="https://data-usdot.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/alternative-fuel-corridors/explore">dataset</a> on “<a href="https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/environment/alternative_fuel_corridors/">alternative fuel corridors</a>” — stretches of highway with a sufficient frequency of fueling stations. (Electric vehicle corridors must, for instance, have charging stations at least every 50 miles.) The release covers electric, hydrogen, propane, compressed natural gas, and liquefied natural gas infrastructure, and complements a prior dataset of <a href="https://data-usdot.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/alternative-fueling-stations-1/explore">56,000+ such stations</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: The Department of Energy’s maps and datasets of <a href="https://afdc.energy.gov/stations/">alternative fueling stations</a> and <a href="https://afdc.energy.gov/corridors">corridors</a>. [h/t <a href="https://datainnovation.org/2021/08/tracking-alternative-fueling-facilities-across-the-united-states/">Morgan Stevens</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>India’s political parties.</strong> The <a href="https://tcpd.ashoka.edu.in/">Trivedi Centre for Political Data</a> has published a <a href="https://tcpd.ashoka.edu.in/political-parties-of-india/">dataset</a> of “all parties that have contested national and state elections in India since 1962,” with an eye toward unifying the information across name changes. For each legislative level and state, the dataset <a href="https://github.com/tcpd/ppi/blob/main/17Aug2021TCPDPPI_1_0.pdf">indicates</a> each party’s first and last year contesting elections, number of seats won, number of female and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scheduled_Castes_and_Scheduled_Tribes">Scheduled Caste/Tribe</a> candidates fielded, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/vijdankawoosa/status/1431642431590567944">Vijdan Mohammad Kawoosa</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/gilkumar/status/1431210872945328146">Gilles Verniers</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Software licenses.</strong> The <a href="https://scancode-licensedb.aboutcode.org/">ScanCode LicenseDB</a> provides information about 1,700+ software licenses, ranging from the common (e.g., <a href="https://scancode-licensedb.aboutcode.org/mit.html">MIT License</a>) to the idiosyncratic (<a href="https://scancode-licensedb.aboutcode.org/blessing.html">SQLite Blessing</a>) to the obscure (<a href="https://scancode-licensedb.aboutcode.org/ubuntu-font-1.0.html">Ubuntu Font License</a>). The <a href="https://github.com/nexB/scancode-toolkit/tree/develop/src/licensedcode/data/licenses">records</a>, which are part of a broader <a href="https://www.aboutcode.org/projects/scancode.html">license-detection toolkit</a>, list each license’s core phrasing, general category, custodian, relevant URLs, and <a href="https://scancode-licensedb.aboutcode.org/help.html">other details</a>. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/pombredanne">Philippe Ombredanne</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>UK parliamentary ejections.</strong> A UK House of Commons Library <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/sn02430/">research briefing</a> in July included a spreadsheet of “MPs who have left the Chamber voluntarily, been asked to withdraw, or who have been suspended,” along with the date, reason, and suspension period. <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/sn03169/">Another briefing</a>, published the same day, “attempts to capture all instances where an apology has been made on the floor of the House of Commons since 1979.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/InductiveStep/status/1419001122799423490">Andi Fugard</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send unparliamentary feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-09-08</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.09.01 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-09-01-edition</link>
      <description>Attacks against aid workers, fact-checks, offshore wind turbines, worker strikes in China, and creative Twitter bots.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Attacks against aid workers, fact-checks, offshore wind turbines, worker strikes in China, and creative Twitter bots.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Attacks against aid workers.</strong> The <a href="https://aidworkersecurity.org/">Aid Worker Security Database</a> is “a global compilation of reports on major security incidents involving deliberate acts of violence affecting aid workers,” with more than 3,200 records since 1997. Researchers gather, evaluate, and categorize information from official reports, partnerships with humanitarian agencies, news media, and other sources. For <a href="https://aidworkersecurity.org/incidents">each incident</a>, the database indicates its date and location; the number of workers killed, wounded, or kidnapped; their general affiliations; the type of attacker and means of attack; a brief description; and more. [h/t <a href="https://watson.brown.edu/costsofwar/figures">The Costs of War Project</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Fact-checks.</strong> <a href="https://www.claimreviewproject.com/">ClaimReview</a> is <a href="https://schema.org/ClaimReview">an open standard</a> for adding structured information to fact-check articles, such as the specific claim reviewed, where it appeared, the fact-checking organization, and the reviewer’s rating. The schema has been adopted by a range of big-name publishers, including the Washington Post, PolitiFact, and Univision, as well as smaller outlets around the world. The structured-data website <a href="https://datacommons.org/">Data Commons</a> hosts a <a href="https://www.datacommons.org/factcheck/download">feed of 29,000+ ClaimReview-tagged fact-checks</a>, as well as a curated subset.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Offshore wind turbines.</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-00982-z">Ting Zhang et al.</a> have trained an algorithm to identify wind turbines in coastal satellite imagery, and have used it to build a <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/dataset/Global_offshore_wind_farm_dataset/13280252/5">dataset</a> listing the location and construction month of 6,924 turbines offshore of 14 countries between 2015 and 2019. To test the algorithm’s accuracy, the researchers compared its results to other sources, including the <a href="https://eerscmap.usgs.gov/uswtdb/">US Wind Turbine Database</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-04-25-edition/">DIP 2018.04.25</a>), the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/renewable-energy-planning-database-monthly-extract">UK’s Renewable Energy Planning Database</a>, the <a href="https://www.emodnet-humanactivities.eu/search-results.php?dataname=Wind+Farms+%28Polygons%29">European Marine Observation and Data Network</a>, and <a href="https://data.open-power-system-data.org/renewable_power_plants/2020-08-25">Open Power System Data</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2019-08-14-edition/">DIP 2019.08.14</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Worker strikes in China.</strong> <a href="https://clb.org.hk/">China Labour Bulletin</a>, <a href="https://clb.org.hk/content/about-us-0">founded in 1994 as a monthly newsletter</a>, is a Hong Kong–based organization “that supports and actively engages with the workers’ movement in China.” Its <a href="https://maps.clb.org.hk/">map and dataset of worker strikes and protests</a> provides details on 13,000+ events since 2011, including their location, date, and description; industry categories and ownership types; employee demands; and authorities’ response. [h/t <a href="https://chinadatalab.ucsd.edu/resources/">The China Data Lab</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Creative Twitter bots.</strong> The website <a href="https://botwiki.org/">Botwiki</a> “was created in July 2015 by <a href="https://botwiki.org/author/stefan/">Stefan Bohacek</a> with the goal of preserving examples of interesting and creative online bots” and providing tutorials for building them. Bohacek has <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/fourtonfish/popular-twitter-bots">curated a dataset</a> of 70+ popular examples running on Twitter, drawn from Botwiki and from <a href="https://tullyhansen.com/">Tully Hansen</a>’s <a href="https://twitter.com/i/lists/120837264">Omnibots list</a>. Among them: <a href="https://twitter.com/year_progress">@year_progress</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/nyt_first_said">@nyt<em>first</em>said</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/tiny_star_field">@tiny<em>star</em>field</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send automated feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-09-01</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.08.25 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-08-25-edition</link>
      <description>Legislator stock trades, national revenues, Africa building outlines, AI patents, and Formula One.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Legislator stock trades, national revenues, Africa building outlines, AI patents, and Formula One.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Legislator stock trades.</strong> US Congress members and candidates must report all stock purchases and sales exceeding $1,000, as well as those of their spouses and dependent children. Those records are technically available through the <a href="https://disclosures-clerk.house.gov/PublicDisclosure/FinancialDisclosure">House</a>’s and <a href="https://efdsearch.senate.gov/">Senate</a>’s financial disclosure portals, but neither provides bulk data. Software engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/tcarambat">Tim Carabat</a>’s <a href="https://senatestockwatcher.com/">Senate Stock Watcher</a> and <a href="https://housestockwatcher.com/">House Stock Watcher</a> websites fill that gap by making the transactions available to browse, query, and download. In the case of the House, where reports are still provided as PDFs, Carabat also coordinates <a href="https://contributor.housestockwatcher.com/">the manual transcription of those files</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>National revenues.</strong> UNU-WIDER’s <a href="https://www.wider.unu.edu/project/government-revenue-dataset">Government Revenue Dataset</a> “aims to present a complete picture of government revenue and tax trends over time.” The project, <a href="https://www.wider.unu.edu/about-grd">updated this month</a>, currently covers 196 countries and goes back, in most cases, to the early 1980s. It <a href="https://www.wider.unu.edu/publication/government-revenue-dataset-2021-source-selection">draws on data from OECD and IMF reports</a> and includes dozens of variables, such as total revenue, natural resource taxes, and foreign grants received. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.oecd.org/tax/tax-policy/global-revenue-statistics-database.htm">The OECD’s Global Revenue Statistics Database</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-08-01-edition/">DIP 2018.08.01</a>). [h/t <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11127-020-00788-4">Lisa Chauvet &amp; Marin Ferry</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/ErikFeiring/status/1428442876237815816">Erik Feiring</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Africa building outlines.</strong> <a href="https://sites.research.google/open-buildings/">Open Buildings</a>, a project led by Google Research’s Ghana office, has <a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2021/07/mapping-africas-buildings-with.html">published</a> a dataset of 516 million building footprints in Africa, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.12283">estimated from satellite imagery</a>. The dataset, which you can explore online and download as CSVs, spans roughly 64% of the continent. It describes each estimated footprint’s coordinates, shape, and area, plus the detection algorithm’s degree of confidence. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/USBuildingFootprints">Footprints of buildings in the US</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-07-18-edition/">DIP 2018.07.18</a>), and in <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/CanadianBuildingFootprints">Canada</a> and <a href="https://medium.com/on-location/an-open-building-outlines-dataset-for-new-zealand-eef8b558ef7a">New Zealand</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2019-09-25-edition/">DIP 2019.09.25</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>AI patents.</strong> The US Patent and Trademark Office has <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3866793">built a series of machine-learning models</a> to identify patents that involve AI technologies, such as natural language processing or computer vision. Its <a href="https://www.uspto.gov/ip-policy/economic-research/research-datasets/artificial-intelligence-patent-dataset">Artificial Intelligence Patent Dataset</a>, released in June, focuses on eight of these technologies and provides predictions of their presence (or absence) in 13.2 million granted patents and patent applications since 1976, finding hits in 11% of the documents. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/nicholas_rada/status/1408440086639702025">Nicholas Rada</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Formula One.</strong> The <a href="https://ergast.com/mrd/">Ergast Developer API</a> provides seven decades of Formula One racing results, with details on each season, race, and result since 1950, each lap time since 1996, each pit stop since 2012, and more. In addition to querying the API, you can also <a href="https://ergast.com/mrd/query/">explore the data online</a> and <a href="https://ergast.com/mrd/db/">download it in full</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: FiveThirtyEight’s “<a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/formula-one-racing/">Who’s The Best Formula One Driver Of All Time?</a>” [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-gardner-0531aa9/">Eric Gardner</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/hydrosquall">Cameron Yick</a> + <a href="https://github.com/davidor/formula1-lap-charts">David Ortiz</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send speedy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-08-25</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.08.18 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-08-18-edition</link>
      <description>US military bases and deployments, Louisiana deaths behind bars, A/B headline tests, the Magazine of Early American Datasets, and shows within shows.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>US military bases and deployments, Louisiana deaths behind bars, A/B headline tests, the Magazine of Early American Datasets, and shows within shows.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US military bases and deployments.</strong> <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/07388942211030885">Michael A. Allen et al.</a> are gathering and standardizing <a href="https://github.com/meflynn/troopdata">data on the United States military’s global presence</a>. The project’s <a href="https://github.com/meflynn/troopdata/tree/master/data-raw">CSV files</a> and <a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/troopdata/index.html">R package</a> include annual, country-level troop counts between 1950 and 2020, drawn from <a href="https://www.heritage.org/defense/report/global-us-troop-deployment-1950-2003">prior work</a> by economist <a href="https://www.hoover.org/profiles/timothy-kane">Tim Kane</a> and from the government’s <a href="https://www.dmdc.osd.mil/appj/dwp/dwp_reports.jsp">Defense Manpower Data Center</a>. They also include a listing of US military bases abroad, primarily sourced from <a href="https://www.basenation.us/"><em>Base Nation</em></a>, a book by political anthropologist <a href="https://www.davidvine.net/">David Vine</a> (who, disclosure, is a cousin of mine). <strong>Related</strong>: Vine also maintains <a href="https://dra.american.edu/islandora/object/auislandora:94927">various lists of US military bases abroad since 1776</a> and has published a follow-up book, <a href="https://www.davidvine.net/unitedstatesofwar.html"><em>The United States of War</em></a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/otir90/dataset_us_overseas_military_deployments_19502020/">u/smurfyjenkins</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Louisiana deaths behind bars.</strong> <a href="https://www.incarcerationtransparency.org/">Incarceration Transparency</a>, a project undertaken by law students and faculty at Loyola University New Orleans, has compiled data on <a href="https://www.incarcerationtransparency.org/?page_id=1425">more than 830 deaths in Louisiana jails, prisons, and juvenile detention centers</a>, primarily <a href="https://www.incarcerationtransparency.org/?page_id=3837">between 2015 and 2019</a>, based on 130+ public records requests. The information includes each decedent’s name, age, sex, race, and trial status; the date, facility, and cause of death; and other factors. <strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/08/23/a-fight-to-expose-the-hidden-human-costs-of-incarceration">The New Yorker’s recent profile of the project and the professor leading it</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-graphic/">Deaths in US jails, via Reuters</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2020-10-21-edition/">DIP 2020.10.21</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A/B headline tests.</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-021-00934-7">The Upworthy Research Archive</a> describes 32,000+ headline-testing experiments conducted in 2013–15 by <a href="https://www.upworthy.com/">Upworthy</a>, the online publication that <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2017/06/20/533529538/upworthy-was-one-of-the-hottest-sites-ever-you-wont-believe-what-happened-next">popularized a once-ubiquitous style of headline</a>. <a href="https://osf.io/jd64p/">The dataset</a>, <a href="https://natematias.medium.com/announcing-the-upworthy-research-archive-c9b11087ddeb">contributed by the publication</a> to <a href="https://upworthy.natematias.com/">a team of academics</a>, is split into three tranches for use in different phases of research. In total, it covers 150,000+ headline-plus-image permutations; for each, it provides the headline, an image identifier, the number of viewers assigned to see it, the number who clicked, <a href="https://upworthy.natematias.com/about-the-archive">and other details</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Magazine of Early American Datasets.</strong> <a href="https://repository.upenn.edu/mead/">MEAD</a>, as the publication acronymizes itself, “provides sweet, intoxicating data for your investigations of early North America and the Atlantic World.” <a href="http://commonplace.online/article/constructing-the-magazine-of-early-american-datasets-mead-an-invitation-to-share-and-use-data-about-early-america/">The initiative</a>, affiliated with the University of Pennsylvania, hosts a few dozen datasets on a range of topics; many focus on Pennsylvania and on slavery, while other subjects include <a href="https://repository.upenn.edu/mead/25/">George Washington’s shipping invoices</a> and <a href="https://repository.upenn.edu/mead/28/">the 19th century children’s book industry</a>. [h/t <a href="https://noahveltman.com/">Noah Veltman</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Shows within shows.</strong> <a href="https://nestflix.fun/">Nestflix</a>, a new website by designer/developer <a href="https://lynnandtonic.com/">Lynn Fisher</a>, catalogs more than 400 fictional films and TV shows that appear within actual films and TV shows. For instance: 30 Rock’s <a href="https://nestflix.fun/the-rural-juror/"><em>The Rural Juror</em></a> and Home Alone’s <a href="https://nestflix.fun/angels-with-filthy-souls/"><em>Angels with Filthy Souls</em></a>. The project <a href="https://github.com/lynnandtonic/nestflix.fun">is open-source</a>; the <a href="https://github.com/lynnandtonic/nestflix.fun/tree/main/src/data">data files for each item</a> include the title, a description, a quotation, the parent show/film, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send nested feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-08-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.08.11 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-08-11-edition</link>
      <description>COVID-era school enrollments, eviction laws, targeted mass killings, European politics in the news, and Seattle street clocks.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>COVID-era school enrollments, eviction laws, targeted mass killings, European politics in the news, and Seattle street clocks.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-era school enrollments.</strong> A collaboration led by Stanford University’s <a href="https://biglocalnews.org">Big Local News</a> has gathered (and standardized) recent enrollment figures from 33 state education departments. The resulting dataset, which spans ~70,000 public schools, can be <a href="https://purl.stanford.edu/zf406jp4427">downloaded in bulk</a> and <a href="https://stanford-school-enrollment-project.datasette.io/">explored online</a>. Most states provided data down to the grade level; some also provided student counts by gender, race, ethnicity, ELL status, homelessness, economic status, and/or disability. The timeframes vary, but include at least the 2019–20 and 2020–21 school years for each state. See the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1WRm4KZPDGL1USPaf0E1AIa7gbyeKncv04Pg_rM1N7po/edit">documentation</a> for details. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/07/us/covid-kindergarten-enrollment.html">The Kindergarten Exodus</a>” (NYT), “<a href="https://edsource.org/2021/how-going-remote-led-to-dramatic-drops-in-public-school-students/659005">How going remote led to dramatic drops in public school students</a>” (EdSource), and a <a href="https://cepa.stanford.edu/content/revealed-preferences-school-reopening-evidence-public-school-disenrollment">new academic study</a>. [h/t <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2021/Aug/8/school-enrollment/">Simon Willison</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/cephillips/status/1424048330150072323">Cheryl Phillips</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Eviction laws.</strong> The <a href="https://www.lsc.gov/about-lsc/who-we-are">Legal Services Corporation</a>, a nonprofit that <a href="https://www.lsc.gov/initiatives/effect-state-local-laws-evictions">Congress has directed</a> to study local eviction procedures and their effects, has partnered with Temple University to compile a <a href="https://www.lsc.gov/initiatives/effect-state-local-laws-evictions/lsc-eviction-laws-database">database of eviction laws in all US states and territories</a>, and in a sample of 30 cities. It lists the causes for which landlords can evict tenants, the remedies available to unlawfully evicted tenants, filing fees, service requirements, and much more, with pointers to the relevant sections of each law. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://evictionlab.org/map/">Eviction rates</a> from <a href="https://evictionlab.org/about/">the Eviction Lab</a>. (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2018-04-18-edition/">DIP 2018.04.18</a>). [h/t <a href="https://datainnovation.org/2021/07/curating-eviction-laws-in-the-united-states/">Morgan Stevens</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Targeted mass killings.</strong> The <a href="https://politicsir.cass.anu.edu.au/research/projects/atrocity-forecasting">Atrocity Forecasting Project</a> has constructed (and <a href="https://twitter.com/goldsmithbe/status/1422776719631474690">recently updated</a>) a <a href="https://politicsir.cass.anu.edu.au/about-targeted-mass-killing-dataset">dataset of targeted mass killings</a>, which it defines as “the direct killing of noncombatant members of a group by an organized armed force or collective with the intent of destroying the group, or intimidating the group by creating a perception of imminent threat to its survival.” The dataset includes 207 such episodes from 1946 to 2020; it lists each atrocity’s timing and location, targeted groups, type of perpetrator, intent, severity, and other aspects.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>European politics in the news.</strong> Projects at the <a href="https://poldem.eui.eu/">Observatory for Political Conflict and Democracy</a> analyze newspaper articles to construct <a href="https://poldem.eui.eu/download/">datasets</a> about election campaigns, protest events, and public debates <a href="https://poldem.eui.eu/data-overview/">across a range of European countries</a>. The projects’ <a href="https://poldem.eui.eu/codebooks/">codebooks</a> describe how they select the articles — often spanning multiple decades — and categorize the people, parties, actions, and issues in them. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/njdullaghan">Neil Dullaghan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Seattle street clocks.</strong> In 2004, Seattle historian <a href="http://ro-ket.com/">Rob Ketcherside</a> began a quest to find every public clock in the city, past and present. In 2015, he <a href="http://ba-kground.com/clock-db-where-seattles-street-clocks-were/">gathered his findings</a> into <a href="https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.1455478">a dataset</a> that identifies each clock, owner, and piece of supporting evidence, which he <a href="https://twitter.com/ro_ket/status/1405187161339535374">continues to update</a>. Ketcherside has also compiled datasets of <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/dataset/Drive-In_Public_Markets/3427760">drive-in public markets</a>, <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/dataset/Seattle_Streets_Renamed_over_time/1387714">Seattle street renamings</a>, and <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/dataset/New_Structures_1890_Seattle/1341924">the city’s new buildings in 1890</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send horological feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-08-11</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.07.14 edition</title>
      <link>http://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2021-07-14-edition</link>
      <description>Refugees resettled in the US, Arizona migrant deaths, Canadian candidates, NBER working papers, and lightning intensity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Refugees resettled in the US, Arizona migrant deaths, Canadian candidates, NBER working papers, and lightning intensity.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>👋 📅 Data Is Plural will be taking a short break, with plans to return in August.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Refugees resettled in the US.</strong> <a href="https://www.refugeeresettlementdata.com/">Axel Dreher et al.</a> have published <a href="https://www.refugeeresettlementdata.com/data.html">person-level data on 2.5+ million refugees</a> who arrived in the US between 1975 and 2008. The anonymized records, obtained from the <a href="https://www.archives.gov/">National Archives</a> and originally collected by the <a href="https://acf.hhs.gov/orr">Office of Refugee Resettlement</a>, indicate each refugee’s country and date of birth, marital and family status, education level and English proficiency, date of US arrival, US city of resettlement, and more. The researchers also combined these records with public reports from the <a href="https://www.wrapsnet.org/">Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration</a> (<a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com/archive/2015-11-25-edition/">DIP 2015.11.25</a>) to create a geocoded dataset of annual resettlements by citizenship and destination city from 1975 to 2018. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ParsonsEcon/status/1409797812540252163">Chris Parsons</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Arizona migrant deaths.</strong> The <a href="https://humaneborders.info/">Arizona OpenGIS Initiative for Deceased Migrants</a> is a collaboration between <a href="https://webcms.pima.gov/government/medical_examiner/">Pima County’s Office of the Medical Examiner</a> and <a href="https://humaneborders.org/">Humane Borders</a>, a nonprofit that <a href="https://humaneborders.org/water-stations/">maintains water stations in the Sonoran Desert</a>. “Although each organization has a distinct mission, both are committed to the common vision of raising awareness about migrant deaths and lessening the suffering of families by helping to provide closure through the identification of the deceased and the return of remains.” The initiative’s <a href="https://humaneborders.info/app/map.asp">maps and dataset</a> provide details on 3,700+ deaths since 1990, including the deceased’s name, sex, age, and cause of death; their body’s location and condition; and the date reported. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/oargueso">Olaya Argüeso Pérez</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Canadian candidates.</strong> PhD candidate <a href="https://semrasevi.com/">Semra Sevi</a> recently <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/canadian-journal-of-political-science-revue-canadienne-de-science-politique/article/abs/who-runs-canadian-federal-and-ontario-provincial-candidates-from-1867-to-2019/2B18F0CB2DA35529340386C548750FC4">compiled</a> a <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/ABFNSQ">dataset</a> of 44,000+ candidates for Canadian federal office from 1867 to 2019 (and similar for Ontario provincial candidates). It lists each candidate’s name, gender, birth year, occupation, party, and incumbency status, plus the election’s date, riding, and outcome. And a <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/MI5XQ6">new dataset</a> from <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/canadian-journal-of-political-science-revue-canadienne-de-science-politique/article/abs/new-dataset-on-the-demographics-of-canadian-federal-election-candidates/62FE243F387DA88718C825961AB24C10">Anna Johnson et al.</a> delves into the demographics of 4,516 Canadian federal candidates from 2008 to 2019, including their gender, age, race, Indigenous background, occupational category, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/marsmailes">Marina Smailes</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/e_tolley/status/1409517394893193216">Erin Tolley</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NBER working papers.</strong> Since 1973, the <a href="https://www.nber.org/">National Bureau of Economic Research</a>’s <a href="https://www.nber.org/about-nber">1,500+ affiliated researchers</a> have published 29,000+ (pre-peer review) articles through the organization’s <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers">working papers series</a>. It <a href="https://www2.nber.org/RePEc/nbr/nberwo/">provides structured information about each paper</a>, using <a href="https://ideas.repec.org/t/papertemplate.html">a template</a> from the <a href="http://repec.org/">RePEc project</a>. PhD student <a href="https://bldavies.com/">Ben Davies</a> has <a href="https://bldavies.com/blog/introducing-nberwp/">converted those files</a> into <a href="https://github.com/bldavies/nberwp">CSV tables and an R package</a> listing each paper’s title, publication month, ID, and authors. [h/t <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/apalbright/home">Alex Albright</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Lightning intensity.</strong> The <a href="https://wwlln.net/">World Wide Lightning Location Network</a> uses radio sensors to detect the location and power of 200+ million lightning strokes per year. Access to WWLLN’s raw, detailed data costs money but earth scientists <a href="http://web.hku.hk/~jkaplan/">Jed O. Kaplan</a> and <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Katie-Hong-Kiu-Lau">Katie Hong-Kiu Lau</a> have <a href="https://essd.copernicus.org/articles/13/3219/2021/">converted it</a> into a few public-access <a href="https://zenodo.org/record/4882792">gridded-globe timeseries of lightning activity from 2010 to 2020</a> — daily and monthly strokes per km<sup>2</sup>, and monthly stroke power. [h/t <a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/">Robin Sloan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ⚡️ feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk/edit#gid=0">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Visit <a href="https://www.data-is-plural.com">data-is-plural.com</a> to subscribe and browse past editions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2021-07-14</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
