<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Is Plural</title>
    <link>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</link>
    <description>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.29 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-29-edition</link>
      <description>Time use surveys, dams, Spanish migration, darknet markets, and (more) vanity plate applications.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Time use surveys, dams, Spanish migration, darknet markets, and (more) vanity plate applications.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>How we spend our time.</strong> Ever year since 2003, the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/tus/home.htm">American Time Use Survey</a>, has been measuring how much time we spend sleeping, eating, and working; with friends, with family, and alone; and much more. Unlike <a href="https://www.timeuse.org/information/access-data">many other time use surveys</a>, the ATUS’s <a href="https://www.bls.gov/tus/data.htm">respondent-level datasets</a> are freely available to the general public. Other time use surveys with downloadable data include the <a href="https://dataverse.unc.edu/dataverse/rlms-hse">Russia Longitudinal Monitoring Survey</a> and a <a href="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/205/study-description">Kosovo time use survey</a> sponsored by the Millennium Challenge Corporation. <strong>Related</strong>: Through <a href="https://ipums.org">IPUMS</a>, you can build custom data extracts <a href="https://www.atusdata.org/atus/">of the ATUS</a>, <a href="https://www.ahtusdata.org/ahtus/">of historical US time survey data</a>, and <a href="https://www.mtusdata.org/mtus/">of the Multinational Time Use Study</a> (registration required). <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://flowingdata.com/2019/07/16/how-the-american-work-day-changed-in-15-years/">How the American Work Day Changed in 15 Years</a>” and “<a href="https://flowingdata.com/2019/03/06/women-men-timeuse/">A Day in the Life: Women and Men</a>,” two visualizations by <a href="https://twitter.com/flowingdata">Nathan Yau</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Petrit/status/1043413638068006912">Petrit Selimi</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Dams.</strong> The <a href="https://globaldamwatch.org/goodd/">Global Georeferenced Database of Dams</a> contains <a href="https://springernature.figshare.com/collections/GOODD_a_global_dataset_of_more_than_38_000_georeferenced_dams/4648214">geographic data on more than 38,000 dams and their watersheds</a>. The project, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0362-5">published by geographers at King’s College London</a>, is based on a combination of satellite imagery, national registries, and other sources. At least one co-author <a href="https://twitter.com/drarnoutvans/status/1219664646107533318">has been working on the project since 2008</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JIDA1983/status/1220374752533131264">Jida Wang</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Three decades of Spanish migration.</strong> Spain’s national statistics institute publishes <a href="https://github.com/ECLaboratorio/unidad-de-datos/tree/master/proyectos/migraciones_espana">annual microdata on the relocation of residents</a> within, into, and out of the country. The datasets indicate each relocator’s gender and age, birthplace, previous location, and destination — down to the municipality for locations within Spain. Currently, the records cover 1988 to 2018. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=&amp;sl=es&amp;tl=en&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.elconfidencial.com%2Feconomia%2F2019-09-27%2Fexodo-urbano-espana-migraciones-provincias_2240119%2F&amp;sandbox=1">El Confidencial’s report on intra-provincial migration patterns</a>, using this data, and <a href="https://github.com/ECLaboratorio/unidad-de-datos/tree/master/proyectos/migraciones_espana">related GitHub repository</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/a4bbc86cc07b/preview-222-in-other-news-3750685">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Darknet market survival.</strong> The researcher who goes by “<a href="https://www.gwern.net/Links">Gwern</a>” maintains a <a href="https://www.gwern.net/DNM-survival">dataset of more than 80 darknet marketplaces</a> founded between 2011 and 2015. For each market (such as the infamous Silk Road), the dataset lists when it began, when it closed, why it closed, its URL, what cryptocurrencies it accepted, whether guns were allowed to be sold, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>California vanity plates.</strong> Through a public records request, <a href="https://twitter.com/veltman">Noah Veltman</a> has obtained data on <a href="https://github.com/veltman/ca-license-plates">more than 23,000 personalized license plate applications</a> flagged for review by the California DMV. For each flagged application, the dataset contains the applicant’s justification, comments from the state’s reviewers, and the proposal’s outcome. The reviewers rejected about 80% of the proposals, including those believed to be referencing racial slurs, swearing, drugs, sex, violence, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/datanews/license-plates">New York vanity plate applications</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2015-10-21-edition">DIP 2015.10.21</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send vain feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-01-29</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.22 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-22-edition</link>
      <description>China’s projects abroad, radio/TV broadcast areas, street sprawl, cannabis tests, and backyard ice rinks.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>China’s projects abroad, radio/TV broadcast areas, street sprawl, cannabis tests, and backyard ice rinks.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>China’s projects abroad.</strong> The <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/about">AidData research lab</a> at the College of William &amp; Mary has published several datasets on China’s international soft-power efforts, including the <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/blog/aiddata-releases-first-ever-global-dataset-on-chinas-development-spending-spree">first-ever</a> dataset of <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/data/geocoded-chinese-global-official-finance-dataset">government-financed development projects abroad</a> (covering 3,485 projects between 2000 and 2014) and a structured dataset of <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/data/chinas-public-diplomacy-dashboard-dataset-version-1-0">diplomacy efforts in 25 Asia/Pacific countries</a> between 2000 and 2016. [h/t <a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/global-chinese-financing-is-fueling-megaprojects">Nick Routley</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/simongerman600/status/1216764349026574337">Simon Kuestenmacher</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Broadcast geography.</strong> To construct her maps “<a href="https://erdavis.com/2020/01/04/visualizing-the-geography-of-fm-radio/">visualizing the geography of FM radio</a>” in the US, <a href="https://erdavis.com/about/">Erin Davis</a> combined the Federal Communication Commission’s <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/radio/fm-service-contour-data-points">service contour data</a> — the area where reception for a station “is generally protected from interference caused by other stations” — with the agency’s <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/radio/fm-query">radio station licensing data</a> and genre information from <a href="https://radio-locator.com">radio-locator.com</a>. The FCC also provides <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/television/tv-service-contour-data-points">service contour data for broadcast television</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="http://reboot.fcc.gov/license-view/">All FCC-issued licenses</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-09-07-edition">DIP 2016.09.07</a>). [h/t <a href="https://us5.campaign-archive.com/?u=77ecabbd32e97a6caa9d7d40b&amp;id=c55fd8b814">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Street sprawl.</strong> Using 46 million kilometers of <a href="https://planet.openstreetmap.org">data from OpenStreetMap</a>, <a href="https://wellbeing.ihsp.mcgill.ca">Christopher Barrington-Leigh</a> and <a href="https://people.ucsc.edu/~adammb/">Adam Millard-Ball</a> have <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0223078">published</a> “the first systematic and globally commensurable measures of street-network sprawl based on graph-theoretic and geographic concepts.” You can explore their findings via an <a href="https://sprawlmap.org/">interactive map</a> and also download <a href="https://sprawl.research.mcgill.ca/publications/2020-PNAS-sprawl/website-FAQ.html">aggregate metrics</a> for nearly 200 cities and more than 160 countries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/robroc">Roberto Rocha</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cannabis tests.</strong> Despite US adults increasingly gaining state-legal access to cannabis, “no universal standards for laboratory testing protocols currently exist,” write <a href="https://twitter.com/trikomes">Nick Jikomes</a> and <a href="https://michaelzoorob.com/about/">Michael Zoorob</a>, in a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-22755-2">March 2018 article</a> for <em>Scientific Reports</em>. “To investigate these concerns, we analyzed a publicly available seed-to-sale traceability dataset from Washington state containing measurements of the cannabinoid content of legal cannabis products from state-certified laboratories.” The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/E8TQSD">dataset</a>, obtained by the authors via public records requests, includes more than 200,000 test results over the course of three years.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Backyard ice rinks.</strong> <a href="https://www.rinkwatch.org/">RinkWatch</a> “asks people who love outdoor skating to help environmental scientists monitor winter weather conditions” by reporting the conditions of their backyard ice rinks. The project’s <a href="https://www.rinkwatch.org/download.html">downloadable data</a> includes more than 30,000 “skateable” / “not skateable” observations of more than 1,200 rinks since 2012. <strong>As mentioned in</strong>: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/13/travel/ice-skating-Quebec.html">Last week’s New York Times article</a> about outdoor skating trails in Quebec.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send icy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-01-22</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.15 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-15-edition</link>
      <description>Missing migrants, global antitrust, microbes, geographic renaming proposals, and the life of a supercomputer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Missing migrants, global antitrust, microbes, geographic renaming proposals, and the life of a supercomputer.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Missing migrants.</strong> The <a href="https://missingmigrants.iom.int/about">Missing Migrants Project</a> “tracks deaths of migrants, including refugees and asylum-seekers, who have gone missing along mixed migration routes worldwide.” Research for the project, an initiative of the <a href="https://www.iom.int">International Organization for Migration</a>, began after the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2013_Lampedusa_migrant_shipwreck">fatal Lampedusa shipwrecks</a> of October 2013. For each incident, the project’s <a href="https://missingmigrants.iom.int/downloads">datasets</a> specify the location, the number of people who died, the number who are missing, the number who survived, the sources of information, the source quality, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/ondata/the-list">European migration deaths</a>, 1993 to May 2018 (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2018-07-18-edition">DIP 2018.07.18</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/eiwiww/dataset_where_migrants_die/">u/cavedave</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/tjukanov/status/1212641818975916032">Topi Tjukanov</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Global antitrust.</strong> The <a href="https://comparativecompetitionlaw.org">Comparative Competition Law project</a> classifies the legal provisions and enforcement of antitrust laws around the world, over time. The project is run by law professors <a href="https://www.law.columbia.edu/faculty/anu-bradford">Anu Bradford</a> and <a href="http://www.adamchilton.org">Adam Chilton</a>, and features several <a href="http://comparativecompetitionlaw.org/data/">datasets and detailed codebooks</a>. (They require an email address but no formal registration.) <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/adamschilton/status/1192498999204483074">Chilton’s introductory Twitter thread</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/dusek_libor/status/1192520366373187586">Libor Dusek</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Microorganisms.</strong> The <a href="https://microbe.directory/">Microbe Directory</a> is an attempt to profile more than 7,000 bacteria, viruses, archaea, and other microorganisms. The directory <a href="https://microbe.directory/developers">can be downloaded</a> <a href="https://github.com/microbe-directory/microbe-directory">in bulk</a> and describes the microbes’ optimal temperature, optimal pH, Gram stain, pathogenicity, antimicrobial resistance, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Geographic (re)naming proposals.</strong> When someone wants to officially name or rename a geographic feature of the United States — such as a mountain, creek, or island — they file a proposal with the <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names">US Board on Geographic Names</a>. Those proposals end up on the agency’s “<a href="https://geonames.usgs.gov/apex/f?p=geonames_web:review_lists:0:::::">Action List</a>,” the most recent year of which can be downloaded as a spreadsheet. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names/download-gnis-data">The Board’s database of every US geographic name</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2015-10-21-edition">DIP 2015.10.21</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/veltman/status/1201906847382269953">Noah Veltman</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The life of a supercomputer.</strong> <a href="http://fusionwiki.ciemat.es/wiki/CIEMAT">CIEMAT</a> — a public institution in Spain that studies energy and the environment — <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340919313629">has published</a> nearly a decade of <a href="https://www.cse.huji.ac.il/labs/parallel/workload/l_ciemat_euler/index.html">processing receipts from its Euler supercomputer</a>. The records, which span the supercomputer’s entire lifetime, contain metadata for more than 9 million computing jobs, including timestamps, memory usage, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send CPU-intensive feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-01-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.01 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-01-edition</link>
      <description>Water quality, legislator ideology, Google copyright complaints, California university history, and game show risk-taking.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Water quality, legislator ideology, Google copyright complaints, California university history, and game show risk-taking.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>But first ... a small New Year’s gift for DIP readers: <a href="https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive/blob/master/README.md">You can now receive the newsletter via RSS</a>.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Global water quality.</strong> The UN’s <a href="https://gemstat.org">GEMStat project</a> provides “scientifically-sound data” on freshwater quality around the world. The <a href="https://gemstat.org/data/data-portal/">data portal</a> lets visitors <a href="https://gemstat.bafg.de/applications/public.html?publicuser=PublicUser">explore</a> and <a href="https://gemstat.org/custom-data-request/">download</a> water-sample results from thousands of stations in more than 80 countries. The information available for each sample varies, but it can include chemical, biological, and physical properties. <strong>Note</strong>: Not all locations have been sampled recently, and data downloads are limited to 500 stations at a time and for noncommercial purposes only. <strong>Related</strong>: “<a href="https://openknowledge.worldbank.org/handle/10986/32245">The Invisible Water Crisis</a>,” a World Bank report from last year that used the GEMStat data. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/rylan_dobson/status/1165142955243515904">Rylan Dobson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>State legislator ideologies.</strong> Political scientists <a href="https://research.bshor.com">Boris Shor</a> and <a href="https://www.princeton.edu/~nmccarty/">Nolan McCarty</a>’s have <a href="https://americanlegislatures.com/faq/">assigned ideology scores</a>, on a conservative-to-liberal scale, to every US lawmaker in all 50 state legislatures. The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/6QWX7Q">most recent update</a>, published May 2018, covers more than 22,000 legislators from 1993 through 2016. Shor and McCarty derived the numeric scores from a combination of legislative voting records and responses to Vote Smart’s “<a href="https://justfacts.votesmart.org/about/political-courage-test/">Political Courage Test</a>.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Copyright complaints.</strong> Google has received millions of requests from copyright holders to delist billions of URLs from its search results. The company’s <a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com">transparency reports</a> include a section where you can <a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/copyright/overview">explore and download data</a> about these requests. One of the datasets describes 8.5 million delisting requests, with their dates, copyright holders, numbers of URLs targeted, and links to more details in <a href="https://www.lumendatabase.org">the Lumen archive</a>. Another contains every web domain targeted, while another lists the URLs for which Google says it took no action. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/54kv4e/database_of_copyright_removal_requests_made_to/">Dan Nguyen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>California university history.</strong> The <a href="https://uccliometric.org">UC ClioMetric History Project</a> is digitizing decades of administrative records from the University of California and other schools in the state (such as USC and Stanford). So far, they’ve uploaded data on more than <a href="https://uccliometric.org/students/">750,000 student enrollments</a>, <a href="https://uccliometric.org/faculty/">tens of thousands of faculty members</a>, and <a href="https://uccliometric.org/courses/">800,000 courses</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Game show gambles.</strong> To study how people make decisions in risky situations, a team of academics <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=636508">analyzed contestants’ choices</a> in 100+ episodes of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deal_or_No_Deal">Deal or No Deal</a> that aired in the Netherlands, Germany, and the US. Their dataset is available <a href="https://www.openicpsr.org/openicpsr/project/113232/version/V1/view">through ICPSR</a> (registration required) and <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/2018*/https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.98.1.38">the Wayback Machine</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send risky feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-01-01</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.12.18 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-12-18-edition</link>
      <description>Emissions, the Arab Barometer, Duterte’s drug war deaths, think tank citations, and jump scares.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Emissions, the Arab Barometer, Duterte’s drug war deaths, think tank citations, and jump scares.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Emissions indicators.</strong> The <a href="https://climateactiontracker.org">Climate Action Tracker</a> is “an independent scientific analysis” that keeps tabs on 32 countries’ progress on tackling climate change. Through its <a href="https://climateactiontracker.org/data-portal/">data portal</a>, you can explore the project’s dozens of indicators — such as emissions per capita and renewable energy capacity — and also download the data in bulk. The countries covered include “the biggest emitters and a representative sample of smaller emitters,” and account for “about 80% of global emissions and approximately 70% of global population.” [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>MENA public opinion.</strong> <a href="https://www.arabbarometer.org/about/">The Arab Barometer</a> has “been conducting high quality and reliable public opinion surveys in the Middle East and North Africa since 2006,” and bills itself as “the largest repository of publicly available data on the views of men and women in the MENA region.” You can <a href="https://www.arabbarometer.org/survey-data/data-downloads/">download raw survey data</a> or explore it through the Barometer’s <a href="https://www.arabbarometer.org/survey-data/data-analysis-tool/">online analysis tool</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ChrisMarsicano/status/1201970565029879808">Chris Marsicano</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Duterte’s drug war deaths.</strong> In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philippine_Drug_War">the Philippines’ drug war</a>, President Rodrigo Duterte has given police broad permission to kill suspected drug dealers. But an <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2019/08/philippines-dead-rodrigo-duterte-drug-war/595978/">investigation by reporters at the Columbia Journalism School</a> earlier this year found that “large numbers of killings [...] have been excluded from official counts.” The reporters collected data from <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6133399-Data-Sources-June04.html">23 sources</a> on 2,320 killings by police and unidentified assailants between July 2016 and December 2017 in three municipalities. <a href="https://data.world/stabile-center/ph-drug-war">Their dataset</a> (free account required to download, <a href="https://github.com/HRDAG/PH-drug-related-killings/tree/master/import/input">alternate version here</a>) indicates the month, local police station, whether police recorded the death, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: Because so many deaths appear to have gone unreported, the journalists worked with the <a href="https://hrdag.org/">Human Rights Data Analysis Group</a> to <a href="https://github.com/HRDAG/PH-drug-related-killings">estimate</a> the total number of undocumented deaths. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/shirafu">Scilla Alecci</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Think tank citations.</strong> <a href="http://andrewsthompson.co/">Andrew Thompson</a> scoured three years of articles from nine publications — Axios, BuzzFeed News, The Economist, The Hill, The New York Times, Politico, Vice News, Vox, and The Wall Street Journal — for mentions of any organization in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_think_tanks_in_the_United_States">Wikipedia’s list of US think tanks</a>. The <a href="https://components.one/datasets/think-tank-mentions-in-nine-publications-2016-2018/">resulting spreadsheet</a> contains more than 15,000 entries, relating to 172 think tanks. Each entry lists the publication, the think tank, the relevant sentence, and a link to the article.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Boo!</strong> <a href="https://wheresthejump.com/">Where’s The Jump</a> aims “to provide a comprehensive listing of the jump scares in horror and thriller movies.” The website doesn’t provide data downloads, but <a href="https://wheresthejump.com/full-movie-list/">its list of 540+ movies</a> — with year of release, “jump count,” “jump scare rating,” availability on Netflix, and more — can be copy-pasted into a spreadsheet. <strong>Related</strong>: “<a href="https://wheresthejump.com/the-lazy-directors-guide-to-jump-scares/">The Lazy Director’s Guide To Jump Scares</a>.” [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-the-100th-edition-213612">Sophie Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send frightening feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-12-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.12.11 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-12-11-edition</link>
      <description>Death row, environmental treaties, spelling fixes, book ratings, and yearbook photos.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Death row, environmental treaties, spelling fixes, book ratings, and yearbook photos.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Death row.</strong> “Forty-three years after the Supreme Court reversed course and reinstated the death penalty, reliable data on the individuals sent to death row is maddeningly difficult to obtain.” <a href="https://theintercept.com/series/the-condemned/">So reporters at The Intercept</a> “set out to compile a comprehensive dataset on everyone sentenced to die in active death penalty jurisdictions since 1976.” <a href="https://github.com/firstlookmedia/the-condemned-data">The resulting database</a> contains more than 7,300 entries; for each person, it contains demographics, sentencing information, whether the person is still on death row, whether they’ve been exonerated, and more. <strong>Previously:</strong> <a href="https://endofitsrope.com/using-the-database/">Death sentences</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2018-08-01-edition">DIP 2018.08.01</a>), <a href="https://deathpenaltyinfo.org/executions/execution-database">executions</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-05-15-edition">DIP 2019.05.15</a>), and <a href="https://selectstarsql.com/frontmatter.html#dataset">last words</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-03-06-edition">DIP 2019.03.06</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Environmental treaties.</strong> The <a href="https://iea.uoregon.edu/">International Environmental Agreements Database Project</a> describes <a href="https://iea.uoregon.edu/iea-project-contents">more than 3,700</a> “international environmental treaties, conventions, and other agreements with links to text, membership, performance data, secretariat, and summary statistics.” The database, hosted at the University of Oregon, includes agreements from the 1850s to the present and can be <a href="https://iea.uoregon.edu/base-agreement-list">queried online</a>. It also includes detailed pages for each treaty, such as <a href="https://iea.uoregon.edu/membership-long-form/5046">this one for the UN’s Paris Agreement</a>. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Spelling fixes.</strong> The <a href="https://github.com/mhagiwara/github-typo-corpus">GitHub Typo Corpus</a> contains structured data on misspellings, bad grammar, and the ways they've been corrected. To build the dataset, <a href="http://masatohagiwara.net/">Masato Hagiwara</a> and <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/masatomita/">Masato Mita</a> analyzed the “commits” — sets of changes to files, typically accompanied by short summaries — made to tens of thousands of projects on the code-sharing platform GitHub. With “more than 350k edits and 65M characters in more than 15 languages,” <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1911.12893">the authors say</a> it's “the largest dataset of misspellings to date.” [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/e5hdxt/spelling_and_grammar_correction_corpus_from/">u/Loves_Portisheads</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Book ratings.</strong> In 2004, computer scientist <a href="http://dbis.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/team/ziegler/cai">Cai-Nicolas Ziegler</a> scraped (with permission) <a href="http://www2.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~cziegler/BX/">433,000 numeric ratings of 186,000 books by 78,000 users</a> on the book-tracking website <a href="https://www.bookcrossing.com/">BookCrossing</a>. For most users, the data includes their stated city and age. [h/t <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02321">Ningshan Zhang, Kyle Schmaus, and Patrick O. Perry</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Yearbook photos.</strong> Over at The Pudding, <a href="https://www.elle-obrien.com/">Elle O'Brien</a> and <a href="http://jandiehmdesigns.com/">Jan Diehm</a> <a href="https://pudding.cool/2019/11/big-hair/">chart the rise and fall of “big hair”</a>. To ’do it, they <a href="https://github.com/andronovhopf/Bigdata_Bighair">combed through</a> a <a href="http://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~shiry/projects/yearbooks/yearbooks.html">public dataset of 37,921 portraits</a>, culled from the yearbooks of 115 American high schools in 26 states between 1905 and 2013. [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-inheritance-tax-nightingale-and-wine-212281">Sophie Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send permed feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-12-11</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.12.04 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-12-04-edition</link>
      <description>Income inequality, ambassadorial qualifications, Samoa’s measles outbreak, science PhD candidates, and the Database of British and Irish Hills.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Income inequality, ambassadorial qualifications, Samoa’s measles outbreak, science PhD candidates, and the Database of British and Irish Hills.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Income inequality around the world, over time.</strong> Political scientist <a href="https://fsolt.org/">Frederick Solt</a>’s <a href="https://fsolt.org/swiid/">Standardized World Income Inequality Database</a> provides annual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gini_coefficient">Gini coefficients</a> for 196 countries and territories. For many, the calculations go back to the 1960s. The database draws on <a href="https://fsolt.org/swiid/swiid_source/">hundreds of sources</a>, including international organizations, national statistical offices, and academic studies. In an <a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/mwnje/">accompanying paper</a>, Solt argues that the SWIID represents an improvement over other similar efforts, such as the United Nations University’s <a href="https://www.wider.unu.edu/project/wiid-world-income-inequality-database">World Income Inequality Database</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-06-01-edition">DIP 2016.06.01</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/YJuliaJung/status/1200986856881610753">Y. Julia Jung</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Ambassadorial qualifications.</strong> The Foreign Service Act of 1980 requires US presidents to provide Congress a “report on the demonstrated competence” for each ambassadorial nominee. In 2014, the government began <a href="https://www.state.gov/resources-bureau-of-human-resources/">disclosing these records</a>, which had long been held secret. But the government’s policy applied only to new nominees. Law professor <a href="https://ryanscoville.com/about/">Ryan Scoville</a>, however, used the Freedom of Information Act to pry loose the rest — more than three decades of concise biographies — and, earlier this year, <a href="https://ryanscoville.com/2019/02/13/certificates-of-competency-for-nominees-to-be-chiefs-of-mission-1980-2014/">put them online</a>, accompanied by a dataset that describes the nominees’ qualifications and political contributions. <strong>Related</strong>: “<a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3333988">Unqualified Ambassadors</a>,” Scoville’s <em>Duke Law Journal</em> article on the topic, and <a href="https://www.lawfareblog.com/troubling-trends-ambassadorial-appointments-1980-present">his summary in <em>Lawfare</em></a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IRstudies/comments/e31izg/dataset_the_professional_qualifications_and/">u/smurfyjenkins</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Samoa’s measles outbreak.</strong> The Samoan government has been <a href="https://twitter.com/samoagovt/status/1201637336515112960">tweeting updates</a> regarding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019_Samoa_measles_outbreak">the country’s measles crisis</a>. Epidemiologist <a href="https://bitsandbugs.io/chris-von-csefalvay/">Chris von Csefalvay</a> has been <a href="https://github.com/chrisvoncsefalvay/samoa-measles-2019">converting those tweets into a simple dataset</a> that counts the number of cases and deaths (by age group) at the time of each tweet.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Science PhD candidates.</strong> Last month, <em>Nature</em> released <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-03459-7">findings</a> and <a href="https://figshare.com/s/74a5ea79d76ad66a8af8">response data</a> from its fifth survey of science graduate students. The questionnaire covered demographics, motivations, ambitions, satisfaction, mental health, and other topics. More than 6,000 students participated, including 1,000+ each living in Europe, the Americas, and Asia. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-03489-1"><em>Nature</em>’s editorial board calls for “urgent attention” to students’ mental health</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/bearore/status/1195296027567443974">Mattias Björnmalm</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>British Isle bumps.</strong> <a href="http://www.hills-database.co.uk/index.html">The Database of British and Irish Hills</a> began 20 years ago and now catalogs more than 20,000 bits of bumpy terrain. The <a href="http://www.hills-database.co.uk/downloads.html">data files</a> include detailed coordinates, map references, and descriptive characteristics. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/dvalts/status/1192513425307504645">Declan Valters</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send elevated feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-12-04</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.11.27 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-11-27-edition</link>
      <description>Blue helmets, earthquakes in Mexico, seized Greek real estate, Bollywood, and medieval monasteries.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Blue helmets, earthquakes in Mexico, seized Greek real estate, Bollywood, and medieval monasteries.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>UN blue helmets.</strong> The United Nations <a href="https://peacekeeping.un.org/en/open-data-portal">publishes data</a> describing its <a href="https://peacekeeping.un.org/en/peacekeeping-master-open-datasets">active peacekeeping missions</a> and <a href="https://peacekeeping.un.org/en/data-troop-and-police-contributions">police and military personnel</a>, plus <a href="https://peacekeeping.un.org/en/peacekeeper-fatalities">all peacekeeping fatalities since 1948</a>. <strong>Also:</strong> The International Peace Institute’s <a href="http://www.providingforpeacekeeping.org/contributions/">Peacekeeping Database</a> tracks member-countries’ historical contributions of personnel going back to 1990. <strong>Plus:</strong> Last month, researchers at Uppsala University’s Department of Peace and Conflict Research <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0022343319871978?journalCode=jpra">introduced</a> a <a href="https://www.pcr.uu.se/data/geo-pko/">Geocoded Peacekeeping Operations dataset</a>, which provides detailed information about the location and troops for all UN peacekeeping deployments in Africa from 1994 to 2014, with stated plans to extend coverage through 2018 soon. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IRstudies/comments/dmhn38/dataset_the_geocoded_peacekeeping_operations/">u/smurfyjenkins</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Earthquakes in Mexico.</strong> Researchers <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0234-z">have constructed</a> a “unified catalog” more than 5,000 earthquakes in Mexico. To do so, they standardized, deduplicated, and fact-checked quake information from more than 100 local, regional, and international sources. <a href="https://springernature.figshare.com/collections/An_updated_and_unified_earthquake_catalog_1787-2018_for_seismic_hazard_assessment_studies_in_Mexico/4492763">The final dataset</a> goes back to 1787 and details each quake’s epicenter, depth, magnitude, and sources. The researchers consider the catalog to be complete for earthquakes with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moment_magnitude_scale">moment magnitude</a> of 6+ since 1925, and for those with a magnitude of 4+ since 1990.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Seized Greek real estate.</strong> <a href="https://medium.com/athenslivegr/whose-home-is-this-f3b45d878b0b">For an article in AthensLive</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sotsideris">Sotiris Sideris</a> collected <a href="https://github.com/2109Sot/eauction_data">data on properties up for bidding</a> through <a href="https://www.eauction.gr/">eauction.gr</a>, Greece’s official website for auctioning real estate seized from over-indebted borrowers. The dataset includes 45,918 lots listed between mid-November 2017 (when the website launched) and September 1, 2019. For each lot, the dataset specifies the auction date, property characteristics, starting bid, total debt, debtor, “hastener” pursuing the auction, links to additional documentation, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bollywood.</strong> <a href="https://pncnmnp.github.io/">Parth Parikh</a>, an engineering student in Mumbai, has created <a href="https://github.com/pncnmnp/TIMDB/">The Indian Movie Database</a>, which aggregates and cross-references data on Bollywood films from <a href="https://www.imdb.com/">IMDB</a>, Wikipedia, and <a href="https://grouplens.org/datasets/movielens/">MovieLens</a>. It currently contains more than 4,700 movies released between 1950 and 2019.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Medieval monasteries.</strong> Economists <a href="https://www.qatar.cmu.edu/directory/serra-boranbay-akan/">Serra Boranbay-Akan</a> and <a href="https://www.unibo.it/sitoweb/c.guerriero/en">Carmine Guerriero</a> have <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340919310868">built a dataset</a> describing the locations and operating years of more than 3,000 Cistercian and Franciscan monasteries in 90 European regions between the years 1000 and 1600.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ascetic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-11-27</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.11.20 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-11-20-edition</link>
      <description>Chicago prosecutions, electricity prices, financial well-being, soccer play-by-play, and Central Park squirrels.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Chicago prosecutions, electricity prices, financial well-being, soccer play-by-play, and Central Park squirrels.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Chicago prosecutions.</strong> Since early 2018, the <a href="https://www.cookcountystatesattorney.org/">Cook County State's Attorney's Office</a> has been publishing <a href="https://www.cookcountystatesattorney.org/about/case-level-data">detailed data</a> on every felony case it has handled since 2010. (The office, whose jurisdiction includes Chicago, is the second-largest local prosecutorial agency in the country.) <a href="https://datacatalog.cookcountyil.gov/browse?tags=state%27s+attorney+case-level&amp;sortBy=most_accessed">The datasets</a> cover four main stages: <a href="https://datacatalog.cookcountyil.gov/Courts/Intake/3k7z-hchi">intake</a>, <a href="https://datacatalog.cookcountyil.gov/Courts/Initiation/7mck-ehwz">initiation</a>, <a href="https://datacatalog.cookcountyil.gov/Courts/Dispositions/apwk-dzx8">charging</a>, and <a href="https://datacatalog.cookcountyil.gov/Courts/Sentencing/tg8v-tm6u">sentencing</a>. <strong>Related:</strong> In a <a href="https://pudding.cool/2019/10/prosecutors/">recent Pudding article</a> copublished with <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2019/10/24/the-kim-foxx-effect-how-prosecutions-have-changed-in-cook-county">The Marshall Project</a> and <a href="https://projects.chicagoreporter.com/kim-foxx-prosecutions-20191024/">Chicago Reporter</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/matthew_daniels">Matt Daniels</a> used the data to examine how prosecutions have changed under State’s Attorney Kim Foxx, who promised reforms.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electricity prices.</strong> OpenEI’s <a href="https://openei.org/wiki/Utility_Rate_Database">Utility Rate Database</a> contains nearly 50,000 expert-verified rates — current and historical — for residential, commercial, industrial, and street-lighting electricity from thousands of US utility companies. <strong>Related:</strong> <a href="https://openei.org/wiki/Data">OpenEI’s other data offerings</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w26385">Arik Levinson and Emilson Delfino Silva</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Financial well-being.</strong> Since the mid-1980s, the US Census Bureau has periodically conducted its <a href="https://www.census.gov/sipp/">Survey of Income and Program Participation</a> and provided <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/sipp/data/datasets.html">anonymized, respondent-level data</a>. In addition to the titular topics, the <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/sipp/about/sipp-content-information.html">extensive questionnaires</a> also ask about “family dynamics, educational attainment, housing expenditures, asset ownership, health insurance, disability, child care, and food security.” <strong>Related:</strong> My colleagues <a href="https://twitter.com/scottpham">Scott Pham</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/venessawwong">Venessa Wong</a> <a href="https://github.com/BuzzFeedNews/2019-11-sipp">used SIPP’s data on familial support</a> to “<a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/venessawong/millennials-parents-stereotypes-boomers-data">finally end the myth of the lazy millennial</a>.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Soccer/football play-by-play.</strong> A group of academics has partnered with a soccer-data company <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0247-7">to publish</a> what they believe to be “the largest collection of soccer-logs ever released.” <a href="https://figshare.com/collections/Soccer_match_event_dataset/4415000">The dataset</a> describes every “event” on the field — each pass, shot, foul, tackle, penalty, and more — for the 2017/18 season of five European leagues, the 2018 World Cup, and the 2016 European championship.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Central Park squirrels.</strong> Last October, the <a href="https://www.thesquirrelcensus.com/">Squirrel Census</a> dispatched 300+ volunteers to record every squirrel they saw in Central Park. In June, the organizers published a multimedia report of their findings (<a href="https://squirrelcensus.bigcartel.com/product/central-park-squirrel-census-2019-report">at $75 each</a>). Now they’ve made the data — with each squirrel’s location, fur color, behavior, and more — <a href="https://data.cityofnewyork.us/Environment/2018-Central-Park-Squirrel-Census-Squirrel-Data/vfnx-vebw">available through New York City’s open data portal</a>. <strong>Related:</strong> <a href="https://www.citylab.com/life/2019/06/squirrel-census-results-population-central-park-nyc/592162/">CityLab has more details on the project and interviews its creator</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jmcastagnetto/status/1191418797384753152">Jesus M. Castagnetto</a> + <a href="https://github.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday#2019">Tidy Tuesday</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send furry-tailed feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-11-20</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2019.11.13 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-11-13-edition</link>
      <description>Millions of violent crimes, online news language, interwar debt, food flows, and perceived vs. real ages.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Millions of violent crimes, online news language, interwar debt, food flows, and perceived vs. real ages.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Millions of violent crimes.</strong> <a href="https://www.thetrace.org/">The Trace</a> has <a href="https://www.thetrace.org/violent-crime-data/">posted raw data</a> on 4.3 million murders, nonfatal shootings, assaults, robberies, and rapes, obtained from 56 police and sheriff’s departments in the United States. <strong>Related:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/missryley/status/1190361721526992896">Sarah Ryley's introductory Twitter thread</a>. <strong>Also related:</strong> The Trace and BuzzFeed News’ <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/sarahryley/police-unsolved-shootings">investigative reporting</a> on <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/sarahryley/5-things-to-know-about-cities-failure-to-arrest-shooters">cities’ failure to arrest shooters</a>, for which Sarah, Sean Campbell, and I <a href="https://github.com/the-trace-and-buzzfeed-news/introduction">used many of these datasets</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Online news language, updated live.</strong> <a href="https://www.gdeltproject.org/">The GDELT Project</a>’s <a href="https://blog.gdeltproject.org/announcing-the-web-news-ngram-datasets-web-ngram/">Web News Ngram</a> dataset keeps track the frequency individual words and two-word in online news around the world. The dataset incorporates news sources in <a href="https://blog.gdeltproject.org/the-languages-of-the-new-web-news-ngram-datasets-web-ngram/">142 languages</a> and provides overall word counts for every 15-minute window since January 1, 2019. An additional dataset tracks phrasings used in <a href="https://blog.gdeltproject.org/announcing-the-web-ngram-character-ngram-datasets/">10 character-based languages</a>. <strong>Previously:</strong> <a href="https://blog.gdeltproject.org/announcing-the-television-news-ngram-datasets-tv-ngram/">GDELT’s similar dataset for television news</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-08-21-edition">DIP 2019.08.21</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.kalevleetaru.com/">Kalev Leetaru</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Interwar debt.</strong> In <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WP/Issues/2019/10/25/Instruments-of-Debtstruction-A-New-Database-of-Interwar-Debt-48689">a recent working paper</a> titled “Instruments of Debtstruction,” researchers at the International Monetary Fund share a “comprehensive instrument-level database of sovereign debt for 18 advanced and emerging countries over the period 1913–46.” (The dataset currently published alongside the paper seems to be missing one of the 18 countries, Russia.) The “instruments” include bonds, credit lines, and several other forms of debt; for each instrument issued, the dataset contains the debt’s coupon rate, maturity, and currency.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Food flows.</strong> A team of researchers has developed a statistical model to <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1748-9326/ab29ae">estimate the flow of food commodities</a> between every pair of US counties in 2012. To calculate the estimates, the researchers used data from the Census’s <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/cfs.html">Commodity Flow Survey</a>, ORNL’s <a href="https://faf.ornl.gov/fafweb/">Freight Analysis Framework</a>, the USDA’s <a href="https://www.nass.usda.gov/AgCensus/">Census of Agriculture</a>, and several other sources. <strong>Related:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/we-mapped-how-food-gets-from-farms-to-your-home-125475">One of the paper’s authors summarizes the findings</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.jainfamilyinstitute.org/media/jfi-letter/">Jain Family Institute weekly newsletter</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Perceived vs. real ages.</strong> <a href="https://www.ageguess.org/">AgeGuess.org</a> asks visitors to guess people’s ages, based on photographs. You can <a href="https://www.ageguess.org/download">download a database of the results</a>, which currently includes more than 220,000 guesses about more than 4,600 photos. For each photograph, the database also includes some metadata, such as the person’s actual age. <strong>Related:</strong> <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0245-9">The researchers describe their project in <em>Scientific Data</em></a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ageless feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2019-11-13</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
