<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</id>
  <title>Data Is Plural</title>
  <updated>2020-03-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Singer-Vine</name>
    <email>jsvine@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-03-25</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.25 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-03-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>More coronavirus data, but also transportation data from the US Census, a prisoner survey, and very old companies.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 cases, continued.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/">European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control</a> has been publishing <a href="https://qap.ecdc.europa.eu/public/extensions/COVID-19/COVID-19.html">a COVID-19 dashboard</a> and <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/publications-data/download-todays-data-geographic-distribution-covid-19-cases-worldwide">daily-updated data files</a> tracking country-level cases and deaths. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/">Our World In Data</a> <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus-source-data">explains why the publication switched</a> from using the <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports">World Health Organization’s situation reports</a> to the ECDC’s data for <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus">its analyses and graphics</a>. <strong>Also related</strong>: <a href="https://usafacts.org/">USAFacts</a> is using data from state governments, local public health agencies, and Johns Hopkins University (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-11-edition">DIP 2020.03.11</a>) to <a href="https://usafacts.org/visualizations/coronavirus-covid-19-spread-map/">map US cases at the county level</a>, with the underlying data available to download. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/covid19-data/covid19-data">YY Ahn</a> + <a href="https://biglocalnews.org/">Big Local News</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Official coronavirus interventions.</strong> <a href="https://www.acaps.org/who-we-are/in-short">ACAPS</a>, a humanitarian analysis nonprofit, is cataloguing <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/acaps-covid19-government-measures-dataset">government measures implemented in response to the pandemic</a>. The measures range from quarantine policies (the most common) to electronic surveillance and the lockdown of refugee camps. As of Tuesday evening, the dataset contained 1,741 entries; each entry includes the date implemented, source links, and descriptive comments. Computational social scientist <a href="https://rexdouglass.com/">Rex Douglass</a>, meanwhile, is <a href="https://github.com/rexdouglass/TIGR">crowdsourcing a dataset of mandatory government restrictions</a>, such as bans on large gatherings, restaurant shutdowns, and shelter-in-place decrees. It has fewer entries so far, but <a href="https://github.com/rexdouglass/TIGR/blob/master/data_out/TIGR_version1_latest.tsv">more detail on US cities and states</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/NArulappan/status/1240305942798848001">Nishanth Arulappan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Getting around.</strong> The <a href="https://www.transportation.org/home/organization/">American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials</a>’ <a href="https://ctpp.transportation.org/">Census Transportation Planning Products</a> initiative “produces special tabulations of American Community Survey (ACS) data that have enhanced value for transportation planning, analysis, and strategic direction,” such as commute times, carpooling, bicycle usage, available vehicles, and more. The program’s <a href="https://ctpp.transportation.org/2012-2016-5-year-ctpp/">core dataset</a> “consists of almost 200 residence-based tables, 115 workplace-based tables and 39 flow tables (home to work) for over 325,000 geographies.” [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrienne-heller-aicp-env-sp-0b96837/">Adrienne Heller</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Prisoners, polled.</strong> <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/">The Marshall Project</a> and <a href="https://slate.com/">Slate</a> have partnered <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/03/11/how-we-pulled-off-a-groundbreaking-political-survey-behind-bars">to conduct</a> a <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/03/11/what-do-we-really-know-about-the-politics-of-people-behind-bars">survey of incarcerated people’s political views</a>. They’ve received more than 8,000 responses so far, and have made the (anonymized) data <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/incarcerated_survey">available to download</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Unfinished business.</strong> <a href="https://businessfinancing.co.uk/about/">BusinessFinancing.co.uk</a> attempted to identify <a href="https://businessfinancing.co.uk/the-oldest-company-in-almost-every-country/">the oldest, still-operating companies in every country in the world</a>, and put its findings into <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ynIAoLhz0SZYzjpwZ5e5mFzBxt6V28FTBjX7A99jq3E/edit#gid=1002274442">a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/ad9d9051041f/preview-222-in-other-news-3843345">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a> + <a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/oldest-companies/">Iman Ghosh</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send centuries-old feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-25-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>More coronavirus data, but also transportation data from the US Census, a prisoner survey, and very old companies.</summary>
    <published>2020-03-25T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-03-18</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.18 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-03-18T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Mostly coronavirus-related data, but also speed dating.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 testing in the US.</strong> The <a href="https://covidtracking.com/">COVID Tracking Project</a> “collects information from 50 US states, the District of Columbia, and 5 other U.S. territories to provide the most comprehensive testing data we can collect for the novel coronavirus, SARS-CoV-2.” The project — <a href="https://covidtracking.com/about-team/">a collaboration between <em>The Atlantic</em>, data scientist Jeff Hammerbacher, and a growing team of volunteers</a> — “attempt[s] to include positive and negative results, pending tests, and total people tested for each state or district currently reporting that data.” (Unfortunately, not all states are reporting each of those numbers, and <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking/status/1240017561757962245">private-lab testing also complicates the picture</a>.) You can access the data <a href="https://covidtracking.com/data/">online</a>, <a href="https://covidtracking.com/api/">through an API</a>, <a href="https://github.com/COVID19Tracking/covid-tracking-data">on GitHub</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking">via Twitter</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/03/how-understand-your-states-coronavirus-numbers/607921/">How to Understand Your State’s Coronavirus Numbers</a> (<em>The Atlantic</em>, March 12).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus research papers.</strong> The <a href="https://pages.semanticscholar.org/coronavirus-research">COVID-19 Open Research Dataset</a> is “a free resource of over 29,000 scholarly articles, including over 13,000 with full text, about COVID-19 and the coronavirus family of viruses for use by the global research community.” The dataset, produced by a collaboration of several research groups and the National Library of Medicine, “will be updated weekly." <strong>Related</strong>: On Monday, the White House <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/call-action-tech-community-new-machine-readable-covid-19-dataset/">issued a “call to action to the tech community”</a> regarding the dataset, asking experts “to develop new text and data mining techniques that can help the science community answer high-priority scientific questions related to COVID-19.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>WFH.</strong> <a href="https://stayinghome.club/">Stayinghome.club</a> is compiling hundreds of coronavirus-spurred <a href="https://stayinghome.club/companies.html">work-from-home policies</a>, <a href="https://stayinghome.club/universities.html">university annoucements</a>, and <a href="https://stayinghome.club/events.html">event cancellation statuses</a>. The project is <a href="https://github.com/phildini/stayinghomeclub">collaboratively edited on GitHub</a>, and includes instructions for how to add your company/university/event. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JackieKazil">Jackie Kazil</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Health security preparedness.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/about/">Global Health Security Index</a> is “the first comprehensive assessment and benchmarking of health security and related capabilities across the 195 countries” that signed on to the WHO’s 2005 <a href="https://www.who.int/ihr/legal_issues/states_parties/en/">International Health Regulations</a>. The index is built on a “framework of 140 questions, organized across 6 categories, 34 indicators, and 85 subindicators to assess a country’s capability to prevent and mitigate epidemics and pandemics.” The first edition of the index <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/news/inaugural-global-health-security-index-finds-no-country-is-prepared-for-epidemics-or-pandemics/">was released this past October</a>, and can be <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/report-model/">downloaded as a macro-enabled Excel spreadsheet</a>. The <a href="https://nhspi.org/">National Health Security Preparedness Index</a> aims to do something similar, but for US states; the <a href="https://nhspi.org/nations-ability-to-manage-health-emergencies-rises/">2019 results</a> are also <a href="https://nhspi.org/tools-resources/2019-release-health-security-data-explorer/nhspi_2019_data_download/">available as a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="https://biglocalnews.org/">Big Local News</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Speed dating.</strong> Between 2002 and 2004, professors <a href="https://twitter.com/RFisman">Ray Fisman</a> and <a href="https://www8.gsb.columbia.edu/cbs-directory/detail/ss957">Sheena Iyengar</a> ran a series of speed dating events for Columbia University graduate students, while collecting detailed data on the participants and results. The full dataset is <a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2008/01/21/the_speeddating_1/">available to download</a>; data scientist <a href="https://drkeithmcnulty.com/">Keith McNulty</a> has also <a href="https://drkeithmcnulty.com/2020/02/14/what-matters-in-speed-dating/">created a simplified version of it</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send at-first-sight feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-18-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Mostly coronavirus-related data, but also speed dating.</summary>
    <published>2020-03-18T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-03-11</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.11 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-03-11T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>More coronavirus data, plus political parties, SFO flights, Tour de France cyclists, and penguins.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>But first ... at BuzzFeed News, we’re <a href="https://boards.greenhouse.io/buzzfeed/jobs/2117225?gh_jid=2117225">hiring a <strong>paid</strong> summer intern</a> to help us use data to cover the US presidential election (and possibly other things). If you apply, let me know at jeremy.singer-vine@buzzfeed.com; I’ll make sure to personally review all applications from DIP readers. Also feel free to send me any questions beforehand.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More coronavirus data.</strong> Last month, <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-05-edition">DIP featured</a> coronavirus case counts <a href="https://gisanddata.maps.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/bda7594740fd40299423467b48e9ecf6">mapped by researchers at Johns Hopkins</a>. Since then, efforts to collect and publish COVID-19 data have grown, including: the Johns Hopkins team has <a href="https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19">moved its data repository to GitHub</a> ... the <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/laninf/article/PIIS1473-3099(20)30119-5/fulltext">Open COVID-19 Data Curation Group</a> has <a href="https://github.com/beoutbreakprepared/nCoV2019">expanded its data on individual cases</a> ... the Italian government is publishing <a href="https://github.com/pcm-dpc/COVID-19">local case and test counts on GitHub</a> ... Princeton PhD student <a href="https://twitter.com/sang_woo_park">Sang Woo Park</a> is building a <a href="https://github.com/parksw3/COVID19-Korea">detailed dataset of cases in South Korea</a> ... the decade-old <a href="https://www.gisaid.org/">Global Initiative on Sharing All Influenza Data</a> is sharing <a href="https://www.gisaid.org/epiflu-applications/next-hcov-19-app/">COVID-19 genome samples and mutations</a> ... while the collaboratively-edited <a href="https://coronavirustechhandbook.com/">CoronavirusTechHandbook.com</a> is pointing to additional datasets and data-trackers. <strong>Related</strong>: My colleague <a href="https://www.peteraldhous.com/">Peter Aldhous</a> is using the Johns Hopkins data to publish clear, concise graphics tracking known case counts <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/peteraldhous/coronavirus-updating-charts-maps-us-states">globally</a> and <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/peteraldhous/coronavirus-updating-charts-maps-us-states">in the United States</a>. [h/t <a href="https://backspace.com/">John Emerson</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/HannahNamMD/status/1233929884994547715">Hannah Nam</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/brsalzano/status/1236564010318925826">Bruno Salzano</a> + <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22520069">illo</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/lamthuyvo">Lam Thuy Vo</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/magiccia">Mago Torres</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Political parties around the world.</strong> The <a href="https://www.globalpartysurvey.org/methods">Global Party Survey</a> is “an international scientific study, directed by Pippa Norris, designed to compare political parties around the world. Drawing on survey data gathered from 1,861 party and election experts, the study uses 21 core items to estimate key ideological values, issue positions, and populist rhetoric for 1,127 parties in 170 countries.” Last month, <a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/faculty/pippa-norris">Norris</a> released <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/GlobalPartySurvey">the dataset</a> and a <a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/publications/measuring-populism-worldwide">paper that uses it to measure</a> “populism as a global phenomenon.” <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://manifesto-project.wzb.eu/">The Manifesto Project</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-06-21-edition">DIP 2017.06.21</a>) and <a href="https://partyfacts.herokuapp.com/">Party Facts</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-01-16-edition">DIP 2019.01.16</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Flights in and out of SFO.</strong> San Francisco International Airport’s <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/about/">museum team</a> has been <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/blog/2019/05/17/flights/">collecting information</a> on all flights in and out of SFO’s terminals. Online, you can <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/flights/">browse and search the data</a>, which includes details about the airlines, flight numbers, gates of arrival and departure, and more. Earlier this year, the team <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/blog/2020/01/24/flightdata/">published a downloadable database</a> of 769,250 flights from 2019. (Or 1.2 million flights, if you count <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Codeshare_agreement">codeshares</a>.) [h/t <a href="https://buttondown.email/vaguemtn">Simon Batistoni</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bicycle racers.</strong> Applied mathematics PhD student <a href="https://camminady.org/">Thomas Camminady</a> has built a <a href="https://github.com/camminady/LeTourDataSet/">spreadsheet of all Tour de France riders since 1903</a> (including name, team, time taken, and final ranking), based on <a href="https://www.letour.fr/en/history">the competition’s official results page</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Penguins.</strong> The <a href="http://www.penguinmap.com/">MAPPPD project</a> — Mapping Application for Penguin Populations and Projected Dynamics — “aims to deliver open access penguin population data for the Antarctic continent, and occupancy probabilities for flying birds around the Antarctic Peninsula.” The data, last updated about a year ago, can be both <a href="http://www.penguinmap.com/mapppd">browsed online and downloaded</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MJPolito">Michael Polito</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send tuxedoed feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-11-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>More coronavirus data, plus political parties, SFO flights, Tour de France cyclists, and penguins.</summary>
    <published>2020-03-11T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-03-04</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.04 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-03-04T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Climate policies, political emails, 2.8 million Smithsonian images, London groceries, and bug splats.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Climate policies.</strong> The <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/">Climate Policy Database</a>, a project of the <a href="https://newclimate.org/about-newclimate/">NewClimate Institute</a>, has collected data on more than 3,800 regulations, subsidies, and other policies related to climate change mitigation. The <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php/Download_policies">downloadable</a> and <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php/Special:BrowsePolicy">browseable</a> database, <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php?title=About_the_database">drawn from more than a dozen sources</a>, includes policies from nearly every country in the world and lists the policies’ names, jurisdictions, years of enactment, general objectives, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Political emails.</strong> Reporters at the <a href="https://themarkup.org/">The Markup</a>, a <a href="https://themarkup.org/2020/02/25/editor-letter-julia-angwin">newly launched newsroom</a> that “investigates how powerful institutions are using technology to change our society,” <a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/02/26/show-your-work-wheres-my-email">subscribed to receive emails</a> from more than 200 presidential candidates, advocacy organizations, and other political groups. Four months later, they had received more than 5,000 messages, which they used <a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/02/26/wheres-my-email">to examine Gmail’s treatment of political communications</a>. On GitHub, <a href="https://github.com/the-markup/investigation-wheres-my-email">they’ve published</a> the emails, relevant code, and a cleaned-up dataset. <strong>Related</strong>: Last year, FiveThirtyEight signed up for emails from the Democratic presidential campaigns; by August, they had collected 830 messages, which <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/candidate-emails">they published</a> and used <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/which-democrats-are-campaigning-on-trump/">to see who was talking most about Donald Trump</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Smithsonian imagery.</strong> “For the first time in its 174-year history, the Smithsonian has released 2.8 million high-resolution two- and three-dimensional images from across its collections onto an <a href="https://www.si.edu/openaccess">open access online platform</a> for patrons to peruse and download free of charge,” <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smithsonian-institution/smithsonian-releases-28-million-images-public-domain-180974263/">the institution announced last week</a>. The new platform includes “data and material from all 19 Smithsonian museums, nine research centers, libraries, archives and the National Zoo”; the records are <a href="https://www.si.edu/openaccess/devtools">accessible via an API</a>, and the metadata is also <a href="https://github.com/Smithsonian/OpenAccess">available on GitHub</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08595">KaoKore</a>, a <a href="https://github.com/rois-codh/kaokore">dataset of 5,552 face images</a> cropped from Japanese artworks at several (non-Smithsonian) institutions. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/EPetenko/status/1232687035237961729">Erin Petenko</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/corintxt">Corin Faife</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>London grocery purchases.</strong> “We present the Tesco Grocery 1.0 dataset: a record of 420 M food items purchased by 1.6 M fidelity card owners who shopped at the 411 Tesco stores in Greater London over the course of the entire year of 2015, aggregated at the level of census areas to preserve anonymity,” researchers announced in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0397-7">a recent academic paper</a>. For each area, <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/Area-level_grocery_purchases/7796666">the dataset</a> contains “the number of transactions and nutritional properties [...] including the average caloric intake and the composition of nutrients.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/lajello/status/1230447728708243456">Luca Maria Aiello</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bug splats.</strong> Danish zoologist Anders Pape Møller <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ece3.5236">counted the number of insects</a> killed on the windscreen of a single car after each of 1,375 journeys along the same stretch of road between 1997 and 2017. After accounting for time of day, weather, and other factors, Møller says <a href="https://datadryad.org/stash/dataset/doi:10.5061/dryad.gq73493">his data</a> suggests an 80% decline in flying insects during that time. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/feb/12/car-splatometer-tests-reveal-huge-decline-number-insects">The Guardian on two bug-splat studies, including Møller’s</a>. [h/t <a href="https://cds.nyu.edu/communitynewsletter/">Laura Norén and Brad Stenger</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send splattered feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-04-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Climate policies, political emails, 2.8 million Smithsonian images, London groceries, and bug splats.</summary>
    <published>2020-03-04T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-02-26</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.02.26 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-02-26T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Government contracts, tech organizing, US anti-press incidents, EU laws, and Cockatoo Island prisoners.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Government contracts, standardized.</strong> The <a href="https://www.open-contracting.org/data-standard/">Open Contracting Data Standard</a> is a “free, non-proprietary open data standard” that makes it “easier to share, compare and analyze” the contracts that governments award to bidders. The project <a href="https://www.open-contracting.org/impact-stories/">has been gaining traction</a>, with <a href="https://www.open-contracting.org/worldwide/">dozens of local and federal governments</a> using <a href="https://standard.open-contracting.org/latest/en/">the standard</a> to publish detailed official data, including in <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/open-contracting">the UK</a>, <a href="https://buyandsell.gc.ca/procurement-data/open-contracting-data-standard-pilot/about-the-ocds-pilot">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.colombiacompra.gov.co/transparencia/gestion-documental/datos-abiertos">Colombia</a>, <a href="http://ppip.gov.np">Nepal</a>, <a href="https://gpp.ppda.go.ug">Uganda</a>, and <a href="https://ageops.net/en/home">Afghanistan</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tech workers, united.</strong> The <a href="https://collectiveactions.tech">Collective Actions In Tech project</a> database aims to document every instance of tech-industry workers banding together to raise awareness of a shared cause. The database, which is <a href="https://github.com/collective-action/tech/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">developed collaboratively</a> and <a href="https://github.com/collective-action/tech">available to download</a>, so far contains more than 200 protests, strikes, union drives, legal actions, and open letters. (The earliest event: In 1979, IBM workers protested their company’s business with apartheid South Africa.) <strong>Related</strong>: Writing for The Guardian, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/dec/22/tech-worker-activism-2019-what-we-learned">two of the project’s organizers describe</a> “our eight most important insights.” [h/t <a href="https://anja.kefala.info">anjakefala</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Anti-press incidents.</strong> Since 2017, the <a href="https://pressfreedomtracker.us">U.S. Press Freedom Tracker</a> has collected information on <a href="https://pressfreedomtracker.us/blog/3-years-tracking-our-january-2020-newsletter/">more than 400 incidents targeting journalists in the United States</a>, such as arrests, attacks, and denials of access. The <a href="https://pressfreedomtracker.us/about/">initiative</a>, led by the <a href="https://freedom.press/">Freedom of the Press Foundation</a> and the <a href="https://www.cpj.org/">Committee to Protect Journalists</a>, provides <a href="https://pressfreedomtracker.us/data/">bulk downloads of the data, plus an API</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: The project <a href="https://pressfreedomtracker.us/blog/back-campaign-trail-president-trump-increases-his-anti-press-tweet-offensive/">also maintains</a> a <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1uNA6nsgcRhhQ0b6USsMNzhYLMfuDRSMhbGZNZ00WkHk/edit?usp=sharing">spreadsheet of anti-press tweets</a> by Donald Trump. <strong>Previously</strong>: CPJ’s <a href="https://cpj.org/data/killed">database of journalists who’ve been killed</a> for reasons related to their work (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-01-16-edition">DIP 2019.01.16</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sidnext2none">Sid Rao</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>EU laws.</strong> The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/0EGYWY">CEPS EurLex dataset</a> contains more than 142,000 European Union regulations, directives, and official decisions — ”almost the entire corpus of the EU’s legally binding acts passed between 1952 - 2019.” The dataset contains two dozen variables, including dates, subject matter, authors, various links, and the full text of most laws. The information comes, ultimately, from the EU’s online legal repository, <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu">eur-lex.europa.eu</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MoritzLaurer/status/1229356229660639237">Moritz Laurer</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cockatoo Island prisoners.</strong> Historical criminologist <a href="https://www.liverpool.ac.uk/sociology-social-policy-and-criminology/staff/katherine-roscoe/">Katherine Roscoe</a> has transcribed archival records to create a <a href="https://cockatooconvicts.wordpress.com">detailed dataset of more than 2,500 people imprisoned</a> between 1847 and 1869 at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cockatoo_Island_(New_South_Wales)">Cockatoo Island Prison</a> — “Sydney’s most notorious 19th century prison,” now a UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send notorious feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-26-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Government contracts, tech organizing, US anti-press incidents, EU laws, and Cockatoo Island prisoners.</summary>
    <published>2020-02-26T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-02-19</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.02.19 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-02-19T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Standardized electric-utility info, school vaccination rates, global empires, farming households, and pinball.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electric utilities, standardized.</strong> “Electric utilities report a huge amount of information to the US government,” but “much of this data is not released in well documented, ready-to-use, machine readable formats.” That assessment comes from the <a href="https://catalyst.coop/pudl/">Public Utility Data Liberation</a> (PUDL) project, which aims to clean, standardize, and cross-link the electric utility information gathered by various agencies. Earlier this month, PUDL published <a href="https://zenodo.org/record/3653159">its first data release</a>; it includes information originally collected through Energy Information Administration <a href="https://www.eia.gov/electricity/data/eia860/">Form 860</a> (details about individual generators) and <a href="https://www.eia.gov/electricity/data/eia923/">Form 923</a> (individual power plants), the Environmental Protection Agency’s <a href="https://www.epa.gov/emc/emc-continuous-emission-monitoring-systems">Continuous Emissions Monitoring System</a> (hourly emissions), and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission’s <a href="https://www.ferc.gov/docs-filing/forms/form-1/data.asp">Form 1</a> (price rates and financial audits). The code PUDL uses to download, extract, and standardize the raw data is also <a href="https://github.com/catalyst-cooperative/pudl">available online</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ZaneSelvans">Zane Selvans</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>School vaccination rates.</strong> Reporters at the Wall Street Journal collected <a href="https://github.com/WSJ/measles-data">data on school-specific vaccination rates</a> — both overall and also for the measles, mumps, and rubella (MMR) vaccine — from 32 US states’ health departments. In total, the WSJ’s dataset covers more than 46,000 schools, of which 42,000 have at least one vaccination rate available. Most states provided data for the 2018–19 school year; the rest did so for 2017–18.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>4,500 years of empire.</strong> To help study “<a href="https://voxeu.org/article/imperial-roots-global-trade">the imperial roots of global trade</a>,” a trio of economists have built a <a href="https://www.wnvermeulen.com/empires/">dataset of 168 historical empires</a>. For each empire, the dataset lists the modern-day countries under rule (and during which years), plus whether the empire had a centralized administration, centralized religion, and/or monopoly on coin-minting. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/newsletter.jainfamilyinstitute.org/some-totality">Jain Family Institute</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Farm households.</strong> The <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0388-8">Rural Household Multiple Indicator Survey</a> (RHoMIS) “collects information on 758 variables covering household demographics, farm area, crops grown and their production, livestock holdings” and more. In an <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0388-8">academic article published this month</a>, researchers from the Nairobi-based <a href="https://www.ilri.org">International Livestock Research Institute</a> presented a <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/9M6EHS">dataset of responses collected from 13,310 farm households</a> in 21 countries in sub-Saharan Africa, Central America, and Asia between 2015 and early 2018.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pinball.</strong> The crowdsourced website <a href="https://pinballmap.com">pinballmap.com</a> provides data on more than 25,500 pinball machines at more than 7,400 locations in the US, UK, Canada, Australia, Finland, and Japan. The <a href="https://pinballmap.com/api/v1/docs">website’s API</a> lets you access the underlying data, including the specific machines available at each location.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send high-scoring feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-19-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Standardized electric-utility info, school vaccination rates, global empires, farming households, and pinball.</summary>
    <published>2020-02-19T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-02-12</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.02.12 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-02-12T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Banking crises, Europe in translation, simulated hurricanes, arXiv metadata, and the greatest hip-hop tracks of all time.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Banking crises.</strong> <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/laevenl/home">Luc Laeven</a> and <a href="https://www.imf.org/external/np/cv/AuthorCV.aspx?AuthID=179">Fabián Valencia</a> — economists at the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund, respectively — have built and maintain a <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WP/Issues/2018/09/14/Systemic-Banking-Crises-Revisited-46232">dataset of systemic banking crises</a>, like those that rippled across the globe in 2008. First published in 2008 and most recently updated in 2018, the dataset covers on 151 crises affecting 118 countries from 1970 to 2017. For each episode, the dataset provides the starting and ending dates, policy responses, output loss, fiscal cost, increase in public debt, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/5499561d2ff6b692ed59770b0f62e3fe98995bdc">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Europe in translation.</strong> <a href="https://iate.europa.eu/home">IATE</a> is the European Union’s official terminology database, containing translations for words and phrases such as “orange juice,” “climate change policy”, and “competence of the Member States.” (That’s <em>succo d’arancia</em> in Italian, <em>ilmastonmuutospolitiikka</em> in Finnish, and <em>tagállami hatáskör</em> in Hungarian.) Over the past 20+ years, the project has accumulated more than 970,000 entries, translated into nearly 8 million phrasings in 25 languages. You can search the entries online or <a href="https://iate.europa.eu/download-iate">download the entire dataset</a> as a single XML file. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Yambo_LSG/status/1224270800150245381">Laura Solana Garzón</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tropical cyclone simulations.</strong> A team of scientists have used historical hurricane and typhoon data to <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0381-2">simulate</a> a <a href="https://data.4tu.nl/repository/uuid:82c1dc0d-5485-43d8-901a-ce7f26cda35d">10,000 plausible years of cyclone activity</a>. The dataset covers the world’s most active “basins” — the areas where cyclones form — and includes each simulated storm’s path, maximum wind speed, average pressure, and more. [h/t <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/jcnathaz/status/1225676744625012736">Jose A Cañizares</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>arXiv metadata.</strong> Founded nearly 30 years ago, <a href="https://arxiv.org">arXiv</a> is an open-access repository of more than 1,600,000 scholarly articles — typically “preprints” of papers, uploaded by the authors before being peer-reviewed — in physics, math, computer science, statistics, economics, and several other fields. The website participates in <a href="https://www.openarchives.org">Open Archives Initiative</a>, providing <a href="https://arxiv.org/help/oa/index">metadata on uploaded articles</a> through the initiative’s protocol; it also <a href="https://arxiv.org/help/api/index">has an API</a>. Last summer, computer science student <a href="https://boramalper.org">Bora M. Alper</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/comments/c39mmj/arxiv_complete_metadata_dump_20190618_internet/">collected</a> the metadata for all the site’s papers and <a href="https://archive.org/details/arXiv-metadata-dump-2019-06-18.tar.xz">published it as a single file</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Biggie data.</strong> What are the greatest hip-hop songs of all time? Last year, the BBC <a href="http://www.bbc.com/culture/story/20191007-the-greatest-hip-hop-songs-of-all-time-who-voted">posed that question</a> to more than 100 artists, producers, critics, and other experts, asking each to rank their top five tracks. (Notorious B.I.G.’s “Juicy” <a href="http://www.bbc.com/culture/story/20191007-the-greatest-hip-hop-songs-of-all-time">nabbed the highest rating</a>.) Software engineer <a href="https://simonjockers.de">Simon Jockers</a> has turned the responses into a <a href="https://github.com/sjockers/bbc-best-rapmusic">structured dataset</a> and <a href="https://blog.datawrapper.de/best-hip-hop-songs-of-all-time-visualized/">visualized the results</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send critic-approved feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-12-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Banking crises, Europe in translation, simulated hurricanes, arXiv metadata, and the greatest hip-hop tracks of all time.</summary>
    <published>2020-02-12T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-02-05</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.02.05 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-02-05T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Credibly accused clergy, coronavirus cases, sign-stealing, hotel bookings, and the Smiths (... and the Johnsons ... and the Williamses ...).</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Credibly accused clergy.</strong> Reporters at ProPublica <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/we-assembled-the-only-nationwide-database-of-priests-deemed-credibly-accused-of-abuse-heres-how">have assembled</a> the first-ever <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/credibly-accused/">nationwide database of US Catholic clergy “credibly accused” of sexual abuse</a>, based on nearly 180 official lists released by dioceses and religious orders. (The majority of the lists were published during the past year and a half, following a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_jury_investigation_of_Catholic_Church_sexual_abuse_in_Pennsylvania">landmark grand jury report in Pennsylvania</a>.) The database contains more than 6,700 names so far, plus details available from some of the lists, including birth year, ordination year, assignments, and status.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus cases.</strong> As the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019%E2%80%9320_Wuhan_coronavirus_outbreak">Wuhan coronavirus outbreak</a> intensifies, a team at Johns Hopkins has been <a href="https://gisanddata.maps.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/bda7594740fd40299423467b48e9ecf6">mapping the number of confirmed cases</a>, deaths, and recoveries. The project <a href="https://systems.jhu.edu/research/public-health/ncov/">aggregates data</a> from several sources, including the <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports/">WHO</a>, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-nCoV/summary.html">US CDC</a>, <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/geographical-distribution-2019-ncov-cases">European CDC</a>, and <a href="https://ncov.dxy.cn/">DXY</a>, a website that reports case counts from China’s CDC and National Health Commission. The dataset powering the Johns Hopkins map is <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wQVypefm946ch4XDp37uZ-wartW4V7ILdg-qYiDXUHM/edit#gid=787605648">available as a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="http://www.fionn.xyz">Fionn Delahunty</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Baseball sign-stealing.</strong> “I’m an Astros fan. They cheated during the 2017 regular season — the evidence is clear. In an attempt to understand the scope of the cheating and the players involved, I decided to listen to every pitch from the Astros’ 2017 home games and log any banging noise I could detect.” That’s from <a href="https://twitter.com/adams_at">Tony Adams</a>, who <a href="http://signstealingscandal.com/about/">analyzed audio spectrograms</a> corresponding to more than 8,200 pitches. Last week, he published <a href="http://signstealingscandal.com/">a website documenting his findings</a>, including <a href="http://signstealingscandal.com/files/">a spreadsheet of the data</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="http://signstealingscandal.com/statistical-analysis/">Adams’s list of stories and analyses that have used the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://danjbrady.com">Dan Brady</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Hotel bookings.</strong> In 2018, a trio of researchers at the Instituto Universitário de Lisboa published a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340918315191">dataset detailing nearly 120,000 (anonymized) bookings</a> at two (unnamed) hotels in Portugal between July 2015 and August 2017. The bookings, extracted from the hotels’ property management systems, are described in detail: the number of adults, children, and babies for the reservation; country of origin; customer, room, and deposit types; whether the guests were repeat visitors; the number of special requests made; and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Last (but not least) names.</strong> From the US Census Bureau, you can download a dataset of <a href="https://www.census.gov/topics/population/genealogy/data/2010_surnames.html">all surnames that belonged to at least 100 people in 2010</a>, and <a href="https://www.census.gov/topics/population/genealogy/data/2000_surnames.html">the same for 2000</a>. Those datasets indicate the total number of people with the name, and distribution of those people by race/ethnicity. A similar list, but based on a sample population and without demographic information, is also <a href="https://www.census.gov/topics/population/genealogy/data/1990_census/1990_census_namefiles.html">available for 1990</a>. <strong>Pop quiz</strong>: Try to guess the five most popular surnames that are also colors ... in order. [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:arnicas/">Lynn Cherny</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send common feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-05-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Credibly accused clergy, coronavirus cases, sign-stealing, hotel bookings, and the Smiths (... and the Johnsons ... and the Williamses ...).</summary>
    <published>2020-02-05T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-01-29</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.29 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-01-29T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Time use surveys, dams, Spanish migration, darknet markets, and (more) vanity plate applications.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>How we spend our time.</strong> Ever year since 2003, the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/tus/home.htm">American Time Use Survey</a>, has been measuring how much time we spend sleeping, eating, and working; with friends, with family, and alone; and much more. Unlike <a href="https://www.timeuse.org/information/access-data">many other time use surveys</a>, the ATUS’s <a href="https://www.bls.gov/tus/data.htm">respondent-level datasets</a> are freely available to the general public. Other time use surveys with downloadable data include the <a href="https://dataverse.unc.edu/dataverse/rlms-hse">Russia Longitudinal Monitoring Survey</a> and a <a href="https://data.mcc.gov/evaluations/index.php/catalog/205/study-description">Kosovo time use survey</a> sponsored by the Millennium Challenge Corporation. <strong>Related</strong>: Through <a href="https://ipums.org">IPUMS</a>, you can build custom data extracts <a href="https://www.atusdata.org/atus/">of the ATUS</a>, <a href="https://www.ahtusdata.org/ahtus/">of historical US time survey data</a>, and <a href="https://www.mtusdata.org/mtus/">of the Multinational Time Use Study</a> (registration required). <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://flowingdata.com/2019/07/16/how-the-american-work-day-changed-in-15-years/">How the American Work Day Changed in 15 Years</a>” and “<a href="https://flowingdata.com/2019/03/06/women-men-timeuse/">A Day in the Life: Women and Men</a>,” two visualizations by <a href="https://twitter.com/flowingdata">Nathan Yau</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Petrit/status/1043413638068006912">Petrit Selimi</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Dams.</strong> The <a href="https://globaldamwatch.org/goodd/">Global Georeferenced Database of Dams</a> contains <a href="https://springernature.figshare.com/collections/GOODD_a_global_dataset_of_more_than_38_000_georeferenced_dams/4648214">geographic data on more than 38,000 dams and their watersheds</a>. The project, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0362-5">published by geographers at King’s College London</a>, is based on a combination of satellite imagery, national registries, and other sources. At least one co-author <a href="https://twitter.com/drarnoutvans/status/1219664646107533318">has been working on the project since 2008</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JIDA1983/status/1220374752533131264">Jida Wang</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Three decades of Spanish migration.</strong> Spain’s national statistics institute publishes <a href="https://github.com/ECLaboratorio/unidad-de-datos/tree/master/proyectos/migraciones_espana">annual microdata on the relocation of residents</a> within, into, and out of the country. The datasets indicate each relocator’s gender and age, birthplace, previous location, and destination — down to the municipality for locations within Spain. Currently, the records cover 1988 to 2018. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=&amp;sl=es&amp;tl=en&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.elconfidencial.com%2Feconomia%2F2019-09-27%2Fexodo-urbano-espana-migraciones-provincias_2240119%2F&amp;sandbox=1">El Confidencial’s report on intra-provincial migration patterns</a>, using this data, and <a href="https://github.com/ECLaboratorio/unidad-de-datos/tree/master/proyectos/migraciones_espana">related GitHub repository</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/a4bbc86cc07b/preview-222-in-other-news-3750685">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Darknet market survival.</strong> The researcher who goes by “<a href="https://www.gwern.net/Links">Gwern</a>” maintains a <a href="https://www.gwern.net/DNM-survival">dataset of more than 80 darknet marketplaces</a> founded between 2011 and 2015. For each market (such as the infamous Silk Road), the dataset lists when it began, when it closed, why it closed, its URL, what cryptocurrencies it accepted, whether guns were allowed to be sold, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>California vanity plates.</strong> Through a public records request, <a href="https://twitter.com/veltman">Noah Veltman</a> has obtained data on <a href="https://github.com/veltman/ca-license-plates">more than 23,000 personalized license plate applications</a> flagged for review by the California DMV. For each flagged application, the dataset contains the applicant’s justification, comments from the state’s reviewers, and the proposal’s outcome. The reviewers rejected about 80% of the proposals, including those believed to be referencing racial slurs, swearing, drugs, sex, violence, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/datanews/license-plates">New York vanity plate applications</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2015-10-21-edition">DIP 2015.10.21</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send vain feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-29-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Time use surveys, dams, Spanish migration, darknet markets, and (more) vanity plate applications.</summary>
    <published>2020-01-29T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-01-22</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.01.22 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-01-22T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>China’s projects abroad, radio/TV broadcast areas, street sprawl, cannabis tests, and backyard ice rinks.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>China’s projects abroad.</strong> The <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/about">AidData research lab</a> at the College of William &amp; Mary has published several datasets on China’s international soft-power efforts, including the <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/blog/aiddata-releases-first-ever-global-dataset-on-chinas-development-spending-spree">first-ever</a> dataset of <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/data/geocoded-chinese-global-official-finance-dataset">government-financed development projects abroad</a> (covering 3,485 projects between 2000 and 2014) and a structured dataset of <a href="https://www.aiddata.org/data/chinas-public-diplomacy-dashboard-dataset-version-1-0">diplomacy efforts in 25 Asia/Pacific countries</a> between 2000 and 2016. [h/t <a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/global-chinese-financing-is-fueling-megaprojects">Nick Routley</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/simongerman600/status/1216764349026574337">Simon Kuestenmacher</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Broadcast geography.</strong> To construct her maps “<a href="https://erdavis.com/2020/01/04/visualizing-the-geography-of-fm-radio/">visualizing the geography of FM radio</a>” in the US, <a href="https://erdavis.com/about/">Erin Davis</a> combined the Federal Communication Commission’s <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/radio/fm-service-contour-data-points">service contour data</a> — the area where reception for a station “is generally protected from interference caused by other stations” — with the agency’s <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/radio/fm-query">radio station licensing data</a> and genre information from <a href="https://radio-locator.com">radio-locator.com</a>. The FCC also provides <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/media/television/tv-service-contour-data-points">service contour data for broadcast television</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="http://reboot.fcc.gov/license-view/">All FCC-issued licenses</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-09-07-edition">DIP 2016.09.07</a>). [h/t <a href="https://us5.campaign-archive.com/?u=77ecabbd32e97a6caa9d7d40b&amp;id=c55fd8b814">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Street sprawl.</strong> Using 46 million kilometers of <a href="https://planet.openstreetmap.org">data from OpenStreetMap</a>, <a href="https://wellbeing.ihsp.mcgill.ca">Christopher Barrington-Leigh</a> and <a href="https://people.ucsc.edu/~adammb/">Adam Millard-Ball</a> have <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0223078">published</a> “the first systematic and globally commensurable measures of street-network sprawl based on graph-theoretic and geographic concepts.” You can explore their findings via an <a href="https://sprawlmap.org/">interactive map</a> and also download <a href="https://sprawl.research.mcgill.ca/publications/2020-PNAS-sprawl/website-FAQ.html">aggregate metrics</a> for nearly 200 cities and more than 160 countries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/robroc">Roberto Rocha</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cannabis tests.</strong> Despite US adults increasingly gaining state-legal access to cannabis, “no universal standards for laboratory testing protocols currently exist,” write <a href="https://twitter.com/trikomes">Nick Jikomes</a> and <a href="https://michaelzoorob.com/about/">Michael Zoorob</a>, in a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-22755-2">March 2018 article</a> for <em>Scientific Reports</em>. “To investigate these concerns, we analyzed a publicly available seed-to-sale traceability dataset from Washington state containing measurements of the cannabinoid content of legal cannabis products from state-certified laboratories.” The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/E8TQSD">dataset</a>, obtained by the authors via public records requests, includes more than 200,000 test results over the course of three years.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Backyard ice rinks.</strong> <a href="https://www.rinkwatch.org/">RinkWatch</a> “asks people who love outdoor skating to help environmental scientists monitor winter weather conditions” by reporting the conditions of their backyard ice rinks. The project’s <a href="https://www.rinkwatch.org/download.html">downloadable data</a> includes more than 30,000 “skateable” / “not skateable” observations of more than 1,200 rinks since 2012. <strong>As mentioned in</strong>: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/13/travel/ice-skating-Quebec.html">Last week’s New York Times article</a> about outdoor skating trails in Quebec.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send icy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-01-22-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>China’s projects abroad, radio/TV broadcast areas, street sprawl, cannabis tests, and backyard ice rinks.</summary>
    <published>2020-01-22T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
