<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</id>
  <title>Data Is Plural</title>
  <updated>2020-06-10T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Singer-Vine</name>
    <email>jsvine@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-06-10</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.06.10 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-06-10T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Black Lives Matter protests, police violence at the protests, police reforms and union contracts, police militarization, and tech’s response.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Black Lives Matter protests.</strong> An unnamed geospatial analyst <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gis/comments/gx8uoa/mapping_george_floyd_black_lives_matter_protests/">has been mapping</a> “every town or city I can find where a George Floyd / Black Lives Matter protest, action, or vigil has occurred since May 25” — <a href="https://www.creosotemaps.com/blm2020/">more than 2,600 so far</a>. The <a href="https://www.creosotemaps.com/blm2020/json/">data files powering the map</a> include each city’s name, state/region, country, coordinates, and the date it was added. <strong>Related</strong>: For <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/perspectives-on-politics/article/black-lives-matter-evidence-that-policecaused-deaths-predict-protest-activity/BFA2E74F4BCB25C3C222807E8B1111D4/share/53d6d67c798695fc19688bd571777e433fca550d">a study of the relationship between police-caused deaths and demonstrations</a>, Williamson et al. built <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L2GSK6">a dataset of Black Lives Matter protests in 2014 and 2015</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police violence at the BLM protests.</strong> Several groups are collecting examples of disproportionate police responses to the protests against police brutality. <a href="https://watchwatch.org/">One such collection</a>, <a href="https://time.com/5849839/police-brutality-george-floyd-protests-spreadsheet/">spurred by criminal defense attorney T. Greg Doucette</a>, has compiled hundreds of instances of “unnecessary violence by law enforcement officers against civilians”; for each one, the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1YmZeSxpz52qT-10tkCjWOwOGkQqle7Wd1P7ZM1wMW0E/edit">underlying spreadsheet</a> provides the city and state of the incident, links to visual documentation on Twitter and YouTube, and a short description. <a href="https://github.com/2020PB/police-brutality">Another collection</a>, which emerged from the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2020PoliceBrutality/">/r/2020PoliceBrutality subreddit</a> and seeks “to accumulate and contextualize evidence of police brutality during the 2020 George Floyd protests,” also includes incident dates, an <a href="https://846policebrutality.com/">interactive map</a>, and APIs. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/americas/2020/06/05/visualizing-police-violence-against-journalists-at-protests-across-the-us/">Bellingcat</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2020/jun/05/im-getting-shot-attacks-on-journalists-surge-in-us-protests">The Guardian</a> have compiled <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1F7Q-XoCoHzb_cX28ARCL4BMsuxp3EpkouUDJ2cRSjOQ/edit">a spreadsheet</a> of 140+ “reports of arrests, violence, and intimidation against journalists” at the protests. [h/t <a href="https://anja.kefala.info">anjakefala</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/AricToler/status/1268892644941447168">Aric Toler</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police reforms and union contracts.</strong> <a href="https://www.joincampaignzero.org/">Campaign Zero</a>’s <a href="https://8cantwait.org/">8cantwait.org</a> advocates for eight specific reforms to curtail police officers’ use of force, including bans on chokeholds, requiring de-escalation tactics, and establishing comprehensive reporting. The organization has compiled <a href="https://useofforceproject.org/database">the use of force policies for 100 large police departments</a>, and <a href="https://8cantwait.org/compare/">determined whether they’ve instituted these reforms</a>. (<a href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/campaign-zero-use-of-force/data/force.csv">Direct CSV download here</a>.) And at <a href="https://www.checkthepolice.org/">checkthepolice.org</a>, the organization has gathered <a href="https://www.checkthepolice.org/database">police union contracts</a> in major cities and assessed whether they contain language makes it harder to hold officers accountable for misconduct. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/samswey/status/1180655721052020737">Samuel Sinyangwe</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police militarization.</strong> The US Defense Logistic Agency’s <a href="https://www.dla.mil/DispositionServices/Offers/Reutilization/LawEnforcement/">Law Enforcement Support Office</a> sends surplus Department of Defense equipment to local law enforcement agencies, through an arrangement known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1033_program">1033 program</a>. The Pentagon publishes <a href="https://www.dla.mil/DispositionServices/Offers/Reutilization/LawEnforcement/PublicInformation/">quarterly updates of the equipment transferred</a> — which can range from coffee makers to rifles to entire aircraft — but only began doing so <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2014/12/03/the-pentagon-finally-details-its-weapons-for-cops-giveaway">after the program came under intense scrutiny</a> for its role in the <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jimdalrympleii/war-zone-in-ferguson-how-billions-in-military-weapons-ended">militarized police response to the 2014 Ferguson protests</a> and police militarization in general. <strong>Related</strong>: Despite the criticisms, the 1033 program has sent police departments hundreds of millions of dollars in military equipment since Ferguson, including more than 490 mine-resistant vehicles, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/johntemplon/police-departments-military-gear-1033-program">my colleague John Templon reports</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tech’s BLM statements.</strong> <a href="https://tpinsights.com/">The Plug</a>, a news site that focuses on the Black innovation economy, <a href="https://tpinsights.com/2020/05/31/twilio-box-spotify-and-other-tech-ceos-speak-out-against-racism-and-police-brutality-others-stay-silent/">has been assembling</a> a dataset of <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1OZx-_tm3PPyx6-ZJAST1xxOJRfn7KfYDjDT6JedrTfs/edit#gid=0">statements made by tech companies on racial justice, Black Lives Matter, and George Floyd</a>. The dataset links to more than 200 statements so far and includes each company’s name, the timing of the statement, and other relevant context, such as the URL of their most recent diversity report and the percentage of employees and/or leaders who identify as Black. [h/t <a href="https://www.sherrelldorsey.com/">Sherrell Dorsey</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-06-10-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Black Lives Matter protests, police violence at the protests, police reforms and union contracts, police militarization, and tech’s response.</summary>
    <published>2020-06-10T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-05-27</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.05.27 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-05-27T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Census response rates, more excess mortality data, ranked-choice votes, Shakespeare and Company’s lending library, and seashells.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Census response rates.</strong> As it has in the past, the US Census Bureau is encouraging residents to <a href="https://2020census.gov/en/ways-to-respond.html">respond to the 2020 Census’s mailed questionnaire</a>, which reduces the need for in-person census-taking. The agency calculates these "self-response" rates all the way down to individual Census tracts, and provides that data <a href="https://www2.census.gov/programs-surveys/decennial/2020/data/2020map/2020/">as a CSV</a> and via <a href="https://www.census.gov/data/developers/data-sets/decennial-response-rates.html">its API</a>. Those datasets, however, only represent the latest numbers, so researchers at the CUNY’s <a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/CUR">Center for Urban Research</a> have been <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/qrwrdkmjb3fjmg5/AAAaxYr9yeU9hBQMJcggriuEa?dl=0">creating daily snapshots</a>, which they’re also <a href="https://www.censushardtocountmaps2020.us/">mapping and analyzing for the public</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/Page-Elements/Academics-Research-Centers-Initiatives/Centers-and-Institutes/Center-for-Urban-Research/CUR-research-initiatives/Census-2020-Self-Response-Data-Questions-and-Answers">The Center’s FAQ for the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/SR_spatial">Steven Romalewski</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More excess mortality data.</strong> <a href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-20-edition">Last week’s newsletter</a> featured the <a href="https://github.com/TheEconomist/covid-19-excess-deaths-tracker">data and code</a> that The Economist is using <a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/04/16/tracking-covid-19-excess-deaths-across-countries">to estimate excess deaths due to COVID-19</a>. Also last week: The New York Times began publishing <a href="https://github.com/nytimes/covid-19-data/tree/master/excess-deaths">the data</a> behind its <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/04/21/world/coronavirus-missing-deaths.html">similar-but-different estimates</a>. And earlier this month, the team at the <a href="https://www.mortality.org/">Human Mortality Database</a> launched its <a href="https://www.mortality.org/Public/STMF_DOC/STMFNote.pdf">Short-term Mortality Fluctuations data series</a>, which provides “user-friendly access to detailed data on mortality by week, sex, and aggregated age group” for more than a dozen countries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/EOrtizOspina/status/1263153998057660416">Esteban Ortiz-Ospina</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Ranked-choice votes.</strong> The website <a href="https://ranked.vote/">ranked.vote</a>, built by quantitative analyst <a href="https://paulbutler.org/">Paul Butler</a>, standardizes and visualizes the detailed results of a few dozen elections — in Maine, San Francisco, Santa Fe, and Burlington — that have used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranked_voting">ranked-choice voting</a>, where voters can list their preferred candidates in sequential order.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Interwar literary lending.</strong> From 1919 to 1941, Sylvia Beach ran <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shakespeare_and_Company_(bookstore)">Shakespeare and Company</a>, the legendary Paris bookstore. It featured a lending library, whose members included writers such as Gertrude Stein, James Joyce, Simone de Beauvoir, and Ernest Hemingway. Princeton University’s <a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/">Shakespeare and Company Project</a> has digitized <a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/sources/">hundreds of the library’s lending cards and logbooks</a>, and has made the data available to <a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/members/">explore</a> and <a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/about/data/">download</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/tmrtsmith">Tom Merritt-Smith</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Seashells.</strong> A team of researchers <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0230-3">has built</a> a dataset that characterizes 29,622 samples of shells from 7,894 water-dwelling species. You can <a href="http://www.cis.um.edu.mo/research/shelldataset/">search the shell images online</a> and also <a href="https://springernature.figshare.com/collections/A_shell_dataset_for_shell_features_extraction_and_recognition/4428335">download the full dataset</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send calcified feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-27-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Census response rates, more excess mortality data, ranked-choice votes, Shakespeare and Company’s lending library, and seashells.</summary>
    <published>2020-05-27T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-05-20</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.05.20 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-05-20T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Excess deaths, trade agreements, US forests, historical crop yields, and Victorian fiction.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Excess deaths.</strong> The Economist has published <a href="https://github.com/TheEconomist/covid-19-excess-deaths-tracker">the data</a> behind its <a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/04/16/tracking-covid-19-excess-deaths-across-countries">estimates of excess deaths due to COVID-19</a>. The data repository currently covers 20 countries; it provides recent weekly/monthly death totals, officially-counted COVID-19 death, and average historical death totals for the same time periods. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/J_CD_T/status/1261625814854045696">Data journalist James Tozer’s introductory Twitter thread</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sharon000/status/1262029159976574976">Sharon Machlis</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Trade agreements.</strong> The <a href="https://www.designoftradeagreements.org">Design of Trade Agreements</a> database collects information about customs unions, free trade agreements, and other similar treaties signed between 1948 and 2018. It currently includes more than 800 agreements, plus additional negotiations, accessions, withdrawals, consolidations, and amendments. For each agreement, the database indicates the its name, member countries, year of signature, and <a href="https://www.designoftradeagreements.org/downloads/">a number of policy-specific variables</a>. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US forests.</strong> The US Department of Agriculture’s <a href="https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/rastergateway/forest_type/">National Forest Type Dataset</a> shows the geographic distribution of the country’s “forest types” — defined as ”logical ecological groupings of species mixes.” (Examples include “deciduous oak woodland” and “subalpine fir.”) To estimate the extent of each forest type, the dataset’s developers combined satellite imagery with “nearly 100 other geospatial data layers, including elevation, slope, aspect, and ecoregions.” <strong>Related</strong>: The Washington Post has used the dataset to <a href="https://wapo.st/peep-these-leaves">map fall foliage</a> and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2019/12/12/where-christmas-trees-come/">forests where Christmas-y trees grow</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/joemfox">Joe Fox</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Historical crop yields.</strong> The <a href="https://doi.pangaea.de/10.1594/PANGAEA.909132">Global Dataset of Historical Yields</a> combines data from agricultural censuses and satellite sensors to estimate the annual yields for four major crops — maize, rice, wheat, and soybean — annually from 1981 to 2016, for each 0.5-degree square on the planet. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0433-7">The dataset’s authors describe their methodology and the latest update</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Victorian fiction.</strong> <a href="https://www.victorianresearch.org/atcl/index.php">At the Circulating Library</a> “offers a biographical and bibliography database of nineteenth-century British fiction.” Launched by literature professor <a href="https://twitter.com/3VolumeNovel">Troy J. Bassett</a> in 2007, the <a href="https://www.victorianresearch.org/atcl/search.php">searchable</a>, <a href="https://www.victorianresearch.org/atcl/view_authors.php">browseable</a>, <a href="http://www.victorianresearch.org/atcl/snapshots.php">downloadable</a> database now contains information on more than 19,000 titles by more than 4,000 authors.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send Dickensian feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-20-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Excess deaths, trade agreements, US forests, historical crop yields, and Victorian fiction.</summary>
    <published>2020-05-20T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-05-13</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.05.13 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-05-13T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Employee protections, COVID stimulus recipients, national wildernesses, EU legislative edits, and millions of Iowa liquor purchases.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Employee protections.</strong> The UN International Labour Organization’s <a href="https://eplex.ilo.org/">Employment Protection Legislation Database</a> tracks “legal information on the regulation of temporary contracts and employment termination at the initiative of the employer,” on a national-regulatory level. The database quantifies and categorizes regulations under nine “themes” — including grounds for dismissal, procedures for collective dismissals, severance pay, and redress — and for more than 100 countries.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID stimulus recipients.</strong> The nonprofit <a href="https://www.goodjobsfirst.org/about-us">Good Jobs First</a> has <a href="https://covidstimuluswatch.org/blog/2020-04/covid-stimulus-watch-new-website-documents-accountability-track-records-cares-act">launched</a> <a href="https://covidstimuluswatch.org/">COVID Stimulus Watch</a>, which is gathering data on the grants and loans that have been provided to corporations through the $2 trillion <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coronavirus_Aid,_Relief,_and_Economic_Security_Act">CARES Act</a>. So far, the dataset contains more than 5,700 awards, totalling $54 billion. The records are based on information from public financial filings, press releases, and, <a href="https://covidstimuluswatch.org/blog/2020-05/covid-stimulus-watch-adds-5000-healthcare-provider-awards">most recently</a>, <a href="https://data.cdc.gov/Administrative/HHS-Provider-Relief-Fund/kh8y-3es6">data from the government’s healthcare-focused Provider Relief Fund</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>National wildernesses.</strong> Since the passage of the Wilderness Act in 1964, the US federal government has established 803 official wilderness areas, which cover more than 111 million acres. They’re all part of the <a href="https://wilderness.net/learn-about-wilderness/fast-facts/default.php">National Wilderness Preservation System</a>, co-managed by the National Park Service, Bureau of Land Management, Fish and Wildlife Service, and Forest Service. The University of Montana’s <a href="https://wilderness.net/default.php">Wilderness.net</a> brings data about each of the agencies’ wildernesses into one place, where it can be <a href="https://umontana.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=a415bca07f0a4bee9f0e894b0db5c3b6">explored via an interactive map</a> and <a href="https://wilderness.net/visit-wilderness/gis-gps.php">downloaded in bulk</a>. For each wilderness, the dataset provides its name, description, boundaries, acreage, year designated, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>EU legislative edits.</strong> Computer science graduate student <a href="https://victorkristof.me/">Victor Kristof</a> has built a <a href="https://zenodo.org/record/3757714">dataset of 450,000 legislative edits</a> proposed by members of the EU parliament from 2009 to 2019. For each proposed edit, the dataset points to the relevant legislation, names the parlimentarian, and indicates whether the edit was accepted. In an accompanying <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/fullHtml/10.1145/3366423.3380041">academic paper</a>, Kristof et al. describe the dataset’s construction and “propose a model for predicting the success of such edits.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Millions of Iowa liquor purchases.</strong> Iowa’s Alcoholic Beverages Division publishes <a href="https://data.iowa.gov/Sales-Distribution/Iowa-Liquor-Sales/m3tr-qhgy">itemized data on all liquor sales</a> by grocery/liquor/convenience-type stores since January 2002 — more than 18 million purchases in all. For each purchase, the dataset includes the specific kind, amount, and cost of the liquor, plus the date and location of the sale. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-08-07-edition">State liquor prices</a> (DIP 2019.08.07). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/seecmb/status/1259948995981516801">Martin Burch</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send distilled feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-13-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Employee protections, COVID stimulus recipients, national wildernesses, EU legislative edits, and millions of Iowa liquor purchases.</summary>
    <published>2020-05-13T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-05-06</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.05.06 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-05-06T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Coronavirus and race, COVID-19 in prisons, “essential” NYC construction, space dollars, and Love Island.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus and race.</strong> Last week, the COVID Tracking Project (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-18-edition">DIP 2020.03.18</a>) <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking/status/1254909756742852608">launched</a> a beta release of its <a href="https://covidtracking.com/race">COVID Racial Data Tracker</a>, built in collaboration with American University’s <a href="https://antiracismcenter.com/">Antiracist Research &amp; Policy Center</a>. The tracker collects demographic statistics, now published by most states, that disaggregate the number of COVID-19 cases and deaths by race and/or ethnicity. “This is a challenging dataset to compile and code, and our data sources remain in flux, but we offer this beta release for full transparency,” the project’s organizers write; they’re seeking feedback “as we work toward building a complete dataset and getting it into our API and onto the website.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 in prisons.</strong> The Marshall Project has been <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/05/01/a-state-by-state-look-at-coronavirus-in-prisons">tracking COVID-19 cases and deaths in US prisons</a>. To compile <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/COVID_prison_data">that dataset</a>, every week the publication’s reporters ask each state prison system and the federal Bureau of Prisons “for the total number of coronavirus tests administered to its staff members and prisoners, the cumulative number who tested positive among staff and prisoners, and the numbers of deaths for each group.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Essential NYC construction sites.</strong> New York City’s Department of Buildings has been publishing a <a href="https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/buildings/html/essential-active-construction.html">dataset and interactive map</a> of construction sites deemed “essential,” and thus <a href="https://www1.nyc.gov/site/buildings/about/essential-construction-faq.page">eligible to continue work</a> during the coronavirus pandemic. The current list covers more than 6,700 sites, including more than 1,200 at schools, 1,000 for public housing, and 250 related to health care. [h/t <a href="https://tinyletter.com/nycdatajobs/letters/nyc-data-188-spotify-northwell-health-the-knot-predicting-weekly-unemployment-claims-turner-cit-bayer">Josh Laurito</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Space dollars.</strong> <a href="https://www.planetary.org/get-involved/be-a-space-advocate/become-an-expert/planetary-exploration-budget-dataset.html">The Planetary Science Budget Dataset</a> “integrates the spending history, by year, of every NASA planetary science mission and related activities.” It also calculates funding by destination (e.g., Mars, Venus, the moon, etc.), and annual budget breakdowns for individual missions. The dataset is maintained by <a href="https://www.planetary.org/about/">The Planetary Society</a>, a nonprofit founded 40 years ago by Carl Sagan, Louis Friedman, and Bruce Murray — and now led by Bill Nye. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/lifewinning/status/1257431537252999168">Ingrid Burrington</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Love Island.</strong> Developer advocate <a href="https://twitter.com/AmyKateNicho">Amy Boyd</a> has assembled <a href="https://github.com/amynic/love-island-workshop">a dataset of 96 contestants</a> who appeared on the British dating reality series <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Island_(2015_TV_series)"><em>Love Island</em></a> from 2016 to 2019, including each contestant’s name, age, profession, and various metrics of success in the competition. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/nckltcha/status/1253977479204818944">Nick Latocha</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send competitively-romantic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-06-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Coronavirus and race, COVID-19 in prisons, “essential” NYC construction, space dollars, and Love Island.</summary>
    <published>2020-05-06T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-04-29</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.29 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Parlimentary speeches, COVID-19 preprints, mobility indicators, US retail, and poems by kids.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Six million parliamentary speeches.</strong> <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L4OAKN">ParlSpeech V2</a> contains 6.3 million parliamentary speeches from nine countries: Austria, the Czech Republic, Germany, Denmark, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Spain, Sweden, and the United Kingdom. The dataset, created by political scientists <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/christianrauh/">Christian Rauh</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/janschwalbach">Jan Schwalbach</a>, includes the full text of each speech, plus the date, speaker, and the speaker’s party. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="http://personal.lse.ac.uk/hix/HixNouryRolandEPdata.HTM">Roll call votes from the European Parliament’s first six terms</a> (1979–2009). [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/pull/5">Robert Stelzle</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 preprints.</strong> Preprints — academic papers published online before they’ve gone through traditional peer review — have become a common way for scientists to disseminate their coronavirus-related findings. So researchers <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7582-6339">Nicholas Fraser</a> and <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5965-6560">Bianca Kramer</a> have begun compiling a <a href="https://github.com/nicholasmfraser/covid19_preprints">dataset of more than 6,000 COVID-19 preprints</a>. For each paper, the dataset includes the title, abstract, DOI, date posted, and the hosting repository (such as <a href="https://www.medrxiv.org/">medRxiv</a>, the most common so far).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mobility indicators.</strong> Tech companies have repurposed some of the data they collect from you into explorable, downloadable datasets that estimate the degree to which movement patterns have (or haven’t) changed in recent months. Among them: Apple, which is <a href="https://www.apple.com/covid19/mobility">quantifying requests for directions</a>; Google, which is <a href="https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/">counting visits to places such as grocery stores and transit station</a>; and Descartes Labs, which is <a href="https://github.com/descarteslabs/DL-COVID-19">tracking smartphone movements</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: Sociologist <a href="https://kieranhealy.org/about/">Kieran Healy</a> recently <a href="https://kieranhealy.org/blog/archives/2020/04/23/apples-covid-mobility-data/">found and explained</a> a curious February 17 spike in Apple’s data. [h/t <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/hillary/status/1250130170029248512">Hillary Hartley</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US retail.</strong> Since the 1950s, the US Census Bureau has conducted <a href="https://www.census.gov/retail/index.html">monthly surveys of retail and food-services industries</a>. The results — which estimate sales and inventory numbers by subsector — are available as machine-readable data going back to 1992. The next release is scheduled for May 15. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/b13add45c669/preview-222-in-other-news-3862701">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Poems by kids.</strong> <a href="https://github.com/whipson/PoKi-Poems-by-Kids">PoKi</a> is “a corpus of 61,330 poems written by children from grades 1 to 12,” scraped with permission from <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20191025052907/teacher.scholastic.com/writewit/poetry/jack_readall.asp">a Scholastic website</a>. The dataset includes each poem’s title, text, and character count, plus the author’s first name and grade. <strong>Noteworthy</strong>: “PoKi is made freely available for research with the condition that the research be used for the benefit of children.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send precocious feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-29-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Parlimentary speeches, COVID-19 preprints, mobility indicators, US retail, and poems by kids.</summary>
    <published>2020-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-04-22</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.22 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-04-22T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>A COVID policy tracker–tracker, every US Census question since 1790, chemical weapons in Syria, NYC sidewalks, and crowdsourced moral judgments.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tracking the COVID policy trackers.</strong> Economics graduate student <a href="https://www.spi.ox.ac.uk/people/lukas-lehner">Lukas Lehner</a> has gathered, <a href="https://twitter.com/LukasLehner_/status/1251048564899397632">with help from the hive-mind</a>, a list of <a href="https://lukaslehner.github.io/covid19policytrackers/">dozens of websites and datasets tracking policy responses</a> to the COVID-19 pandemic – a few that have been mentioned in DIP, plus many that haven’t. Lehner’s tracker-tracker groups the resources into several topic areas, summarizes them, and indicates their data formats. [h/t <a href="https://f.briatte.org/">François Briatte</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Every Census question, ever.</strong> Programmer <a href="https://github.com/anbnyc">Alec Barrett</a> has built a spreadsheet listing <a href="https://github.com/the-pudding/data/tree/master/census-history">every question asked on every decennial US Census</a> since 1790 — more than 900 items overall. In addition to the questions themselves, the dataset describes the subgroups of people questioned and the types of answers expected. <strong>Related</strong>: The dataset powers “<a href="https://pudding.cool/2020/03/census-history/">The Evolution of the American Census</a>,” Barrett’s interactive exploration of how the questions have changed over time, and what they say about America.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Chemical weapons attacks in Syria.</strong> “Building on years of painstaking work alongside our Syrian and international partners,” the <a href="https://chemicalweapons.gppi.net/">Global Public Policy Institute</a> “has compiled the most comprehensive dataset of incidents of chemical weapons use in Syria to date.” The institute has published a <a href="https://chemicalweapons.gppi.net/data-portal/">new interactive data portal</a> to display the data on 345 attacks between 2012 and 2019. The data fields include the date and time of the attack, location, chemical agent, munition type and method of delivery, perpetrator, confidence rating, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/1247665719334100994">Tobias Schneider</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NYC sidewalks, narrow and broad.</strong> Urban planner <a href="http://meliharvey.com/">Meli Harvey</a> has taken <a href="https://data.cityofnewyork.us/City-Government/Sidewalk/vfx9-tbb6">New York City’s official dataset of sidewalks</a> and <a href="https://github.com/meliharvey/sidewalkwidths-nyc">dissected its geometries</a> to <a href="http://www.sidewalkwidths.nyc/">map the width of each segment of walkable pavement</a>. [h/t <a href="https://danjbrady.com">Dan Brady</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Crowdsourced moral judgements.</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://www.elle-obrien.com/">Elle O’Brien</a> <a href="https://dvc.org/blog/a-public-reddit-dataset">recently described</a> how she built and cleaned a <a href="https://github.com/iterative/aita_dataset">dataset of the moral dilemmas</a> posted to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/">r/AmItheAsshole</a>, “a semi-structured online forum that’s the internet’s closest approximation of a judicial system.” For each of the 97,628 posts collected, the dataset includes the title, body, date, number of Reddit upvotes, and number of comments — plus the community’s verdict. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/f5t5fo/a_public_dataset_of_reddit_posts_about_moral/">u/thumbsdrivesmecrazy</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send morally-questionable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-22-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A COVID policy tracker–tracker, every US Census question since 1790, chemical weapons in Syria, NYC sidewalks, and crowdsourced moral judgments.</summary>
    <published>2020-04-22T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-04-15</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.15 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>COVID-19 testing around the world, aggregated smartphone movements, privacy policies, NYC trash, and Animal Crossing.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 testing around the world.</strong> Nearly every country publishes the number of residents who’ve tested positive for COVID-19. Far fewer post data on the total number of <em>people tested</em> (or <em>tests performed</em>). But as more countries start doing that, the team at <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/">Our World In Data</a> has begun compiling a <a href="https://github.com/owid/covid-19-data/tree/master/public/data/testing">regularly-updated dataset on COVID-19 testing</a>, along with <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/covid-testing">key context, a detailed methodology, and interactive charts</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Aggregated smartphone movements.</strong> A team of academics has begun publishing a <a href="https://github.com/COVIDExposureIndices/COVIDExposureIndices">series of “exposure indices”</a> based on smartphone “pings” collected by a location-analytics company. One set of indices describes the proportion of smartphones that, on a given day in a given US state or county, were observed at least once in another given state or county during the previous 14 days. Another tries to quantify how often smartphones are observed in the same “commercial venues” as other devices. “We are making these indices publicly available to all researchers in the context of the spread of COVID-19,” the researchers write.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Privacy policies.</strong> Researchers at Imperial College London and Oxford have compiled a dataset of <a href="https://github.com/ansgarw/privacy">more than 4,000 privacy policies</a> published on major US companies’ websites. For each policy, the dataset includes its full text, counts the number of words and paragraphs in it, calculates a readability metric, and reports the number of third-party tracking cookies loaded through the policy’s webpage. [h/t <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/a.uettwiller17">Antione Uettwiller</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Thirty years of NYC trash and recycling.</strong> New York City’s Department of Sanitation publishes a dataset of <a href="https://data.cityofnewyork.us/City-Government/DSNY-Monthly-Tonnage-Data/ebb7-mvp5">the monthly tonnage it collects from city residences</a>, going back to 1990. For each community district and month, the dataset tallies the weight of household trash, recyclables, “organics,” and more — including, for each January, the tonnage of Christmas trees collected. <strong>Related</strong>: Reporters at The City recently analyzed the dataset, and <a href="https://thecity.nyc/2020/04/garbage-pickups-tell-tale-of-two-cities-as-manhattan-shrinks.html">found potential evidence of Manhattanites fleeing the city in March</a>. They also interviewed the Department of Sanitation’s <a href="https://robinnagle.com/">anthropologist-in-residence</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Animal Crossing.</strong> <a href="https://villagerdb.com/">VillagerDB</a> is an online and <a href="https://github.com/jefflomacy/villagerdb/tree/master/data">downloadable</a> database of thousands of the characters, accessories, tools, and other items in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Crossing:_New_Horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> — the <em>Sims</em>-like game that’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/26/21195022/animal-crossing-switch-sales-japan-famitsu">breaking sales records</a> and <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scaachikoul/animal-crossing-quarantine-distraction">saving my colleague’s marriage</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ACWorldBlog/status/1248376259735769090">Justin</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send deserted-island feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-15-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>COVID-19 testing around the world, aggregated smartphone movements, privacy policies, NYC trash, and Animal Crossing.</summary>
    <published>2020-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-04-08</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.08 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-04-08T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Pandemic-era economic policies, historical economic productivity, FOIA figures, police drones, and a lot of domain names.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pandemic-era economic policies.</strong> A group of researchers have built a structured dataset quantifying <a href="http://web.boun.edu.tr/elgin/COVID.htm">166 countries’ economic responses to the COVID-19 pandemic</a>. The dataset draws mainly from the <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Topics/imf-and-covid19/Policy-Responses-to-COVID-19">International Monetary Fund’s COVID-19 Policy Tracker</a> — which describes the policies in free-form text — and supplements it with additional research. The quantified policies include fiscal stimuli, monetary stimuli, interest-rate cuts, and interventions to control the countries’ balance of payments. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/fve5ta/dataset_economic_policy_measures_adopted_by_166/">u/smurfyjenkins</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Historical economic productivity.</strong> The <a href="http://longtermproductivity.com/">Long-Term Productivity database</a> was created at the Bank of France in 2013, and has been updated several times since then. For 23 OECD countries from 1890 to 2018, the database tracks <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Total_factor_productivity">total factor productivity</a>, <a href="https://data.oecd.org/lprdty/gdp-per-hour-worked.htm">labor productivity</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_intensity">capital intensity</a>, GDP per capita, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.mokhtartabari.ca/">Mokhtar Tabari</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Forty-plus years of FOIA.</strong> Journalism professor <a href="https://www.ajaywagner.com/">A.Jay Wagner</a> has compiled a dataset of <a href="https://epublications.marquette.edu/comm_data/1/">14 federal agencies’ Freedom of Information Act annual reports</a> from 1975 through 2018. For each agency and year, the dataset contains the number of FOIA requests processed, granted, and denied; exemptions invoked; appeal outcomes; staffing figures; fees assessed; and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgelevines/">George LeVines</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police drones.</strong> Last month, the <a href="https://dronecenter.bard.edu/about/">Center for the Study of the Drone at Bard College</a> released the third edition of its <a href="https://dronecenter.bard.edu/projects/public-safety-drones-project/public-safety-drones-3rd-edition/">Public Safety Drones report</a>, in which researchers identified “1,578 state and local police, sheriff, fire, and emergency services agencies in the U.S. that are believed to have acquired drones.” You can explore and download the data through <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=1zcTdAkQB_gqVX383oQcyujM7Nd85rquH">the report’s interactive map</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lot of domain names.</strong> Software engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bohdanturkynewych">Bohdan Turkynewych</a> has compiled a <a href="https://github.com/tb0hdan/domains">dataset of more than 50 million domain names</a>, discovered by crawling the web and processing 86 terabytes of internet traffic. <strong>Related</strong>: French registry <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_fran%C3%A7aise_pour_le_nommage_Internet_en_coop%C3%A9ration">Afnic</a> publishes a <a href="http://opendata.afnic.fr/en/products-and-services/services/opendata-en.html">full list of all registered <em>.fr</em> domains</a>. [h/t <a href="https://opendata.stackexchange.com/a/6835">Javier Sáenz</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send DNS-queryable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-08-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Pandemic-era economic policies, historical economic productivity, FOIA figures, police drones, and a lot of domain names.</summary>
    <published>2020-04-08T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-04-01</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.01 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Still more coronavirus data, but also visa fees, iPhone search warrants, and the Encyclopaedia Britannica.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Subnational COVID-19 case counts.</strong> The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/coronavirus-county-data-us.html">is conducting</a> “a round-the-clock effort to tally every known coronavirus case in the United States,” and has begun publishing <a href="https://github.com/nytimes/covid-19-data">a dataset of county-level cases and deaths</a>. France publishes <a href="https://www.data.gouv.fr/fr/datasets/donnees-hospitalieres-relatives-a-lepidemie-de-covid-19/">spreadsheets of COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths</a> by <em>département</em> and sex; on GitHub, <a href="https://github.com/opencovid19-fr/data">there’s an active effort</a> to collect and standardize this dataset and others from France. The German government has a <a href="https://experience.arcgis.com/experience/478220a4c454480e823b17327b2bf1d4/page/page_1/">dashboard showing official case counts</a> in each of its <em>Bundesländer</em> and <em>Landkreise</em>; software engineer <a href="https://gehrcke.de/about/">Jan-Philip Gehrcke</a> has been <a href="https://github.com/jgehrcke/covid-19-germany-gae">pulling that data into standardized CSV files</a>. Spain publishes daily case, hospitalization, death, and recovery counts for each <em>comunidad autónoma</em>, as a <a href="https://covid19.isciii.es/">dashboard with downloadable data</a>; investigative outlet <a href="https://datadista.com/">Datadista</a> has been <a href="https://github.com/datadista/datasets/tree/master/COVID%2019">compiling and standardizing that dataset and similar ones</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Official coronavirus interventions, continued.</strong> The <a href="https://www.bsg.ox.ac.uk/research/research-projects/oxford-covid-19-government-response-tracker">Oxford COVID-19 Government Response Tracker</a> “aims to track and compare government responses to the coronavirus outbreak worldwide rigorously and consistently.” The project posts daily information concerning 11 kinds of responses, ranging from travel bans to investment in vaccines, and is based on data “collected from public sources by a team of dozens of Oxford University students and staff from every part of the world.” One of those public sources is UNESCO, which has been tracking <a href="https://en.unesco.org/covid19/educationresponse">countries’ school closure policies over time</a>. In the US, the Kaiser Family Foundation is keeping tabs on the <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/issue-brief/state-data-and-policy-actions-to-address-coronavirus/">current mandates issued by state governors</a> (rather than legislators or local governments).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Visa fees.</strong> The <a href="http://www.migrationpolicycentre.eu/globalmobilities/dataset/">Global Visa Cost Dataset</a>, published by the European University Institute’s <a href="http://www.migrationpolicycentre.eu/about/">Migration Policy Centre</a>, “reports the cost [in 2019] of country-to-country visas for tourism, student, business, work, transit, family reunification and other motives worldwide.” The dataset’s authors describe their methodology and findings in a <a href="https://cadmus.eui.eu/handle/1814/66583">detailed working paper</a>. There is, they write, “a fundamentally paradoxical situation: The richer a country, the less its citizens pay for visas to go abroad.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>iPhone search warrants.</strong> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/pkeeay/apple-dmca-take-down-tweet-containing-an-iphone-encryption-key">In light of ongoing debates over encryption</a>, tech publication Motherboard “collected and analyzed over <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1l20Kgp77tG7BBDnblx8vH_VWevuCbPkg?usp=sharing">500 iPhone search warrants and related documents</a> filed throughout 2019 to <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Xmh1QEXYJmVPFlqAdEIVGemvbkoZmk_WyAPGC4eY-eE/edit?usp=sharing">build a database of cases</a> in which law enforcement attempted to get information from an iPhone.” The database, published last month, includes court-docket information, the requesting agency, the suspected crimes, phone models, and more. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22557091">Colin Prince</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Before Wikipedia.</strong> The National Library of Scotland has digitized <a href="https://data.nls.uk/data/digitised-collections/encyclopaedia-britannica/">the first eight editions of the Encyclopaedia Britannica</a>, issued between 1768 and 1860. The effort, which captured approximately 167 million words across 143 volumes, was named a runner-up in the <a href="http://dhawards.org/dhawards2019/results/">2019 Digital Humanities Awards</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send know-it-all feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-01-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Still more coronavirus data, but also visa fees, iPhone search warrants, and the Encyclopaedia Britannica.</summary>
    <published>2020-04-01T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
