<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Is Plural</title>
    <link>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</link>
    <description>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.11.11 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-11-11-edition</link>
      <description>Child detention, USPS performance, transit costs, the early Islamic world, and the opera.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Child detention, USPS performance, transit costs, the early Islamic world, and the opera.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Child detention.</strong> The Marshall Project has <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/cbp-migrantchildren-detention-data">obtained and published</a> official data from US Customs and Border Protection listing 580,000+ times that the agency detained migrant children since early 2017. For each detention, the dataset <a href="https://observablehq.com/@themarshallproject/cbp-child-detentions-2017-to-2020">includes</a> the date and time the child entered and left CBP custody, as well as the child’s age, gender, and citizenship. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/10/30/500-000-kids-30-million-hours-trump-s-vast-expansion-of-child-detention">The Marshall Project’s report on the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>USPS performance.</strong> As part of <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/17449832/jones-v-united-states-postal-service/"><em>Jones v. United States Postal Service</em></a>, a federal lawsuit filed in August, USPS must submit weekly performance reports that indicate, at a national and district level, the percentage of mail that was processed (though not necessarily delivered) on time. The agency files these reports as PDFs; <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/">Save the Post Office</a>, a <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/about/">decade-old website run by a retired English professor</a>, has been <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/updates-on-the-service-performance-reports/">collecting those PDFs</a> and converting them <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1WIiUIu0PP_5D1j8R_-T7IN7kVWk9lvuj">into spreadsheets</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://themail.substack.com/p/crunch-time">Aaron Gordon’s pre-election analysis of the USPS data</a>, from <a href="https://themail.substack.com/">Gordon’s (limited-run) newsletter about the postal service</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Transit costs.</strong> “Why do transit-infrastructure projects in New York cost 20 times more on a per kilometer basis than in Seoul?” With the aim of answering questions like these, the NYU-based <a href="https://transitcosts.com/about/">Transit Costs Project</a> is building <a href="https://transitcosts.com/data/">a dataset</a> that already spans <a href="https://transitcosts.com/projects/">more than 500 urban rail projects</a> around the world. For each project, the dataset specifies the city, start year, end year, rail length, number of stations, total cost, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The early Islamic world.</strong> The <a href="https://althurayya.github.io/">al-Ṯurayyā Project</a> features an interactive map of the early Islamic world, with 2,000 named locations — from Damascus to Baghdad and beyond — and historical routes between them. The <a href="https://github.com/althurayya/althurayya.github.io/tree/master/master">underlying dataset</a> includes geocoordinates, Arabic spellings, transliterations, primary sources, and other details. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JajRK/status/1299889379817775106">Jajwalya Karajgikar</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The opera.</strong> <a href="https://www.operabase.com/">Operabase</a> has gathered information about more than 500,000 opera performances staged since 1996. The website doesn’t provide direct downloads but you can access <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/8LUFN8">a dataset on six full seasons of stagings</a>, covering thousands of runs in hundreds of cities, thanks to a “data donation” to support <a href="https://ideas.repec.org/e/pcu83.html">Alexander N. Cuntz</a>’s <a href="https://www.wipo.int/publications/en/details.jsp?id=4521">study of how copyright affects performance frequency</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send glass-shattering feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-11-11</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.10.28 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-10-28-edition</link>
      <description>Pregnancy/birth/abortion rates, COVID-19 in ICE facilities, mining areas, e-bike/scooter laws, and witch trials.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Pregnancy/birth/abortion rates, COVID-19 in ICE facilities, mining areas, e-bike/scooter laws, and witch trials.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pregnancy, birth, and abortion.</strong> Last month the Guttmacher Institute, a “research and policy organization committed to advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights,” <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/report/pregnancies-births-abortions-in-united-states-1973-2016#">released</a> its <a href="https://osf.io/kthnf/">latest estimates of annual pregnancies, births, and abortions</a> among women in the US — overall, and also by <a href="https://guttinst.github.io/National-State-Pregnancy-Codebook/">age-group and state</a>. The national statistics cover 1973 to 2016, while the state-level numbers go from 1988 to 2016; both sets of estimates are derived from a combination of government data and the institute’s own <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/report/abortion-incidence-service-availability-us-2017">Abortion Provider Census</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/Imaddowzimet/status/1313501719406555138">An introductory Twitter thread</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Imaddowzimet">Isaac Maddow-Zimet</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 in ICE facilities.</strong> Since late March, US Immigration and Customs Enforcement has been <a href="https://www.ice.gov/coronavirus">updating a webpage</a> that tallies coronavirus cases and deaths at each of its detention facilities. But the site doesn’t provide any historical numbers; it’s just a snapshot. To fill that gap, the <a href="https://www.vera.org/">Vera Institute of Justice</a> has been continually downloading the webpage, parsing it, and <a href="https://github.com/vera-institute/ice-detention-covid">turning the information into structured, longitudinal data</a>. <strong>Related:</strong> Over the summer, <a href="https://www.vera.org/the-hidden-curve-covid-19-in-ice-detention">Vera used the data to estimate “the true scope” of COVID-19 in ICE detention</a>, and called on the agency to provide more detailed statistics.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mining areas.</strong> A team of academics has built a <a href="https://doi.pangaea.de/10.1594/PANGAEA.910894">dataset</a> and <a href="https://www.fineprint.global/visualisations/viewer/">map</a> indicating the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-00624-w">geographic extents of 6,000+ mining sites around the world</a>. The project traces out 21,000+ polygons covering 57,000+ square kilometers, with boundaries based on experts’ visual interpretation of satellite imagery. It focuses on “above-ground features,” such as “open cuts, tailings dams, waste rock dumps, water ponds, and processing infrastructure.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>E-bike and e-scooter laws.</strong> A dataset of <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/W9NGI2">state regulations pertaining to standard bicycles, electric bicycles, and electric scooters</a> accompanies <a href="https://repository.law.umich.edu/jlm/vol2020/iss1/2/">a recent paper in the Journal of Law and Mobility</a>. It includes various classifications for each state — indicating, for instance, whether riders can use the sidewalk, whether adults must wear helmets, and whether DUI laws apply.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Witch trials.</strong> Some years ago, economists <a href="https://economics.gmu.edu/people/pleeson">Peter T. Leeson</a> and <a href="https://www.jakeruss.com/">Jake Russ</a> compiled a <a href="https://github.com/JakeRuss/witch-trials">dataset of 10,000+ witch trials in Europe</a>. Over the course of 550 years, the trials accused more than 43,000 people and led to 16,000 deaths. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.peterleeson.com/Witch_Trials.pdf">Leeson and Russ’s academic paper analyzing the data</a> (PDF). <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.shca.ed.ac.uk/Research/witches/">The Survey of Scottish Witchcraft</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-01-27-edition">DIP 2016.01.27</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-blasts-birdwatchers-and-battleground-states-272882">Sophie Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send allegedly-wicked feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-10-28</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.10.21 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-10-21-edition</link>
      <description>Voting equipment, jail deaths, college athletics, bug bounties, and shrinking salmon.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Voting equipment, jail deaths, college athletics, bug bounties, and shrinking salmon.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Voting equipment.</strong> <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/">Verified Voting</a> is “a non-partisan organization focused exclusively on the critical role technology plays in election administration," and its <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/verifier/">Verifier project</a> provides “the only comprehensive data set of voting equipment down to the precinct level of the United States, going back to 2006.” For each election year and jurisdiction, the database indicates the type of technology in use (ranging from hand-counted paper ballots to touchscreen systems), equipment brands and models, and other details, such as whether there is a “voter-verified paper audit trail.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jonpcohen">Jonathan Cohen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Jail deaths.</strong> Last week, Reuters published an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-deaths/">investigation into deaths in US jails</a>. Because the federal government doesn’t publish jail-by-jail mortality data, reporters “filed more than 1,500 records requests to obtain information about deaths in 523 U.S. jails – every jail with an average population of 750 or more inmates, and the 10 largest jails or jail systems in nearly every state.” The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-graphic/">resulting dataset</a> contains details about more than 7,500 inmate deaths between 2008 and 2019, including the cause of death, custody status, and demographic information. <strong>Among the findings</strong>: “At least two-thirds of the dead inmates identified by Reuters, 4,998 people, were never convicted of the charges on which they were being held.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/grantmeaccess">Grant Smith</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>College athletics.</strong> The <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/finaid/prof/resources/athletics/eada.html">Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act</a> requires thousands of US colleges to provide annual data on athletic particpation, staffing, and finances by team gender and sport. <a href="https://ope.ed.gov/athletics/">School- and team-level datasets</a> are available through the Department of Education for the academic years ending 2003–19. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/coronavirus-college-football-profit-sec-acc-pac-12-big-ten-millions-fall-2020/">USAFacts recently used the data to examine college football finances</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sashananderson">Sasha Anderson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bug bounties.</strong> Technology companies often offer “bug bounties” — rewards to people who tell them about vulnerabilities in their websites and apps, often coordinated through online platforms. For the past few years, security engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/arkadiyt">Arkadiy Tetelman</a> has been scraping and publishing data about <a href="https://github.com/arkadiyt/bounty-targets-data">the bug bounty “targets” listed on several platforms</a>, including the eligible domains, maximum payouts, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Shrinking salmon.</strong> Scientists <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17726-z">recently documented</a> “widespread declines in Pacific salmon size based on 60 years of measurements from 12.5 million fish across Alaska,” collected by state officials from more than 1,000 sampling locations. The <a href="https://knb.ecoinformatics.org/view/doi:10.5063/F1707ZTM">underlying dataset</a> lists each salmon’s age, sex, length, and other details where available. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/HollyKindsvater/status/1298960157876027394">Holly Kindsvater</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send fishy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-10-21</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.10.07 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-10-07-edition</link>
      <description>Polling places, Xinjiang internment camps, historical newspaper imagery, a millennium of UK macroeconomic data, and a lifetime of first kisses.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Polling places, Xinjiang internment camps, historical newspaper imagery, a millennium of UK macroeconomic data, and a lifetime of first kisses.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Polling places.</strong> As part of <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/topics/politics/elections/ballotboxbarriers/">a new investigative series</a>, the <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/">Center for Public Integrity</a> and <a href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline">Stateline</a> have published a <a href="https://github.com/PublicI/us-polling-places">dataset of polling places</a> during the 2012–18 US general elections for 30 states (and plan to add more states “in the coming weeks”). To assemble the dataset, <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/ballotboxbarriers/data-release-sheds-light-on-past-polling-place-changes">reporters filed 1,200 records requests</a>, and then converted the disparate files they received into standardized CSVs listing each polling place’s county, precinct, name, and address.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Xinjiang internment camps.</strong> In August, BuzzFeed News published a <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/china-new-internment-camps-xinjiang-uighurs-muslims">two-part investigation</a> into China’s “vast new infrastructure” for imprisoning Muslim minorities in its Xinjiang region. The reporters used a novel methodology to of hundreds of detention facilities: <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/satellite-images-investigation-xinjiang-detention-camps">examining the gaps in Baidu Maps’ satellite imagery</a>. Last month, they published <a href="https://github.com/critocrito/xinjiang-camps-data">a dataset</a> of those facilities’ coordinates and statuses. The <a href="https://www.aspi.org.au/">Australian Strategic Policy Institute</a> has also <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/sep/24/china-has-built-380-internment-camps-in-xinjiang-study-finds">launched</a> its <a href="https://xjdp.aspi.org.au/">Xinjiang Data Project</a>, <a href="https://xjdp.aspi.org.au/data/?tab=datasets">identifying</a> <a href="https://xjdp.aspi.org.au/explainers/exploring-xinjiangs-detention-facilities/">more than 380 detention facilities</a> as well as <a href="https://xjdp.aspi.org.au/explainers/cultural-erasure/">the destruction of religious/cultural sites in the region</a>. The project — which builds on previous research <a href="https://www.aspi.org.au/report/mapping-xinjiangs-re-education-camps">by the institute</a>, BuzzFeed News, and others — classifies the detention sites into four tiers, from “low-security re-education facilities” to “suspected maximum-security prisons.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/WilliamYang120/status/1308950380219252736">William Yang</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Historical newspaper imagery.</strong> The Library of Congress’ <a href="https://news-navigator.labs.loc.gov/">Newspaper Navigator dataset</a> extracts “visual content” from more than 16 million pages of newspapers from 1789 to 1963, drawn from the library’s <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/about/">Chronicling America project</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-08-16-edition">DIP 2017.08.16</a>). To compile the dataset, its creators <a href="https://github.com/LibraryOfCongress/newspaper-navigator">used machine learning</a> to detect seven types of visuals: photos, illustrations, maps, comics, editorial cartoons, headlines, and ads. They also built <a href="https://news-navigator.labs.loc.gov/search">an interactive search tool</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.metafilter.com/188743/This-is-the-largest-dataset-of-its-kind-ever-produced">Jessamyn West</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Even older UK economic figures.</strong> The Bank of England has considerably expanded its <a href="https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/statistics/research-datasets">longitudinal dataset on the UK’s economy</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-01-25-edition">DIP 2017.01.25</a>), renaming it “a millennium of macroeconomic data.” A few indicators (such as GDP per capita) now stretch back to 1086, thanks to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domesday_Book">Domesday Book</a>, while several others (such as consumer price inflation) now extend to the 13th century. [h/t <a href="https://thelittledataset.com/about/">Alex Albright</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lifetime of first kisses.</strong> <a href="http://beebe-west.com/viz/kiss-list/">The Kiss List</a> explores artist <a href="https://www.galenbeebe.com/">Galen Beebe</a>’s 48 first kisses. Reconstructed from “memories and journals,” and developed with her partner <a href="http://beebe-west.com/john/">John West</a>, the <a href="https://github.com/jswest/kiss-list-refresh/blob/master/public/data.json.js">dataset</a> and visualization present “a set of facts that show who, what, where, when, and why I kissed how I did.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send smoochy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-10-07</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.09.30 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-09-30-edition</link>
      <description>State bills, centuries of federal debt, the Global Wind Atlas, the Social Connectedness Index, and prime numbers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>State bills, centuries of federal debt, the Global Wind Atlas, the Social Connectedness Index, and prime numbers.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>State bills.</strong> For years, <a href="https://openstates.org/">Open States</a> has allowed you to “track bills, review upcoming legislation, and see how your local representatives are voting in your state.” The <a href="https://openstates.org/about/">volunteer-driven project</a> provides <a href="https://openstates.org/data/">bulk downloads</a> of nearly all its data, plus <a href="https://docs.openstates.org/en/latest/api/v2/">an API</a>. More recently, it has started <a href="https://openstates.org/covid19/">tracking coronavirus-related legislation</a>, with data on more than 3,300 bills across the country. [h/t <a href="https://www.amycesal.com/">Amy Cesal</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Centuries of federal debt.</strong> The US Treasury’s “<a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/debt-to-the-penny/debt-to-the-penny">Debt to the Penny</a>” dataset reports the total amount of outstanding public debt issued by the federal government — updated daily and going back to April 1, 1993. As of Monday, that number was $26,811,409,726,497.33. Another of <a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/">the Treasury’s datasets</a> provides <a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/historical-debt-outstanding/historical-debt-outstanding"><em>annual</em> debt figures going back to 1789</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/shunley42/status/1301875586101583877">Sam Hunley</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Wind.</strong> The <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/">Global Wind Atlas</a> aims “to help policymakers, planners, and investors identify high-wind areas for wind power generation virtually anywhere in the world.” The internationally-funded project provides a range of <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/downloads/gis-files">global and country-specific datasets</a>, including wind speeds at various heights, as well as a <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/about/method">description of its methodology</a> and an <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/about/faq">FAQ</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AntnRueh/status/1291634332965261312">Anton Rühling</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cross-border friendliness.</strong> The <a href="https://dataforgood.fb.com/tools/social-connectedness-index/">Social Connectedness Index</a>, a collaboration between Facebook and academic researchers, quantifies “the intensity of connectedness between locations” by measuring the frequency of Facebook-friendships linking their residents. The index represents this measurement on a scale from 1 to 1,000,000,000; the <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/social-connectedness-index">publicly available datasets</a> provide it for every pair of countries, every pair of US counties, every county-country pair, and between subnational regions around the world. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/stroebel_econ/status/1247537135487299590">An illustrative Twitter thread demonstrating the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/stroebel_econ">Johannes Stroebel</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Prime numbers.</strong> Mathematician <a href="https://www.utm.edu/staff/caldwell/">Chris K. Caldwell</a> maintains a <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/search.php">searchable</a>, <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/download.php">downloadable</a> database of <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/home.php">the largest prime numbers known to humankind</a> — plus who discovered them, when, and how. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/lists/small/">Smaller primes</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send minimally-factorable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-09-30</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.09.02 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-09-02-edition</link>
      <description>The China Biographical Database, school reopenings, US cabinets since Washington, papal visits, and the Bible.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The China Biographical Database, school reopenings, US cabinets since Washington, papal visits, and the Bible.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A who’s who of historical China.</strong> The <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb">China Biographical Database</a> is packed with details on “approximately 470,000 individuals” from historical China, “primarily from the 7th through 19th centuries.” The <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/supporting-documents">extensively documented</a> records include information about kinships, social statuses, offices and postings, aliases, known addresses, and more. The project, which has a <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/history-of-cbdb">long history of its own</a>, provides <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/download-cbdb-standalone-database">bulk downloads</a> as well as <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/cbdb-api">an API</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/yifeiphu">Yifei Hu</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>School reopenings.</strong> Education Week is <a href="https://www.edweek.org/ew/section/multimedia/school-districts-reopening-plans-a-snapshot.html">collecting coronavirus-era reopening plans</a> “from a sample of school districts around the country.” The <a href="https://fs24.formsite.com/edweek/lpuqp09jhq/index.html">dataset</a> (free registration required) covers more than 800 US public school districts so far, and is being updated weekly. USAFacts has collected similar information <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-are-children-going-back-school-americas-225-largest-public-school-districts/">from the 255 largest US public school districts</a> as of August 17. And <a href="http://www.coronaviral.fyi/">coronaviral.fyi</a> has pulled together data on <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/16f99488ylGL9L1BaeqaD-yy85mayS7-BSHJS31ukiXk/edit#gid=608920111">a thousand districts’ plans</a> in Connecticut, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sashananderson">Sasha Anderson</a> + <a href="https://us19.campaign-archive.com/?u=f41127908fa3aa16b3d6c4d99&amp;id=542bdcc636">Stephen Stirling and Rebekah F. Ward</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US cabinets.</strong> UX designer <a href="https://taitcha.com/">Tait Chamberlain</a> has constructed a dataset of <a href="https://github.com/taitcha/American_cabinet_appointments">all US presidential cabinet nominations</a> — including nominees appointed, withdrawn, and rejected — from George Washington’s to the current administration. The spreadsheets contain “service dates, notable scandals, education, military service, foreign birth, known minority and gender status, whether the appointee died in office, and the senate confirmation vote tallies.” <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/">Cabinets around the world, 1966–2016</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-05-edition">DIP 2020.08.05</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Papal visits.</strong> For their “<a href="https://econpapers.repec.org/paper/zbwilewps/37.htm">Pacem in Terris: Are Papal Visits Good News for Human Rights?</a>” working paper, economists <a href="https://www.jura.uni-hamburg.de/die-fakultaet/personenverzeichnis/endrich-marek.html">Marek Endrich</a> and <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/jerggutmann/home">Jerg Gutmann</a> have compiled “<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Lr3qQvtReCAbke6DksuX5IoGMqwjbN_r/view">the first global dataset on papal travels outside of Italy</a>.” For each country-year combination between 1964 and 2017, the dataset indicates whether the Pope visited, who he was, and the country’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/HumanRightsScores">“latent human rights” score</a> for that year.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Bible.</strong> <a href="https://timmorgan.dev/">Tim Morgan</a>’s <a href="https://bible-api.com/">bible-api.com</a> “provides a JSON API for grabbing bible verses and passages.” You can choose verses from six translations in five languages, and can download both <a href="https://github.com/seven1m/bible_api">the underlying code</a> and <a href="https://github.com/seven1m/open-bibles">the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23737601">Oto Brglez</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send scriptural feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-09-02</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.26 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-26-edition</link>
      <description>The Mass Mobilization Project, ruling elites, government publications, national park trails, and bad words.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Mass Mobilization Project, ruling elites, government publications, national park trails, and bad words.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Protests around the world.</strong> The <a href="https://massmobilization.github.io/">Mass Mobilization Project</a> is “an effort to understand citizen movements against governments, what citizens want when they demonstrate against governments, and how governments respond to citizens.” The project’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/MMdata">dataset</a> covers more than 14,000 protests in more than 160 countries between 1990 and early 2017. For each protest, it indicates the location, dates, estimated number of participants, protesters’ demands, the state’s response, and more. The project, led by political scientists <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=miiCGvgAAAAJ&amp;hl=en">David H. Clark</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_M._Regan">Patrick M. Regan</a>, is indirectly funded by the CIA through the government-sponsored <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_Instability_Task_Force">Political Instability Task Force</a>. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/884ae0d5e6dce893c2ad986ae51fb09bbd0d0cd2">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Ruling elites.</strong> The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/QZ9BSA">Authoritarian Ruling Elites Database</a>, compiled by political scientist <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/austinsmatthews/home">Austin S. Matthews</a>, is “a collection of biographical and professional information on the individuals who constitute the top elite of authoritarian regimes.” Each of the project’s 18 datasets focuses on a particular regime, such as the military dictatorship that ruled Chile from 1973 to 1990. The biographical data-points include gender, occupation, dates of birth and death, tenure among the elite, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Government publications.</strong> The US Government Publishing Office’s <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/">govinfo.gov</a> provides online access to a wide range of official federal publications — including <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/bulkdata">bulk downloads</a> of <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/bills">congressional bills</a>, the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/fr">Federal Register</a>, the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/cfr">Code of Federal Regulations</a>, and more. It also provides <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/sitemaps">sitemaps</a> “to crawl and harvest content” from many of its other collections. [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christine-stefano-5615456/">Christine Stefano</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>National park trails.</strong> The US National Park Service publishes a <a href="https://public-nps.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/nps-trails-geographic-coordinate-system-1">dataset of 28,000+ lines</a> describing “formal and informal trails as well as routes within and across” the park system. The dataset provides the trail names, types, surfaces, allowed uses, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/icxtxf/csv_of_us_national_park_trails/">u/torrijasycafe</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bad words.</strong> “With millions of images in our library and billions of user-submitted keywords, we work hard at Shutterstock to make sure that bad words don’t show up in places they shouldn’t.” The company’s dataset of <a href="https://github.com/LDNOOBW/List-of-Dirty-Naughty-Obscene-and-Otherwise-Bad-Words">Dirty, Naughty, Obscene, and Otherwise Bad Words</a> contains the block-lists for their autocompletion and recommendation features, covering 2,600+ words and phrases in 28 languages. [h/t <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-04-16-f*%24!-you-in-4-languages/">Katie McCulloch</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send uncensored feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-26</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.19 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-19-edition</link>
      <description>Federal sentencing, the demographics of power, House job listings, late-medieval England immigrants, and bees.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Federal sentencing, the demographics of power, House job listings, late-medieval England immigrants, and bees.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Federal sentencing.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ussc.gov/">United States Sentencing Commission</a> publishes <a href="https://www.ussc.gov/research/datafiles/commission-datafiles">annual datasets</a>, going back to 2002, on people and organizations criminally sentenced in federal court. The files are anonymized, but contain hundreds of variables detailing the circumstances and outcomes of each decision. The commission also publishes “special collections” with additional information on drug-trafficking and economic crimes. <strong>Note</strong>: The datasets are published as SAS and SPSS files, but <a href="https://kevinhayeswilson.com/">Kevin H. Wilson</a> has shared <a href="https://github.com/khwilson/SentencingCommissionDatasets">Python code to convert them to CSVs</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/6e3a3405cf45/preview-222-in-other-news-3899490">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The demographics of power.</strong> The <a href="https://wholeads.us/">Reflective Democracy Campaign</a> and the <a href="https://www.techandciviclife.org/">Center for Technology and Civic Life</a> have partnered to produce <a href="https://wholeads.us/resources/for-researchers/">datasets examining the demographics</a> of 3,000+ elected sheriffs; 2,800+ elected prosecutors; and candidates for federal, state, and local offices in 2012, 2014, 2016, and 2018. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/teacupwoozy">Stacy Montemayor</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>House work.</strong> With help from academics and former Hill staffers, journalist <a href="http://thescoop.org/about/">Derek Willis</a> has assembled an <a href="https://github.com/dwillis/house-jobs">archive of the weekly job and internship bulletins</a> sent by the US House of Representatives. The archive, which goes back to late 2013, includes both the original PDFs and text extracted from them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Late-medieval English immigrants.</strong> <a href="https://www.englandsimmigrants.com/">England’s Immigrants 1330-1550</a> is “a fully-searchable database containing over 64,000 names of people known to have migrated to England during the period of the Hundred Years’ War and the Black Death, the Wars of the Roses and the Reformation,” drawing on “taxation assessments, letters of denization and protection, and a variety of other licences and grants.” In addition to names, the <a href="https://www.englandsimmigrants.com/browse/">dataset</a> includes nationalities, places of residence, occupations, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-british-studies/article/englands-immigrants-13301550-aliens-in-later-medieval-and-early-tudor-england/18763980AF6911AD8DEA4B5D27984007">W. Mark Ormrod</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bees.</strong> The US Geological Survey’s <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/pwrc/science/native-bee-inventory-and-monitoring-lab">Native Bee Inventory and Monitoring Lab</a> keeps tabs on the country’s bee species, including through a <a href="https://www.gbif.org/dataset/f519367d-6b9d-411c-b319-99424741e7de">dataset of more than 400,000 observations</a> of “native and non-native bees, wasps and other insects.” (Free registration required.) <strong>Related</strong>: The lab also publishes “<a href="https://prd-wret.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/assets/palladium/production/s3fs-public/atoms/files/The%20Very%20Handy%20Manual%20-%202015.pdf">The Very Handy Manual: How to Catch and Identify Bees and Manage a Collection</a>,” plus <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/usgsbiml">thousands of high-resolution photos</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send pollinating feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-19</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.12 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-12-edition</link>
      <description>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus humanitarian funding.</strong> The <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/">Centre for Disaster Protection</a> and <a href="https://devinit.org/">Development Initiatives</a> have been jointly compiling <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/funding-covid-19-response">data</a> on the <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/latest-news/funding-covid-19-response-tracking-global-humanitarian-and-development-flows-to-meet-crisis-needs">billions of dollars of humanitarian and development aid</a> that the IMF, World Bank, and other agencies have allocated in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. For each “flow” of funds, the dataset specifies the funding source, amount, approval date, purpose, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: The UN’s provides a <a href="https://pfbi.unocha.org/COVID19/">downloadable and explorable dataset</a> of its coronavirus–related humanitarian funding, and <a href="https://centre.humdata.org/covid-19-map-explorer-whats-included-and-how-we-built-it/">has built</a> an <a href="https://data.humdata.org/visualization/covid19-humanitarian-operations/">interactive map based on these and related datasets</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US climate change.</strong> On Friday, the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2020/08/07/how-use-posts-climate-data-analysis/">released</a> several <a href="https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-2C-beyond-the-limit-usa/">datasets and computer scripts</a> from its <a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/staff-washington-post">Pulitzer Prize–winning</a> series, “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/climate-environment/climate-change-america/">2°C: Beyond the Limit</a>,” which examined how “extreme climate change has arrived in America.” The data files — derived from NOAA’s <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00005">nClimDiv</a> and <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00332">nClimGrid</a> climate datasets — contain the annual average temperatures and seasonal temperature changes for each state and county in the contiguous US.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>International banking statistics.</strong> The <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/index.htm">Bank for International Settlements</a>, established in 1930 and run by <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/member_cb.htm">a group of central banks</a>, publishes a <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/index.htm">range of statistical datasets</a> “designed to inform analysis of financial stability, international monetary spillovers and global liquidity.” The datasets are available to <a href="https://stats.bis.org/statx/toc/LBS.html">explore online</a> and to <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/full_data_sets.htm">download</a>; they cover exchange rates, cross-border liabilities, consumer prices, debt service ratios, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/a09133e2c4343415c6d6cbdc81f88da3748265a5">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electric vehicle charging.</strong> A team led by public policy professor <a href="https://spp.gatech.edu/people/person/omar-isaac-asensio">Omar Asensio</a> used a field experiment to collect <a href="https://github.com/asensio-lab/workplace-charging-experiment">data on 3,395 electric vehicle charging sessions</a>. The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/NFPQLW">dataset</a> “contains sessions from 85 EV drivers with repeat usage at 105 stations across 25 sites at a workplace charging program”; it indicates the date and length of each session, total energy used, cost, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>44 million Reddit votes.</strong> On Reddit, users can choose to publicize their history of upvoting and downvoting other users’ posts. Software engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joey-leake-83229b1/">Joey Leake</a> recently <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/hzdkbp/a_huge_collection_of_reddit_voting_data/">collected</a> and <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/josephleake/huge-collection-of-reddit-votes/">published</a> data on more than 44 million of these votes. For each, Leake’s dataset lists the post ID, relevant subreddit, the vote’s timestamp (in most cases), and the voter’s username.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send thumbs-up/down feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-12</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.05 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-05-edition</link>
      <description>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cabinet members.</strong> <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/">WhoGov</a>, a new project <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/people/">led by two graduate students at Oxford</a>, provides “bibliographic information, such as gender and party affiliation, on cabinet members in July every year in the period 1966-2016 in all countries with a population of more than 400,000 citizens.” In all, <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/download-dataset/">the dataset</a> covers more than 50,000 officials and “makes it possible to answer questions such as; what is the share of female cabinet members globally, which type of regime has the highest cabinet turnover, and have cabinets increased in size over time?” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/YJuliaJung/status/1285598237068582912">Yujin Julia Jung</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxGroemping/status/1285641311677231106">Max Grömping</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Values and beliefs.</strong> The <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSContents.jsp">World Values Survey</a>, first fielded in 1981, “is the largest non-commercial, cross-national, time series investigation of human beliefs and values ever executed, currently including interviews with almost 400,000 respondents.” Last month, the project <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSEventsShow.jsp?ID=413">began releasing</a> data <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSDocumentationWV7.jsp">from its seventh wave of interviews</a>, conducted in 77 countries and covering hundreds of questions about religion, migration, stereotypes, trust, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/howlettm/status/1285279256906395648">Michael Howlett</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/SethJMeyer/status/1287439947209879552">Seth J. Meyer</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Software supply chain attacks.</strong> <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/breaking-trust-shades-of-crisis-across-an-insecure-software-supply-chain/">Breaking Trust</a>, a new project from the <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/">Atlantic Council</a>, provides <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/resources/breaking-trust-the-dataset/">a dataset</a> of 115 “software supply chain” attacks and disclosures in the past decaude. These vulnerabilities occur “when an attacker accesses and edits software somewhere in the complex software development supply chain to compromise a target farther up the chain by inserting their own malicious code.” The dataset’s examples include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuxnet">Stuxnet</a>, <a href="https://threatpost.com/500-malicious-chrome-extensions-millions/152918/">malicious browswer extensions</a>, and various attacks on software package registries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MayaKaczorowski/status/1288231258422575105">Maya Kaczorowski</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/LilyZimeng/status/1290331849928118272">Lily Liu</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Animals with SARS-CoV-2.</strong> The USDA has been <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/sa_one_health/sars-cov-2-animals-us">publishing basic information</a> about animals that its <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/lab-info-services/sa_about_nvsl/ct_about_nvsl">National Veterinary Services Laboratories</a> have confirmed contracted the novel coronvirus. The simple table — unavailable to download, but easy enough to copy-paste into a spreadsheet — lists the types of animals (mostly “Cat” and “Dog,” but also a lion and a tiger), the states they lived in, the dates confirmed, and the methods of diagnosis.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lot of CAD sketches.</strong> <a href="https://github.com/PrincetonLIPS/SketchGraphs/">SketchGraphs</a> characterizes 15 million computer-aided design (CAD) sketches, “extracted from real-world CAD models” and obtained from a popular online CAD platform. Each of the dataset’s sketches “is represented as a geometric constraint graph where edges denote designer-imposed geometric relationships between primitives, the nodes of the graph.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send impactful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-05</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
