<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Is Plural</title>
    <link>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</link>
    <description>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.09.30 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-09-30-edition</link>
      <description>State bills, centuries of federal debt, the Global Wind Atlas, the Social Connectedness Index, and prime numbers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>State bills, centuries of federal debt, the Global Wind Atlas, the Social Connectedness Index, and prime numbers.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>State bills.</strong> For years, <a href="https://openstates.org/">Open States</a> has allowed you to “track bills, review upcoming legislation, and see how your local representatives are voting in your state.” The <a href="https://openstates.org/about/">volunteer-driven project</a> provides <a href="https://openstates.org/data/">bulk downloads</a> of nearly all its data, plus <a href="https://docs.openstates.org/en/latest/api/v2/">an API</a>. More recently, it has started <a href="https://openstates.org/covid19/">tracking coronavirus-related legislation</a>, with data on more than 3,300 bills across the country. [h/t <a href="https://www.amycesal.com/">Amy Cesal</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Centuries of federal debt.</strong> The US Treasury’s “<a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/debt-to-the-penny/debt-to-the-penny">Debt to the Penny</a>” dataset reports the total amount of outstanding public debt issued by the federal government — updated daily and going back to April 1, 1993. As of Monday, that number was $26,811,409,726,497.33. Another of <a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/">the Treasury’s datasets</a> provides <a href="https://fiscaldata.treasury.gov/datasets/historical-debt-outstanding/historical-debt-outstanding"><em>annual</em> debt figures going back to 1789</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/shunley42/status/1301875586101583877">Sam Hunley</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Wind.</strong> The <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/">Global Wind Atlas</a> aims “to help policymakers, planners, and investors identify high-wind areas for wind power generation virtually anywhere in the world.” The internationally-funded project provides a range of <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/downloads/gis-files">global and country-specific datasets</a>, including wind speeds at various heights, as well as a <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/about/method">description of its methodology</a> and an <a href="https://globalwindatlas.info/about/faq">FAQ</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AntnRueh/status/1291634332965261312">Anton Rühling</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cross-border friendliness.</strong> The <a href="https://dataforgood.fb.com/tools/social-connectedness-index/">Social Connectedness Index</a>, a collaboration between Facebook and academic researchers, quantifies “the intensity of connectedness between locations” by measuring the frequency of Facebook-friendships linking their residents. The index represents this measurement on a scale from 1 to 1,000,000,000; the <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/social-connectedness-index">publicly available datasets</a> provide it for every pair of countries, every pair of US counties, every county-country pair, and between subnational regions around the world. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/stroebel_econ/status/1247537135487299590">An illustrative Twitter thread demonstrating the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/stroebel_econ">Johannes Stroebel</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Prime numbers.</strong> Mathematician <a href="https://www.utm.edu/staff/caldwell/">Chris K. Caldwell</a> maintains a <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/search.php">searchable</a>, <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/download.php">downloadable</a> database of <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/primes/home.php">the largest prime numbers known to humankind</a> — plus who discovered them, when, and how. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://primes.utm.edu/lists/small/">Smaller primes</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send minimally-factorable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-09-30</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.09.02 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-09-02-edition</link>
      <description>The China Biographical Database, school reopenings, US cabinets since Washington, papal visits, and the Bible.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The China Biographical Database, school reopenings, US cabinets since Washington, papal visits, and the Bible.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A who’s who of historical China.</strong> The <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb">China Biographical Database</a> is packed with details on “approximately 470,000 individuals” from historical China, “primarily from the 7th through 19th centuries.” The <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/supporting-documents">extensively documented</a> records include information about kinships, social statuses, offices and postings, aliases, known addresses, and more. The project, which has a <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/history-of-cbdb">long history of its own</a>, provides <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/download-cbdb-standalone-database">bulk downloads</a> as well as <a href="https://projects.iq.harvard.edu/cbdb/cbdb-api">an API</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/yifeiphu">Yifei Hu</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>School reopenings.</strong> Education Week is <a href="https://www.edweek.org/ew/section/multimedia/school-districts-reopening-plans-a-snapshot.html">collecting coronavirus-era reopening plans</a> “from a sample of school districts around the country.” The <a href="https://fs24.formsite.com/edweek/lpuqp09jhq/index.html">dataset</a> (free registration required) covers more than 800 US public school districts so far, and is being updated weekly. USAFacts has collected similar information <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-are-children-going-back-school-americas-225-largest-public-school-districts/">from the 255 largest US public school districts</a> as of August 17. And <a href="http://www.coronaviral.fyi/">coronaviral.fyi</a> has pulled together data on <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/16f99488ylGL9L1BaeqaD-yy85mayS7-BSHJS31ukiXk/edit#gid=608920111">a thousand districts’ plans</a> in Connecticut, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sashananderson">Sasha Anderson</a> + <a href="https://us19.campaign-archive.com/?u=f41127908fa3aa16b3d6c4d99&amp;id=542bdcc636">Stephen Stirling and Rebekah F. Ward</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US cabinets.</strong> UX designer <a href="https://taitcha.com/">Tait Chamberlain</a> has constructed a dataset of <a href="https://github.com/taitcha/American_cabinet_appointments">all US presidential cabinet nominations</a> — including nominees appointed, withdrawn, and rejected — from George Washington’s to the current administration. The spreadsheets contain “service dates, notable scandals, education, military service, foreign birth, known minority and gender status, whether the appointee died in office, and the senate confirmation vote tallies.” <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/">Cabinets around the world, 1966–2016</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-05-edition">DIP 2020.08.05</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Papal visits.</strong> For their “<a href="https://econpapers.repec.org/paper/zbwilewps/37.htm">Pacem in Terris: Are Papal Visits Good News for Human Rights?</a>” working paper, economists <a href="https://www.jura.uni-hamburg.de/die-fakultaet/personenverzeichnis/endrich-marek.html">Marek Endrich</a> and <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/jerggutmann/home">Jerg Gutmann</a> have compiled “<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Lr3qQvtReCAbke6DksuX5IoGMqwjbN_r/view">the first global dataset on papal travels outside of Italy</a>.” For each country-year combination between 1964 and 2017, the dataset indicates whether the Pope visited, who he was, and the country’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/HumanRightsScores">“latent human rights” score</a> for that year.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Bible.</strong> <a href="https://timmorgan.dev/">Tim Morgan</a>’s <a href="https://bible-api.com/">bible-api.com</a> “provides a JSON API for grabbing bible verses and passages.” You can choose verses from six translations in five languages, and can download both <a href="https://github.com/seven1m/bible_api">the underlying code</a> and <a href="https://github.com/seven1m/open-bibles">the data</a>. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23737601">Oto Brglez</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send scriptural feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-09-02</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.26 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-26-edition</link>
      <description>The Mass Mobilization Project, ruling elites, government publications, national park trails, and bad words.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Mass Mobilization Project, ruling elites, government publications, national park trails, and bad words.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Protests around the world.</strong> The <a href="https://massmobilization.github.io/">Mass Mobilization Project</a> is “an effort to understand citizen movements against governments, what citizens want when they demonstrate against governments, and how governments respond to citizens.” The project’s <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/MMdata">dataset</a> covers more than 14,000 protests in more than 160 countries between 1990 and early 2017. For each protest, it indicates the location, dates, estimated number of participants, protesters’ demands, the state’s response, and more. The project, led by political scientists <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=miiCGvgAAAAJ&amp;hl=en">David H. Clark</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_M._Regan">Patrick M. Regan</a>, is indirectly funded by the CIA through the government-sponsored <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_Instability_Task_Force">Political Instability Task Force</a>. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/884ae0d5e6dce893c2ad986ae51fb09bbd0d0cd2">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Ruling elites.</strong> The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/QZ9BSA">Authoritarian Ruling Elites Database</a>, compiled by political scientist <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/austinsmatthews/home">Austin S. Matthews</a>, is “a collection of biographical and professional information on the individuals who constitute the top elite of authoritarian regimes.” Each of the project’s 18 datasets focuses on a particular regime, such as the military dictatorship that ruled Chile from 1973 to 1990. The biographical data-points include gender, occupation, dates of birth and death, tenure among the elite, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Government publications.</strong> The US Government Publishing Office’s <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/">govinfo.gov</a> provides online access to a wide range of official federal publications — including <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/bulkdata">bulk downloads</a> of <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/bills">congressional bills</a>, the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/fr">Federal Register</a>, the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/cfr">Code of Federal Regulations</a>, and more. It also provides <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/sitemaps">sitemaps</a> “to crawl and harvest content” from many of its other collections. [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christine-stefano-5615456/">Christine Stefano</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>National park trails.</strong> The US National Park Service publishes a <a href="https://public-nps.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/nps-trails-geographic-coordinate-system-1">dataset of 28,000+ lines</a> describing “formal and informal trails as well as routes within and across” the park system. The dataset provides the trail names, types, surfaces, allowed uses, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/icxtxf/csv_of_us_national_park_trails/">u/torrijasycafe</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bad words.</strong> “With millions of images in our library and billions of user-submitted keywords, we work hard at Shutterstock to make sure that bad words don’t show up in places they shouldn’t.” The company’s dataset of <a href="https://github.com/LDNOOBW/List-of-Dirty-Naughty-Obscene-and-Otherwise-Bad-Words">Dirty, Naughty, Obscene, and Otherwise Bad Words</a> contains the block-lists for their autocompletion and recommendation features, covering 2,600+ words and phrases in 28 languages. [h/t <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-04-16-f*%24!-you-in-4-languages/">Katie McCulloch</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send uncensored feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-26</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.19 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-19-edition</link>
      <description>Federal sentencing, the demographics of power, House job listings, late-medieval England immigrants, and bees.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Federal sentencing, the demographics of power, House job listings, late-medieval England immigrants, and bees.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Federal sentencing.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ussc.gov/">United States Sentencing Commission</a> publishes <a href="https://www.ussc.gov/research/datafiles/commission-datafiles">annual datasets</a>, going back to 2002, on people and organizations criminally sentenced in federal court. The files are anonymized, but contain hundreds of variables detailing the circumstances and outcomes of each decision. The commission also publishes “special collections” with additional information on drug-trafficking and economic crimes. <strong>Note</strong>: The datasets are published as SAS and SPSS files, but <a href="https://kevinhayeswilson.com/">Kevin H. Wilson</a> has shared <a href="https://github.com/khwilson/SentencingCommissionDatasets">Python code to convert them to CSVs</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/6e3a3405cf45/preview-222-in-other-news-3899490">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The demographics of power.</strong> The <a href="https://wholeads.us/">Reflective Democracy Campaign</a> and the <a href="https://www.techandciviclife.org/">Center for Technology and Civic Life</a> have partnered to produce <a href="https://wholeads.us/resources/for-researchers/">datasets examining the demographics</a> of 3,000+ elected sheriffs; 2,800+ elected prosecutors; and candidates for federal, state, and local offices in 2012, 2014, 2016, and 2018. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/teacupwoozy">Stacy Montemayor</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>House work.</strong> With help from academics and former Hill staffers, journalist <a href="http://thescoop.org/about/">Derek Willis</a> has assembled an <a href="https://github.com/dwillis/house-jobs">archive of the weekly job and internship bulletins</a> sent by the US House of Representatives. The archive, which goes back to late 2013, includes both the original PDFs and text extracted from them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Late-medieval English immigrants.</strong> <a href="https://www.englandsimmigrants.com/">England’s Immigrants 1330-1550</a> is “a fully-searchable database containing over 64,000 names of people known to have migrated to England during the period of the Hundred Years’ War and the Black Death, the Wars of the Roses and the Reformation,” drawing on “taxation assessments, letters of denization and protection, and a variety of other licences and grants.” In addition to names, the <a href="https://www.englandsimmigrants.com/browse/">dataset</a> includes nationalities, places of residence, occupations, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-british-studies/article/englands-immigrants-13301550-aliens-in-later-medieval-and-early-tudor-england/18763980AF6911AD8DEA4B5D27984007">W. Mark Ormrod</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bees.</strong> The US Geological Survey’s <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/pwrc/science/native-bee-inventory-and-monitoring-lab">Native Bee Inventory and Monitoring Lab</a> keeps tabs on the country’s bee species, including through a <a href="https://www.gbif.org/dataset/f519367d-6b9d-411c-b319-99424741e7de">dataset of more than 400,000 observations</a> of “native and non-native bees, wasps and other insects.” (Free registration required.) <strong>Related</strong>: The lab also publishes “<a href="https://prd-wret.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/assets/palladium/production/s3fs-public/atoms/files/The%20Very%20Handy%20Manual%20-%202015.pdf">The Very Handy Manual: How to Catch and Identify Bees and Manage a Collection</a>,” plus <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/usgsbiml">thousands of high-resolution photos</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send pollinating feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-19</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.12 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-12-edition</link>
      <description>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus humanitarian funding.</strong> The <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/">Centre for Disaster Protection</a> and <a href="https://devinit.org/">Development Initiatives</a> have been jointly compiling <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/funding-covid-19-response">data</a> on the <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/latest-news/funding-covid-19-response-tracking-global-humanitarian-and-development-flows-to-meet-crisis-needs">billions of dollars of humanitarian and development aid</a> that the IMF, World Bank, and other agencies have allocated in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. For each “flow” of funds, the dataset specifies the funding source, amount, approval date, purpose, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: The UN’s provides a <a href="https://pfbi.unocha.org/COVID19/">downloadable and explorable dataset</a> of its coronavirus–related humanitarian funding, and <a href="https://centre.humdata.org/covid-19-map-explorer-whats-included-and-how-we-built-it/">has built</a> an <a href="https://data.humdata.org/visualization/covid19-humanitarian-operations/">interactive map based on these and related datasets</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US climate change.</strong> On Friday, the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2020/08/07/how-use-posts-climate-data-analysis/">released</a> several <a href="https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-2C-beyond-the-limit-usa/">datasets and computer scripts</a> from its <a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/staff-washington-post">Pulitzer Prize–winning</a> series, “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/climate-environment/climate-change-america/">2°C: Beyond the Limit</a>,” which examined how “extreme climate change has arrived in America.” The data files — derived from NOAA’s <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00005">nClimDiv</a> and <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00332">nClimGrid</a> climate datasets — contain the annual average temperatures and seasonal temperature changes for each state and county in the contiguous US.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>International banking statistics.</strong> The <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/index.htm">Bank for International Settlements</a>, established in 1930 and run by <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/member_cb.htm">a group of central banks</a>, publishes a <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/index.htm">range of statistical datasets</a> “designed to inform analysis of financial stability, international monetary spillovers and global liquidity.” The datasets are available to <a href="https://stats.bis.org/statx/toc/LBS.html">explore online</a> and to <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/full_data_sets.htm">download</a>; they cover exchange rates, cross-border liabilities, consumer prices, debt service ratios, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/a09133e2c4343415c6d6cbdc81f88da3748265a5">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electric vehicle charging.</strong> A team led by public policy professor <a href="https://spp.gatech.edu/people/person/omar-isaac-asensio">Omar Asensio</a> used a field experiment to collect <a href="https://github.com/asensio-lab/workplace-charging-experiment">data on 3,395 electric vehicle charging sessions</a>. The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/NFPQLW">dataset</a> “contains sessions from 85 EV drivers with repeat usage at 105 stations across 25 sites at a workplace charging program”; it indicates the date and length of each session, total energy used, cost, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>44 million Reddit votes.</strong> On Reddit, users can choose to publicize their history of upvoting and downvoting other users’ posts. Software engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joey-leake-83229b1/">Joey Leake</a> recently <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/hzdkbp/a_huge_collection_of_reddit_voting_data/">collected</a> and <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/josephleake/huge-collection-of-reddit-votes/">published</a> data on more than 44 million of these votes. For each, Leake’s dataset lists the post ID, relevant subreddit, the vote’s timestamp (in most cases), and the voter’s username.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send thumbs-up/down feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-12</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.05 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-05-edition</link>
      <description>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cabinet members.</strong> <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/">WhoGov</a>, a new project <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/people/">led by two graduate students at Oxford</a>, provides “bibliographic information, such as gender and party affiliation, on cabinet members in July every year in the period 1966-2016 in all countries with a population of more than 400,000 citizens.” In all, <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/download-dataset/">the dataset</a> covers more than 50,000 officials and “makes it possible to answer questions such as; what is the share of female cabinet members globally, which type of regime has the highest cabinet turnover, and have cabinets increased in size over time?” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/YJuliaJung/status/1285598237068582912">Yujin Julia Jung</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxGroemping/status/1285641311677231106">Max Grömping</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Values and beliefs.</strong> The <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSContents.jsp">World Values Survey</a>, first fielded in 1981, “is the largest non-commercial, cross-national, time series investigation of human beliefs and values ever executed, currently including interviews with almost 400,000 respondents.” Last month, the project <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSEventsShow.jsp?ID=413">began releasing</a> data <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSDocumentationWV7.jsp">from its seventh wave of interviews</a>, conducted in 77 countries and covering hundreds of questions about religion, migration, stereotypes, trust, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/howlettm/status/1285279256906395648">Michael Howlett</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/SethJMeyer/status/1287439947209879552">Seth J. Meyer</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Software supply chain attacks.</strong> <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/breaking-trust-shades-of-crisis-across-an-insecure-software-supply-chain/">Breaking Trust</a>, a new project from the <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/">Atlantic Council</a>, provides <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/resources/breaking-trust-the-dataset/">a dataset</a> of 115 “software supply chain” attacks and disclosures in the past decaude. These vulnerabilities occur “when an attacker accesses and edits software somewhere in the complex software development supply chain to compromise a target farther up the chain by inserting their own malicious code.” The dataset’s examples include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuxnet">Stuxnet</a>, <a href="https://threatpost.com/500-malicious-chrome-extensions-millions/152918/">malicious browswer extensions</a>, and various attacks on software package registries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MayaKaczorowski/status/1288231258422575105">Maya Kaczorowski</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/LilyZimeng/status/1290331849928118272">Lily Liu</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Animals with SARS-CoV-2.</strong> The USDA has been <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/sa_one_health/sars-cov-2-animals-us">publishing basic information</a> about animals that its <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/lab-info-services/sa_about_nvsl/ct_about_nvsl">National Veterinary Services Laboratories</a> have confirmed contracted the novel coronvirus. The simple table — unavailable to download, but easy enough to copy-paste into a spreadsheet — lists the types of animals (mostly “Cat” and “Dog,” but also a lion and a tiger), the states they lived in, the dates confirmed, and the methods of diagnosis.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lot of CAD sketches.</strong> <a href="https://github.com/PrincetonLIPS/SketchGraphs/">SketchGraphs</a> characterizes 15 million computer-aided design (CAD) sketches, “extracted from real-world CAD models” and obtained from a popular online CAD platform. Each of the dataset’s sketches “is represented as a geometric constraint graph where edges denote designer-imposed geometric relationships between primitives, the nodes of the graph.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send impactful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-08-05</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.29 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-29-edition</link>
      <description>COVID-19 vaccines and treatments, NYPD officer misconduct, thousands of political polls, territorial self-governance, and meteorite landings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>COVID-19 vaccines and treatments, NYPD officer misconduct, thousands of political polls, territorial self-governance, and meteorite landings.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 treatments and vaccines.</strong> The Milken Institute’s <a href="https://milkeninstitute.org/centers/fastercures">FasterCures project</a> is tracking <a href="https://covid-19tracker.milkeninstitute.org/">hundreds of potential COVID-19 treatments and vaccines</a>. For each candidate, <a href="https://airtable.com/shrSAi6t5WFwqo3GM/tblEzPQS5fnc0FHYR/viweyymxOAtNvo7yH?blocks=bipZFzhJ7wHPv7x9z">the project’s database</a> lists its category (e.g., DNA-based vaccines, cell-based therapies, et cetera), a brief description, its stage of development, “anticipated next steps,” funders, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.covid-19vaccinetracker.org/">The project’s interactive graphic exploring the vaccines</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NYPD officer misconduct.</strong> ProPublica <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note">has published</a> a dataset of <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/">more than 12,000 civilian complaints against nearly 4,000 NYPD officers</a>. The reporters obtained <a href="https://www.propublica.org/datastore/dataset/civilian-complaints-against-new-york-city-police-officers">the data</a> through a freedom-of-information request to New York City’s Civilian Complaint Review Board, after state lawmakers overturned a decades-old statute that had shielded the records. ProPublica’s database “lists the name of each officer, the race of the complainant and the officer, a category describing the alleged misconduct, and whether the CCRB concluded the officers’ conduct violated NYPD rules.” <strong>Related</strong>: In 2018, my colleagues <a href="https://twitter.com/KendallTTaggart">Kendall Taggart</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/michaelhayes">Mike Hayes</a> obtained <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/nypd-police-misconduct-database">thousands of NYPD disciplinary records</a> from a source who requested anonymity — <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/nypd-police-misconduct-database-explainer">giving the public access to this closely-guarded information for the first time</a> and demonstrating how the department had <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/secret-nypd-files-hundreds-of-officers-committed-serious">let hundreds of officers keep their jobs after committing fireable offenses</a>. (Soon after, the NYPD <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/mikehayes/nypd-disciplinary-review-board-created">announced an independent panel</a> to review its disciplinary program.) [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JanWillemTulp">Jan Willem Tulp</a> + <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ed-vine-a480347">Ed Vine</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US political polls.</strong> FiveThirtyEight’s frequently-updated <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/">polling database</a> provides results from thousands of polls (and hundreds of pollsters) on the current presidential, congressional, and gubernatorial elections. Those datasets — plus historical polling averages for presidential elections since 1980 — are <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/data/tree/master/polls">available to download</a>. The files list each poll’s sample size, methods, timeframe, <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/pollster-ratings/">FiveThirtyEight pollster rating</a>, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Territorial self-governance.</strong> <a href="https://www.uni-heidelberg.de/politikwissenschaften/personal/croissant/trinn_en.html">Christoph Trinn</a> and <a href="https://www.uni-heidelberg.de/politikwissenschaften/personal/croissant/schulte_en.html">Felix Schulte</a>’s <a href="https://territorial-governance.com/">TERRGO</a> dataset presents “a fresh look at territorial self-governance in more than 2,200 second-level regions in 96 Western and non-Western democracies, semi-democracies, and a selection of autocratic regimes between 2000 and 2018.” For each region (for instance, Guam or Greenland), TERRGO provides several self-governance metrics, such as whether the national constitution protects the its status and to what degree it can set taxes.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Meteorite landings.</strong> <a href="https://meteoritical.org/">The Meteoritical Society</a>’s <a href="https://www.lpi.usra.edu/meteor/">Meteoritical Bulletin Database</a> “is a clearinghouse for <em>basic</em> information about each meteorite, including the classification, place and year of discovery, whether if was observed to fall, references to catalogues in which the meteorite is described, and known synonyms that may be encountered in the literature.” The society doesn’t provide an easy way to download the full database, but NASA’s open data portal hosts a key slice of it — <a href="https://data.nasa.gov/Space-Science/Meteorite-Landings/gh4g-9sfh">45,000+ landings recorded through mid-2013</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/CraigTaylorViz">Craig Taylor</a>’s <a href="https://twitter.com/CraigTaylorViz/status/1287007372053970945">animated, 3-D rendering of the data</a>. [h/t EwanP]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send impactful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-07-29</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.22 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-22-edition</link>
      <description>Police surveillance tech, COVID-related behavior, the Mexican Migration Project, the Arctic seafloor, and the Big Mac Index.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Police surveillance tech, COVID-related behavior, the Mexican Migration Project, the Arctic seafloor, and the Big Mac Index.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police surveillance tech.</strong> The <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/">Atlas of Surveillance</a>, a new project from the <a href="https://www.eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation</a>, documents various types of surveillance technology used by 3,500 law enforcement agencies around the US. The <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/search">5,300 data-points</a>, <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/methodology">crowdsourced with the help of hundreds of students and volunteers</a>, cover a dozen categories of technology, such as automated license plate readers, facial recognition systems, and partnerships with doorbell camera–companies. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23824845">anigbrowl</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-related behavior.</strong> Since early April, Imperial College London and YouGov have been <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/global-health-innovation/our-research/covid-19-response/covid-19-behaviour-tracker/">surveying people in 29 countries</a> about their coronavirus-related behaviors and opinions. Topics include mask usage, self-isolation, working from home, vaccinations, and economic activity; the 230,000+ (anonymized) responses <a href="https://github.com/YouGov-Data/covid-19-tracker">are available to download</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AkinUnver/status/1282815737288183810">Akin Unver</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mexican migration to the US.</strong> The <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/">Mexican Migration Project</a> “was created in 1982 by an interdisciplinary team of researchers to further our understanding of the complex process of Mexican migration to the United States.” Since then, the project — co-directed by professors at the University of Guadalajara and Princeton University — has interviewed <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/dataoverview-en.aspx">more than 176,000 people</a> from <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/research/maps-en.aspx">170 communities in Mexico</a>, some who migrated and others who did not. <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/instructions-en.aspx">The datasets</a> (registration required) record <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/codebooks-en.aspx">various facets of their lives and migrations</a>: demographic, health, and economic attributes; migration timings, circumstances, and destinations; community characteristics; and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w26790">Brian K. Kovak and Rebecca Lessem</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Arctic seafloor.</strong> The <a href="https://www.gebco.net/about_us/overview/">General Bathymetric Chart of the Ocean</a> project <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0520-9">has published</a> a new version of <a href="https://www.gebco.net/data_and_products/gridded_bathymetry_data/arctic_ocean/">its Arctic Ocean depth chart</a>, which was first released in 1997 and last updated in 2012. The latest dataset incorporates new sources, has “more than twice the resolution” as the previous version, and is more precise. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://nsidc.org/data/seaice_index/">Arctic (and Antarctic) ice coverage</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-09-14-edition">DIP 2016.09.14</a>), <a href="https://twitter.com/paldhous/status/1283049748614848528">which is hitting year-over-year lows</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Big Mac Index.</strong> The Economist’s <a href="https://www.economist.com/news/2020/07/15/the-big-mac-index">Big Mac Index</a>, which the magazine invented in 1986, compares the cost of the signature McDonald’s hamburger around the world. “Burgernomics was never intended as a precise gauge of currency misalignment, merely a tool to make exchange-rate theory more digestible,” it says. “Yet the Big Mac index has become a global standard, included in several economic textbooks and the subject of dozens of academic studies.” The index is updated twice a year (including last week) and now covers 55 countries; both the data (going back to April 2000) and calculation code are <a href="https://github.com/TheEconomist/big-mac-data">available to download</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send double-patty feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-07-22</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.15 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-15-edition</link>
      <description>1.75 million US COVID patients, more goverment responses to the coronavirus, COVID cases in migrant worker dorms, 43 million court case citations, and old British lighthouses.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>1.75 million US COVID patients, more goverment responses to the coronavirus, COVID cases in migrant worker dorms, 43 million court case citations, and old British lighthouses.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>1.75 million US COVID patients.</strong> The US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has published a <a href="https://data.cdc.gov/Case-Surveillance/COVID-19-Case-Surveillance-Public-Use-Data/vbim-akqf">dataset containing demographic and medical information on 1.75 million deidentified COVID-19 patients</a>. For each confirmed or probable case, the dataset report reports the patient’s age group and race/ethnicity, the date of their initial symptoms, whether they were hospitalized, whether they had an “underlying morbidity or disease,” and more — although several of the fields contain high percentages of “unknown” values. The dataset is similar to the one The New York Times got from the CDC <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/08/podcasts/the-daily/coronavirus-data-united-states.html">through a Freedom of Information Act lawsuit</a> (see: “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/07/05/us/coronavirus-latinos-african-americans-cdc-data.html">The Fullest Look Yet at the Racial Inequity of Coronavirus</a>”), but it does not specify the patient’s county. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/zorinaq/status/1282139606905786369">Marc Bevand</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/stevenmosher/status/1282136596628688896">Steven Mosher</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More government responses to the coronavirus.</strong> The <a href="https://www.coronanet-project.org/">CoronaNet Research Project</a> aims “to collect as much information as we can about the various fine-grained actions governments are taking to defeat the coronavirus.” The project, which has drawn contributions from more than 400 researchers around the world, published its <a href="https://www.coronanet-project.org/download.html">initial release</a> a few weeks ago, and now details nearly 16,000 policy events in nearly 200 countries. <strong>Related</strong>: The nonprofit <a href="https://www.hikmahealth.org/">Hikma Health</a> says <a href="https://www.hikmahealth.org/map">it has compiled</a> “the largest county-level COVID-19 policy dataset in the nation,” covering 1,200 US counties and more than 120 Native American communities. <a href="https://github.com/hikmahealth/covid19countymap/tree/gh-pages">The dataset</a> indicates the dates on which each jurisdiction undertook various responses, such as closing schools and restricting large gatherings. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexPashanov/status/1275441552324612102">Alex Pashanov</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID cases in migrant worker dorms.</strong> The anonymous author of <a href="https://squirrellingdata.wixsite.com/home/">Squirrelling Data</a> has been <a href="https://squirrellingdata.wixsite.com/home/post/singapore-covid-19-data">collating information</a> from the Singapore Ministry of Health’s <a href="https://www.moh.gov.sg/news-highlights/">coronavirus press releases</a>. Among the datasets: <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1NcoRQkvlPTiXh1_CWtjQFyyGXNTY5enbRPNLf4cHuhc/edit#gid=0">daily case counts in dozens of migrant worker dormitories</a>, which <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/23/singapore-million-migrant-workers-suffer-as-covid-19-surges-back">have been hit hard</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.josesho.com/">Joses Ho</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Case citations.</strong> The <a href="https://case.law/about/">Caselaw Access Project</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2018-11-07-edition">DIP 2018.11.07</a>) has begun publishing a <a href="https://case.law/download/citation_graph/">citation graph</a>, a dataset listing the previous cases that each court decision cites. The <a href="https://case.law/download/citation_graph/2020-05-08/">latest release</a> covers 43 million citations. The project also provides aggregated versions of the data, plus <a href="https://case.law/exhibits/cite-grid">interactive graphics</a> showing the frequency of citations to and from courts in each state.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Old British lighthouses.</strong> The <a href="https://reshare.ukdataservice.ac.uk/854172/">Historical Light Aids to Navigation</a> dataset “shows the development of historical lighthouses, lightships, harbour lights and beacons in England and Wales for several benchmark years between 1514-1911,” <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340920308854">drawn from</a> navigational charts, government publications, and other sources. For each of the 600+ entries, the dataset provides the light aid’s name, geocoordinates, and (when available) its visibility range, height, and number of lights.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send illuminating feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-07-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.08 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-08-edition</link>
      <description>The Paycheck Protection Program, women in office, programmer surveys, UK land parcels, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Paycheck Protection Program, women in office, programmer surveys, UK land parcels, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Paycheck Protection Program.</strong> On Monday, the US Treasury Department and Small Business Administration <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm1052">released detailed data</a> on the financial assistance given to businesses through the government’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paycheck_Protection_Program">Paycheck Protection Program</a>. For the 660,000+ loans of at least $150,000, <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/cares-act/assistance-for-small-businesses/sba-paycheck-protection-program-loan-level-data">the dataset</a> includes each recipient’s name, address, industry classification, and business type, plus the name of lender, the number of jobs the business said would be supported, loan amount (grouped into several ranges), and more. For aid less than $150,000, the dataset contains similar information, but without names or addresses. <strong>Related</strong>: Efforts to make the data more accessible are already underway. <a href="https://simonwillison.net">Simon Willison</a>, for instance, <a href="https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1280283053726691329">generated</a> a <a href="https://sba-loans-covid-19.datasettes.com/loans_150k_plus/foia_150k_plus">searchable database of all loans of $150,000+</a>, and The Washington Post has published an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/business/sba-ppp-data/">interactive database of the $1,000,000+ loans</a>. <strong>Also related</strong>: <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/07/06/ppp-small-business-coroniavirus-loan-database-contains-errors.html">There are some errors in the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Women in office.</strong> Rutgers University’s <a href="https://cawp.rutgers.edu">Center for American Women and Politics</a> has made public its <a href="https://cawpdata.rutgers.edu">Women Elected Officials Database</a>, which “represents the most complete collection of information anywhere in the world about women elected officials in the United States.” It covers all “women who have held office at the congressional, statewide elected executive, and state legislative levels nationwide,” going back to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_J._Eisenhuth">the 1890s</a>. For each of the 11,540 officeholders, “the database includes their geographic information, party identification, and race identification where available.” You can <a href="https://cawpdata.rutgers.edu/women-elected-officials">explore the data online</a> and also (with a free registration) download it. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/CFPBRI">Women candidates for the US House, 1972–2010</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-07-26-edition">DIP 2017.07.26</a>) .</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Programmer surveys.</strong> For the past decade, programming Q&amp;A site <a href="https://stackoverflow.com">StackOverflow</a> has run an annual survey, asking developers about the languages they use, their workplaces, learning goals, salaries, and more. The site provides <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/">anonymized, respondent-level data</a> for each survey, including the 2020 edition, which received 64,000+ responses. Between 2016 and 2018, the not-for-profit <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org">FreeCodeCamp</a> ran an <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-2018-new-coder-survey-31-000-people-told-us-how-theyre-learning-to-code-and-getting-dev-jobs-e10feb9ed419/">annual “new coder” survey</a>, which attracted more than 31,000 responses in its most recent year; those datasets are also <a href="https://github.com/freeCodeCamp?q=new-coder-survey">available to download</a>. [h/t <a href="https://nakeddata.org/2020/06/12/the-most-loved-and-dreaded-computing-languages/">Jason Norwood-Young</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>UK land parcels.</strong> Last week, the UK <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/inspire-data-to-be-shared-under-open-terms">expanded access</a> to its <a href="https://use-land-property-data.service.gov.uk/datasets/inspire">datasets defining the geographical boundaries</a> of 23 million “title extents” in England, Wales, and <a href="https://ros.locationcentre.co.uk/inspire/">Scotland</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/price-paid-data">UK property sales</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-03-23-edition">DIP 2016.03.23</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</strong> Microsoft researchers <a href="https://twitter.com/rev_rameshkumar">Revanth Rameshkumar</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/peter_r_bailey">Peter Bailey</a> have assembled the <a href="https://github.com/RevanthRameshkumar/CRD3">Critical Role Dungeons and Dragons Dataset</a>, converting 159 transcripts of <a href="https://critrole.com">a popular, live-streamed role-playing show</a> into structured information about 398,682 bits of dialogue. [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:arnicas/">Lynn Cherny</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send monstrous feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-07-08</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
