<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Is Plural</title>
    <link>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</link>
    <description>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 08:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.05.06 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-05-06-edition</link>
      <description>Coronavirus and race, COVID-19 in prisons, “essential” NYC construction, space dollars, and Love Island.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Coronavirus and race, COVID-19 in prisons, “essential” NYC construction, space dollars, and Love Island.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus and race.</strong> Last week, the COVID Tracking Project (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-18-edition">DIP 2020.03.18</a>) <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking/status/1254909756742852608">launched</a> a beta release of its <a href="https://covidtracking.com/race">COVID Racial Data Tracker</a>, built in collaboration with American University’s <a href="https://antiracismcenter.com/">Antiracist Research &amp; Policy Center</a>. The tracker collects demographic statistics, now published by most states, that disaggregate the number of COVID-19 cases and deaths by race and/or ethnicity. “This is a challenging dataset to compile and code, and our data sources remain in flux, but we offer this beta release for full transparency,” the project’s organizers write; they’re seeking feedback “as we work toward building a complete dataset and getting it into our API and onto the website.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 in prisons.</strong> The Marshall Project has been <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/05/01/a-state-by-state-look-at-coronavirus-in-prisons">tracking COVID-19 cases and deaths in US prisons</a>. To compile <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/COVID_prison_data">that dataset</a>, every week the publication’s reporters ask each state prison system and the federal Bureau of Prisons “for the total number of coronavirus tests administered to its staff members and prisoners, the cumulative number who tested positive among staff and prisoners, and the numbers of deaths for each group.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Essential NYC construction sites.</strong> New York City’s Department of Buildings has been publishing a <a href="https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/buildings/html/essential-active-construction.html">dataset and interactive map</a> of construction sites deemed “essential,” and thus <a href="https://www1.nyc.gov/site/buildings/about/essential-construction-faq.page">eligible to continue work</a> during the coronavirus pandemic. The current list covers more than 6,700 sites, including more than 1,200 at schools, 1,000 for public housing, and 250 related to health care. [h/t <a href="https://tinyletter.com/nycdatajobs/letters/nyc-data-188-spotify-northwell-health-the-knot-predicting-weekly-unemployment-claims-turner-cit-bayer">Josh Laurito</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Space dollars.</strong> <a href="https://www.planetary.org/get-involved/be-a-space-advocate/become-an-expert/planetary-exploration-budget-dataset.html">The Planetary Science Budget Dataset</a> “integrates the spending history, by year, of every NASA planetary science mission and related activities.” It also calculates funding by destination (e.g., Mars, Venus, the moon, etc.), and annual budget breakdowns for individual missions. The dataset is maintained by <a href="https://www.planetary.org/about/">The Planetary Society</a>, a nonprofit founded 40 years ago by Carl Sagan, Louis Friedman, and Bruce Murray — and now led by Bill Nye. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/lifewinning/status/1257431537252999168">Ingrid Burrington</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Love Island.</strong> Developer advocate <a href="https://twitter.com/AmyKateNicho">Amy Boyd</a> has assembled <a href="https://github.com/amynic/love-island-workshop">a dataset of 96 contestants</a> who appeared on the British dating reality series <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Island_(2015_TV_series)"><em>Love Island</em></a> from 2016 to 2019, including each contestant’s name, age, profession, and various metrics of success in the competition. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/nckltcha/status/1253977479204818944">Nick Latocha</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send competitively-romantic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-05-06</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.29 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-29-edition</link>
      <description>Parlimentary speeches, COVID-19 preprints, mobility indicators, US retail, and poems by kids.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Parlimentary speeches, COVID-19 preprints, mobility indicators, US retail, and poems by kids.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Six million parliamentary speeches.</strong> <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L4OAKN">ParlSpeech V2</a> contains 6.3 million parliamentary speeches from nine countries: Austria, the Czech Republic, Germany, Denmark, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Spain, Sweden, and the United Kingdom. The dataset, created by political scientists <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/christianrauh/">Christian Rauh</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/janschwalbach">Jan Schwalbach</a>, includes the full text of each speech, plus the date, speaker, and the speaker’s party. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="http://personal.lse.ac.uk/hix/HixNouryRolandEPdata.HTM">Roll call votes from the European Parliament’s first six terms</a> (1979–2009). [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/pull/5">Robert Stelzle</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 preprints.</strong> Preprints — academic papers published online before they’ve gone through traditional peer review — have become a common way for scientists to disseminate their coronavirus-related findings. So researchers <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7582-6339">Nicholas Fraser</a> and <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5965-6560">Bianca Kramer</a> have begun compiling a <a href="https://github.com/nicholasmfraser/covid19_preprints">dataset of more than 6,000 COVID-19 preprints</a>. For each paper, the dataset includes the title, abstract, DOI, date posted, and the hosting repository (such as <a href="https://www.medrxiv.org/">medRxiv</a>, the most common so far).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mobility indicators.</strong> Tech companies have repurposed some of the data they collect from you into explorable, downloadable datasets that estimate the degree to which movement patterns have (or haven’t) changed in recent months. Among them: Apple, which is <a href="https://www.apple.com/covid19/mobility">quantifying requests for directions</a>; Google, which is <a href="https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/">counting visits to places such as grocery stores and transit station</a>; and Descartes Labs, which is <a href="https://github.com/descarteslabs/DL-COVID-19">tracking smartphone movements</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: Sociologist <a href="https://kieranhealy.org/about/">Kieran Healy</a> recently <a href="https://kieranhealy.org/blog/archives/2020/04/23/apples-covid-mobility-data/">found and explained</a> a curious February 17 spike in Apple’s data. [h/t <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/hillary/status/1250130170029248512">Hillary Hartley</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US retail.</strong> Since the 1950s, the US Census Bureau has conducted <a href="https://www.census.gov/retail/index.html">monthly surveys of retail and food-services industries</a>. The results — which estimate sales and inventory numbers by subsector — are available as machine-readable data going back to 1992. The next release is scheduled for May 15. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/b13add45c669/preview-222-in-other-news-3862701">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Poems by kids.</strong> <a href="https://github.com/whipson/PoKi-Poems-by-Kids">PoKi</a> is “a corpus of 61,330 poems written by children from grades 1 to 12,” scraped with permission from <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20191025052907/teacher.scholastic.com/writewit/poetry/jack_readall.asp">a Scholastic website</a>. The dataset includes each poem’s title, text, and character count, plus the author’s first name and grade. <strong>Noteworthy</strong>: “PoKi is made freely available for research with the condition that the research be used for the benefit of children.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send precocious feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-04-29</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.22 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-22-edition</link>
      <description>A COVID policy tracker–tracker, every US Census question since 1790, chemical weapons in Syria, NYC sidewalks, and crowdsourced moral judgments.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A COVID policy tracker–tracker, every US Census question since 1790, chemical weapons in Syria, NYC sidewalks, and crowdsourced moral judgments.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tracking the COVID policy trackers.</strong> Economics graduate student <a href="https://www.spi.ox.ac.uk/people/lukas-lehner">Lukas Lehner</a> has gathered, <a href="https://twitter.com/LukasLehner_/status/1251048564899397632">with help from the hive-mind</a>, a list of <a href="https://lukaslehner.github.io/covid19policytrackers/">dozens of websites and datasets tracking policy responses</a> to the COVID-19 pandemic – a few that have been mentioned in DIP, plus many that haven’t. Lehner’s tracker-tracker groups the resources into several topic areas, summarizes them, and indicates their data formats. [h/t <a href="https://f.briatte.org/">François Briatte</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Every Census question, ever.</strong> Programmer <a href="https://github.com/anbnyc">Alec Barrett</a> has built a spreadsheet listing <a href="https://github.com/the-pudding/data/tree/master/census-history">every question asked on every decennial US Census</a> since 1790 — more than 900 items overall. In addition to the questions themselves, the dataset describes the subgroups of people questioned and the types of answers expected. <strong>Related</strong>: The dataset powers “<a href="https://pudding.cool/2020/03/census-history/">The Evolution of the American Census</a>,” Barrett’s interactive exploration of how the questions have changed over time, and what they say about America.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Chemical weapons attacks in Syria.</strong> “Building on years of painstaking work alongside our Syrian and international partners,” the <a href="https://chemicalweapons.gppi.net/">Global Public Policy Institute</a> “has compiled the most comprehensive dataset of incidents of chemical weapons use in Syria to date.” The institute has published a <a href="https://chemicalweapons.gppi.net/data-portal/">new interactive data portal</a> to display the data on 345 attacks between 2012 and 2019. The data fields include the date and time of the attack, location, chemical agent, munition type and method of delivery, perpetrator, confidence rating, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/1247665719334100994">Tobias Schneider</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NYC sidewalks, narrow and broad.</strong> Urban planner <a href="http://meliharvey.com/">Meli Harvey</a> has taken <a href="https://data.cityofnewyork.us/City-Government/Sidewalk/vfx9-tbb6">New York City’s official dataset of sidewalks</a> and <a href="https://github.com/meliharvey/sidewalkwidths-nyc">dissected its geometries</a> to <a href="http://www.sidewalkwidths.nyc/">map the width of each segment of walkable pavement</a>. [h/t <a href="https://danjbrady.com">Dan Brady</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Crowdsourced moral judgements.</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://www.elle-obrien.com/">Elle O’Brien</a> <a href="https://dvc.org/blog/a-public-reddit-dataset">recently described</a> how she built and cleaned a <a href="https://github.com/iterative/aita_dataset">dataset of the moral dilemmas</a> posted to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/">r/AmItheAsshole</a>, “a semi-structured online forum that’s the internet’s closest approximation of a judicial system.” For each of the 97,628 posts collected, the dataset includes the title, body, date, number of Reddit upvotes, and number of comments — plus the community’s verdict. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/f5t5fo/a_public_dataset_of_reddit_posts_about_moral/">u/thumbsdrivesmecrazy</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send morally-questionable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-04-22</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.15 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-15-edition</link>
      <description>COVID-19 testing around the world, aggregated smartphone movements, privacy policies, NYC trash, and Animal Crossing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>COVID-19 testing around the world, aggregated smartphone movements, privacy policies, NYC trash, and Animal Crossing.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 testing around the world.</strong> Nearly every country publishes the number of residents who’ve tested positive for COVID-19. Far fewer post data on the total number of <em>people tested</em> (or <em>tests performed</em>). But as more countries start doing that, the team at <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/">Our World In Data</a> has begun compiling a <a href="https://github.com/owid/covid-19-data/tree/master/public/data/testing">regularly-updated dataset on COVID-19 testing</a>, along with <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/covid-testing">key context, a detailed methodology, and interactive charts</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Aggregated smartphone movements.</strong> A team of academics has begun publishing a <a href="https://github.com/COVIDExposureIndices/COVIDExposureIndices">series of “exposure indices”</a> based on smartphone “pings” collected by a location-analytics company. One set of indices describes the proportion of smartphones that, on a given day in a given US state or county, were observed at least once in another given state or county during the previous 14 days. Another tries to quantify how often smartphones are observed in the same “commercial venues” as other devices. “We are making these indices publicly available to all researchers in the context of the spread of COVID-19,” the researchers write.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Privacy policies.</strong> Researchers at Imperial College London and Oxford have compiled a dataset of <a href="https://github.com/ansgarw/privacy">more than 4,000 privacy policies</a> published on major US companies’ websites. For each policy, the dataset includes its full text, counts the number of words and paragraphs in it, calculates a readability metric, and reports the number of third-party tracking cookies loaded through the policy’s webpage. [h/t <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/a.uettwiller17">Antione Uettwiller</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Thirty years of NYC trash and recycling.</strong> New York City’s Department of Sanitation publishes a dataset of <a href="https://data.cityofnewyork.us/City-Government/DSNY-Monthly-Tonnage-Data/ebb7-mvp5">the monthly tonnage it collects from city residences</a>, going back to 1990. For each community district and month, the dataset tallies the weight of household trash, recyclables, “organics,” and more — including, for each January, the tonnage of Christmas trees collected. <strong>Related</strong>: Reporters at The City recently analyzed the dataset, and <a href="https://thecity.nyc/2020/04/garbage-pickups-tell-tale-of-two-cities-as-manhattan-shrinks.html">found potential evidence of Manhattanites fleeing the city in March</a>. They also interviewed the Department of Sanitation’s <a href="https://robinnagle.com/">anthropologist-in-residence</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Animal Crossing.</strong> <a href="https://villagerdb.com/">VillagerDB</a> is an online and <a href="https://github.com/jefflomacy/villagerdb/tree/master/data">downloadable</a> database of thousands of the characters, accessories, tools, and other items in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Crossing:_New_Horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> — the <em>Sims</em>-like game that’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/26/21195022/animal-crossing-switch-sales-japan-famitsu">breaking sales records</a> and <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scaachikoul/animal-crossing-quarantine-distraction">saving my colleague’s marriage</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ACWorldBlog/status/1248376259735769090">Justin</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send deserted-island feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-04-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.08 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-08-edition</link>
      <description>Pandemic-era economic policies, historical economic productivity, FOIA figures, police drones, and a lot of domain names.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Pandemic-era economic policies, historical economic productivity, FOIA figures, police drones, and a lot of domain names.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pandemic-era economic policies.</strong> A group of researchers have built a structured dataset quantifying <a href="http://web.boun.edu.tr/elgin/COVID.htm">166 countries’ economic responses to the COVID-19 pandemic</a>. The dataset draws mainly from the <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Topics/imf-and-covid19/Policy-Responses-to-COVID-19">International Monetary Fund’s COVID-19 Policy Tracker</a> — which describes the policies in free-form text — and supplements it with additional research. The quantified policies include fiscal stimuli, monetary stimuli, interest-rate cuts, and interventions to control the countries’ balance of payments. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/fve5ta/dataset_economic_policy_measures_adopted_by_166/">u/smurfyjenkins</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Historical economic productivity.</strong> The <a href="http://longtermproductivity.com/">Long-Term Productivity database</a> was created at the Bank of France in 2013, and has been updated several times since then. For 23 OECD countries from 1890 to 2018, the database tracks <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Total_factor_productivity">total factor productivity</a>, <a href="https://data.oecd.org/lprdty/gdp-per-hour-worked.htm">labor productivity</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_intensity">capital intensity</a>, GDP per capita, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.mokhtartabari.ca/">Mokhtar Tabari</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Forty-plus years of FOIA.</strong> Journalism professor <a href="https://www.ajaywagner.com/">A.Jay Wagner</a> has compiled a dataset of <a href="https://epublications.marquette.edu/comm_data/1/">14 federal agencies’ Freedom of Information Act annual reports</a> from 1975 through 2018. For each agency and year, the dataset contains the number of FOIA requests processed, granted, and denied; exemptions invoked; appeal outcomes; staffing figures; fees assessed; and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgelevines/">George LeVines</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police drones.</strong> Last month, the <a href="https://dronecenter.bard.edu/about/">Center for the Study of the Drone at Bard College</a> released the third edition of its <a href="https://dronecenter.bard.edu/projects/public-safety-drones-project/public-safety-drones-3rd-edition/">Public Safety Drones report</a>, in which researchers identified “1,578 state and local police, sheriff, fire, and emergency services agencies in the U.S. that are believed to have acquired drones.” You can explore and download the data through <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=1zcTdAkQB_gqVX383oQcyujM7Nd85rquH">the report’s interactive map</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lot of domain names.</strong> Software engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bohdanturkynewych">Bohdan Turkynewych</a> has compiled a <a href="https://github.com/tb0hdan/domains">dataset of more than 50 million domain names</a>, discovered by crawling the web and processing 86 terabytes of internet traffic. <strong>Related</strong>: French registry <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_fran%C3%A7aise_pour_le_nommage_Internet_en_coop%C3%A9ration">Afnic</a> publishes a <a href="http://opendata.afnic.fr/en/products-and-services/services/opendata-en.html">full list of all registered <em>.fr</em> domains</a>. [h/t <a href="https://opendata.stackexchange.com/a/6835">Javier Sáenz</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send DNS-queryable feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-04-08</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.04.01 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-01-edition</link>
      <description>Still more coronavirus data, but also visa fees, iPhone search warrants, and the Encyclopaedia Britannica.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Still more coronavirus data, but also visa fees, iPhone search warrants, and the Encyclopaedia Britannica.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Subnational COVID-19 case counts.</strong> The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/coronavirus-county-data-us.html">is conducting</a> “a round-the-clock effort to tally every known coronavirus case in the United States,” and has begun publishing <a href="https://github.com/nytimes/covid-19-data">a dataset of county-level cases and deaths</a>. France publishes <a href="https://www.data.gouv.fr/fr/datasets/donnees-hospitalieres-relatives-a-lepidemie-de-covid-19/">spreadsheets of COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths</a> by <em>département</em> and sex; on GitHub, <a href="https://github.com/opencovid19-fr/data">there’s an active effort</a> to collect and standardize this dataset and others from France. The German government has a <a href="https://experience.arcgis.com/experience/478220a4c454480e823b17327b2bf1d4/page/page_1/">dashboard showing official case counts</a> in each of its <em>Bundesländer</em> and <em>Landkreise</em>; software engineer <a href="https://gehrcke.de/about/">Jan-Philip Gehrcke</a> has been <a href="https://github.com/jgehrcke/covid-19-germany-gae">pulling that data into standardized CSV files</a>. Spain publishes daily case, hospitalization, death, and recovery counts for each <em>comunidad autónoma</em>, as a <a href="https://covid19.isciii.es/">dashboard with downloadable data</a>; investigative outlet <a href="https://datadista.com/">Datadista</a> has been <a href="https://github.com/datadista/datasets/tree/master/COVID%2019">compiling and standardizing that dataset and similar ones</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Official coronavirus interventions, continued.</strong> The <a href="https://www.bsg.ox.ac.uk/research/research-projects/oxford-covid-19-government-response-tracker">Oxford COVID-19 Government Response Tracker</a> “aims to track and compare government responses to the coronavirus outbreak worldwide rigorously and consistently.” The project posts daily information concerning 11 kinds of responses, ranging from travel bans to investment in vaccines, and is based on data “collected from public sources by a team of dozens of Oxford University students and staff from every part of the world.” One of those public sources is UNESCO, which has been tracking <a href="https://en.unesco.org/covid19/educationresponse">countries’ school closure policies over time</a>. In the US, the Kaiser Family Foundation is keeping tabs on the <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/issue-brief/state-data-and-policy-actions-to-address-coronavirus/">current mandates issued by state governors</a> (rather than legislators or local governments).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Visa fees.</strong> The <a href="http://www.migrationpolicycentre.eu/globalmobilities/dataset/">Global Visa Cost Dataset</a>, published by the European University Institute’s <a href="http://www.migrationpolicycentre.eu/about/">Migration Policy Centre</a>, “reports the cost [in 2019] of country-to-country visas for tourism, student, business, work, transit, family reunification and other motives worldwide.” The dataset’s authors describe their methodology and findings in a <a href="https://cadmus.eui.eu/handle/1814/66583">detailed working paper</a>. There is, they write, “a fundamentally paradoxical situation: The richer a country, the less its citizens pay for visas to go abroad.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>iPhone search warrants.</strong> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/pkeeay/apple-dmca-take-down-tweet-containing-an-iphone-encryption-key">In light of ongoing debates over encryption</a>, tech publication Motherboard “collected and analyzed over <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1l20Kgp77tG7BBDnblx8vH_VWevuCbPkg?usp=sharing">500 iPhone search warrants and related documents</a> filed throughout 2019 to <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Xmh1QEXYJmVPFlqAdEIVGemvbkoZmk_WyAPGC4eY-eE/edit?usp=sharing">build a database of cases</a> in which law enforcement attempted to get information from an iPhone.” The database, published last month, includes court-docket information, the requesting agency, the suspected crimes, phone models, and more. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22557091">Colin Prince</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Before Wikipedia.</strong> The National Library of Scotland has digitized <a href="https://data.nls.uk/data/digitised-collections/encyclopaedia-britannica/">the first eight editions of the Encyclopaedia Britannica</a>, issued between 1768 and 1860. The effort, which captured approximately 167 million words across 143 volumes, was named a runner-up in the <a href="http://dhawards.org/dhawards2019/results/">2019 Digital Humanities Awards</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send know-it-all feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-04-01</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.25 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-25-edition</link>
      <description>More coronavirus data, but also transportation data from the US Census, a prisoner survey, and very old companies.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>More coronavirus data, but also transportation data from the US Census, a prisoner survey, and very old companies.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 cases, continued.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/">European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control</a> has been publishing <a href="https://qap.ecdc.europa.eu/public/extensions/COVID-19/COVID-19.html">a COVID-19 dashboard</a> and <a href="https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/publications-data/download-todays-data-geographic-distribution-covid-19-cases-worldwide">daily-updated data files</a> tracking country-level cases and deaths. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/">Our World In Data</a> <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus-source-data">explains why the publication switched</a> from using the <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/situation-reports">World Health Organization’s situation reports</a> to the ECDC’s data for <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus">its analyses and graphics</a>. <strong>Also related</strong>: <a href="https://usafacts.org/">USAFacts</a> is using data from state governments, local public health agencies, and Johns Hopkins University (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-11-edition">DIP 2020.03.11</a>) to <a href="https://usafacts.org/visualizations/coronavirus-covid-19-spread-map/">map US cases at the county level</a>, with the underlying data available to download. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/covid19-data/covid19-data">YY Ahn</a> + <a href="https://biglocalnews.org/">Big Local News</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Official coronavirus interventions.</strong> <a href="https://www.acaps.org/who-we-are/in-short">ACAPS</a>, a humanitarian analysis nonprofit, is cataloguing <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/acaps-covid19-government-measures-dataset">government measures implemented in response to the pandemic</a>. The measures range from quarantine policies (the most common) to electronic surveillance and the lockdown of refugee camps. As of Tuesday evening, the dataset contained 1,741 entries; each entry includes the date implemented, source links, and descriptive comments. Computational social scientist <a href="https://rexdouglass.com/">Rex Douglass</a>, meanwhile, is <a href="https://github.com/rexdouglass/TIGR">crowdsourcing a dataset of mandatory government restrictions</a>, such as bans on large gatherings, restaurant shutdowns, and shelter-in-place decrees. It has fewer entries so far, but <a href="https://github.com/rexdouglass/TIGR/blob/master/data_out/TIGR_version1_latest.tsv">more detail on US cities and states</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/NArulappan/status/1240305942798848001">Nishanth Arulappan</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Getting around.</strong> The <a href="https://www.transportation.org/home/organization/">American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials</a>’ <a href="https://ctpp.transportation.org/">Census Transportation Planning Products</a> initiative “produces special tabulations of American Community Survey (ACS) data that have enhanced value for transportation planning, analysis, and strategic direction,” such as commute times, carpooling, bicycle usage, available vehicles, and more. The program’s <a href="https://ctpp.transportation.org/2012-2016-5-year-ctpp/">core dataset</a> “consists of almost 200 residence-based tables, 115 workplace-based tables and 39 flow tables (home to work) for over 325,000 geographies.” [h/t <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrienne-heller-aicp-env-sp-0b96837/">Adrienne Heller</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Prisoners, polled.</strong> <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/">The Marshall Project</a> and <a href="https://slate.com/">Slate</a> have partnered <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/03/11/how-we-pulled-off-a-groundbreaking-political-survey-behind-bars">to conduct</a> a <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/03/11/what-do-we-really-know-about-the-politics-of-people-behind-bars">survey of incarcerated people’s political views</a>. They’ve received more than 8,000 responses so far, and have made the (anonymized) data <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/incarcerated_survey">available to download</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Unfinished business.</strong> <a href="https://businessfinancing.co.uk/about/">BusinessFinancing.co.uk</a> attempted to identify <a href="https://businessfinancing.co.uk/the-oldest-company-in-almost-every-country/">the oldest, still-operating companies in every country in the world</a>, and put its findings into <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ynIAoLhz0SZYzjpwZ5e5mFzBxt6V28FTBjX7A99jq3E/edit#gid=1002274442">a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/ad9d9051041f/preview-222-in-other-news-3843345">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a> + <a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/oldest-companies/">Iman Ghosh</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send centuries-old feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-03-25</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.18 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-18-edition</link>
      <description>Mostly coronavirus-related data, but also speed dating.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Mostly coronavirus-related data, but also speed dating.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 testing in the US.</strong> The <a href="https://covidtracking.com/">COVID Tracking Project</a> “collects information from 50 US states, the District of Columbia, and 5 other U.S. territories to provide the most comprehensive testing data we can collect for the novel coronavirus, SARS-CoV-2.” The project — <a href="https://covidtracking.com/about-team/">a collaboration between <em>The Atlantic</em>, data scientist Jeff Hammerbacher, and a growing team of volunteers</a> — “attempt[s] to include positive and negative results, pending tests, and total people tested for each state or district currently reporting that data.” (Unfortunately, not all states are reporting each of those numbers, and <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking/status/1240017561757962245">private-lab testing also complicates the picture</a>.) You can access the data <a href="https://covidtracking.com/data/">online</a>, <a href="https://covidtracking.com/api/">through an API</a>, <a href="https://github.com/COVID19Tracking/covid-tracking-data">on GitHub</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/COVID19Tracking">via Twitter</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/03/how-understand-your-states-coronavirus-numbers/607921/">How to Understand Your State’s Coronavirus Numbers</a> (<em>The Atlantic</em>, March 12).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus research papers.</strong> The <a href="https://pages.semanticscholar.org/coronavirus-research">COVID-19 Open Research Dataset</a> is “a free resource of over 29,000 scholarly articles, including over 13,000 with full text, about COVID-19 and the coronavirus family of viruses for use by the global research community.” The dataset, produced by a collaboration of several research groups and the National Library of Medicine, “will be updated weekly." <strong>Related</strong>: On Monday, the White House <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/call-action-tech-community-new-machine-readable-covid-19-dataset/">issued a “call to action to the tech community”</a> regarding the dataset, asking experts “to develop new text and data mining techniques that can help the science community answer high-priority scientific questions related to COVID-19.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>WFH.</strong> <a href="https://stayinghome.club/">Stayinghome.club</a> is compiling hundreds of coronavirus-spurred <a href="https://stayinghome.club/companies.html">work-from-home policies</a>, <a href="https://stayinghome.club/universities.html">university annoucements</a>, and <a href="https://stayinghome.club/events.html">event cancellation statuses</a>. The project is <a href="https://github.com/phildini/stayinghomeclub">collaboratively edited on GitHub</a>, and includes instructions for how to add your company/university/event. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JackieKazil">Jackie Kazil</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Health security preparedness.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/about/">Global Health Security Index</a> is “the first comprehensive assessment and benchmarking of health security and related capabilities across the 195 countries” that signed on to the WHO’s 2005 <a href="https://www.who.int/ihr/legal_issues/states_parties/en/">International Health Regulations</a>. The index is built on a “framework of 140 questions, organized across 6 categories, 34 indicators, and 85 subindicators to assess a country’s capability to prevent and mitigate epidemics and pandemics.” The first edition of the index <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/news/inaugural-global-health-security-index-finds-no-country-is-prepared-for-epidemics-or-pandemics/">was released this past October</a>, and can be <a href="https://www.ghsindex.org/report-model/">downloaded as a macro-enabled Excel spreadsheet</a>. The <a href="https://nhspi.org/">National Health Security Preparedness Index</a> aims to do something similar, but for US states; the <a href="https://nhspi.org/nations-ability-to-manage-health-emergencies-rises/">2019 results</a> are also <a href="https://nhspi.org/tools-resources/2019-release-health-security-data-explorer/nhspi_2019_data_download/">available as a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="https://biglocalnews.org/">Big Local News</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Speed dating.</strong> Between 2002 and 2004, professors <a href="https://twitter.com/RFisman">Ray Fisman</a> and <a href="https://www8.gsb.columbia.edu/cbs-directory/detail/ss957">Sheena Iyengar</a> ran a series of speed dating events for Columbia University graduate students, while collecting detailed data on the participants and results. The full dataset is <a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2008/01/21/the_speeddating_1/">available to download</a>; data scientist <a href="https://drkeithmcnulty.com/">Keith McNulty</a> has also <a href="https://drkeithmcnulty.com/2020/02/14/what-matters-in-speed-dating/">created a simplified version of it</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send at-first-sight feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-03-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.11 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-11-edition</link>
      <description>More coronavirus data, plus political parties, SFO flights, Tour de France cyclists, and penguins.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>More coronavirus data, plus political parties, SFO flights, Tour de France cyclists, and penguins.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>But first ... at BuzzFeed News, we’re <a href="https://boards.greenhouse.io/buzzfeed/jobs/2117225?gh_jid=2117225">hiring a <strong>paid</strong> summer intern</a> to help us use data to cover the US presidential election (and possibly other things). If you apply, let me know at jeremy.singer-vine@buzzfeed.com; I’ll make sure to personally review all applications from DIP readers. Also feel free to send me any questions beforehand.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More coronavirus data.</strong> Last month, <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-02-05-edition">DIP featured</a> coronavirus case counts <a href="https://gisanddata.maps.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/bda7594740fd40299423467b48e9ecf6">mapped by researchers at Johns Hopkins</a>. Since then, efforts to collect and publish COVID-19 data have grown, including: the Johns Hopkins team has <a href="https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19">moved its data repository to GitHub</a> ... the <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/laninf/article/PIIS1473-3099(20)30119-5/fulltext">Open COVID-19 Data Curation Group</a> has <a href="https://github.com/beoutbreakprepared/nCoV2019">expanded its data on individual cases</a> ... the Italian government is publishing <a href="https://github.com/pcm-dpc/COVID-19">local case and test counts on GitHub</a> ... Princeton PhD student <a href="https://twitter.com/sang_woo_park">Sang Woo Park</a> is building a <a href="https://github.com/parksw3/COVID19-Korea">detailed dataset of cases in South Korea</a> ... the decade-old <a href="https://www.gisaid.org/">Global Initiative on Sharing All Influenza Data</a> is sharing <a href="https://www.gisaid.org/epiflu-applications/next-hcov-19-app/">COVID-19 genome samples and mutations</a> ... while the collaboratively-edited <a href="https://coronavirustechhandbook.com/">CoronavirusTechHandbook.com</a> is pointing to additional datasets and data-trackers. <strong>Related</strong>: My colleague <a href="https://www.peteraldhous.com/">Peter Aldhous</a> is using the Johns Hopkins data to publish clear, concise graphics tracking known case counts <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/peteraldhous/coronavirus-updating-charts-maps-us-states">globally</a> and <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/peteraldhous/coronavirus-updating-charts-maps-us-states">in the United States</a>. [h/t <a href="https://backspace.com/">John Emerson</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/HannahNamMD/status/1233929884994547715">Hannah Nam</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/brsalzano/status/1236564010318925826">Bruno Salzano</a> + <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22520069">illo</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/lamthuyvo">Lam Thuy Vo</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/magiccia">Mago Torres</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Political parties around the world.</strong> The <a href="https://www.globalpartysurvey.org/methods">Global Party Survey</a> is “an international scientific study, directed by Pippa Norris, designed to compare political parties around the world. Drawing on survey data gathered from 1,861 party and election experts, the study uses 21 core items to estimate key ideological values, issue positions, and populist rhetoric for 1,127 parties in 170 countries.” Last month, <a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/faculty/pippa-norris">Norris</a> released <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/GlobalPartySurvey">the dataset</a> and a <a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/publications/measuring-populism-worldwide">paper that uses it to measure</a> “populism as a global phenomenon.” <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://manifesto-project.wzb.eu/">The Manifesto Project</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-06-21-edition">DIP 2017.06.21</a>) and <a href="https://partyfacts.herokuapp.com/">Party Facts</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-01-16-edition">DIP 2019.01.16</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Flights in and out of SFO.</strong> San Francisco International Airport’s <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/about/">museum team</a> has been <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/blog/2019/05/17/flights/">collecting information</a> on all flights in and out of SFO’s terminals. Online, you can <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/flights/">browse and search the data</a>, which includes details about the airlines, flight numbers, gates of arrival and departure, and more. Earlier this year, the team <a href="https://millsfield.sfomuseum.org/blog/2020/01/24/flightdata/">published a downloadable database</a> of 769,250 flights from 2019. (Or 1.2 million flights, if you count <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Codeshare_agreement">codeshares</a>.) [h/t <a href="https://buttondown.email/vaguemtn">Simon Batistoni</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bicycle racers.</strong> Applied mathematics PhD student <a href="https://camminady.org/">Thomas Camminady</a> has built a <a href="https://github.com/camminady/LeTourDataSet/">spreadsheet of all Tour de France riders since 1903</a> (including name, team, time taken, and final ranking), based on <a href="https://www.letour.fr/en/history">the competition’s official results page</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Penguins.</strong> The <a href="http://www.penguinmap.com/">MAPPPD project</a> — Mapping Application for Penguin Populations and Projected Dynamics — “aims to deliver open access penguin population data for the Antarctic continent, and occupancy probabilities for flying birds around the Antarctic Peninsula.” The data, last updated about a year ago, can be both <a href="http://www.penguinmap.com/mapppd">browsed online and downloaded</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MJPolito">Michael Polito</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send tuxedoed feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-03-11</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.03.04 edition</title>
      <link>http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-04-edition</link>
      <description>Climate policies, political emails, 2.8 million Smithsonian images, London groceries, and bug splats.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Climate policies, political emails, 2.8 million Smithsonian images, London groceries, and bug splats.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Climate policies.</strong> The <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/">Climate Policy Database</a>, a project of the <a href="https://newclimate.org/about-newclimate/">NewClimate Institute</a>, has collected data on more than 3,800 regulations, subsidies, and other policies related to climate change mitigation. The <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php/Download_policies">downloadable</a> and <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php/Special:BrowsePolicy">browseable</a> database, <a href="http://climatepolicydatabase.org/index.php?title=About_the_database">drawn from more than a dozen sources</a>, includes policies from nearly every country in the world and lists the policies’ names, jurisdictions, years of enactment, general objectives, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Political emails.</strong> Reporters at the <a href="https://themarkup.org/">The Markup</a>, a <a href="https://themarkup.org/2020/02/25/editor-letter-julia-angwin">newly launched newsroom</a> that “investigates how powerful institutions are using technology to change our society,” <a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/02/26/show-your-work-wheres-my-email">subscribed to receive emails</a> from more than 200 presidential candidates, advocacy organizations, and other political groups. Four months later, they had received more than 5,000 messages, which they used <a href="https://themarkup.org/google-the-giant/2020/02/26/wheres-my-email">to examine Gmail’s treatment of political communications</a>. On GitHub, <a href="https://github.com/the-markup/investigation-wheres-my-email">they’ve published</a> the emails, relevant code, and a cleaned-up dataset. <strong>Related</strong>: Last year, FiveThirtyEight signed up for emails from the Democratic presidential campaigns; by August, they had collected 830 messages, which <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/candidate-emails">they published</a> and used <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/which-democrats-are-campaigning-on-trump/">to see who was talking most about Donald Trump</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Smithsonian imagery.</strong> “For the first time in its 174-year history, the Smithsonian has released 2.8 million high-resolution two- and three-dimensional images from across its collections onto an <a href="https://www.si.edu/openaccess">open access online platform</a> for patrons to peruse and download free of charge,” <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smithsonian-institution/smithsonian-releases-28-million-images-public-domain-180974263/">the institution announced last week</a>. The new platform includes “data and material from all 19 Smithsonian museums, nine research centers, libraries, archives and the National Zoo”; the records are <a href="https://www.si.edu/openaccess/devtools">accessible via an API</a>, and the metadata is also <a href="https://github.com/Smithsonian/OpenAccess">available on GitHub</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08595">KaoKore</a>, a <a href="https://github.com/rois-codh/kaokore">dataset of 5,552 face images</a> cropped from Japanese artworks at several (non-Smithsonian) institutions. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/EPetenko/status/1232687035237961729">Erin Petenko</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/corintxt">Corin Faife</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>London grocery purchases.</strong> “We present the Tesco Grocery 1.0 dataset: a record of 420 M food items purchased by 1.6 M fidelity card owners who shopped at the 411 Tesco stores in Greater London over the course of the entire year of 2015, aggregated at the level of census areas to preserve anonymity,” researchers announced in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0397-7">a recent academic paper</a>. For each area, <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/Area-level_grocery_purchases/7796666">the dataset</a> contains “the number of transactions and nutritional properties [...] including the average caloric intake and the composition of nutrients.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/lajello/status/1230447728708243456">Luca Maria Aiello</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bug splats.</strong> Danish zoologist Anders Pape Møller <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ece3.5236">counted the number of insects</a> killed on the windscreen of a single car after each of 1,375 journeys along the same stretch of road between 1997 and 2017. After accounting for time of day, weather, and other factors, Møller says <a href="https://datadryad.org/stash/dataset/doi:10.5061/dryad.gq73493">his data</a> suggests an 80% decline in flying insects during that time. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/feb/12/car-splatometer-tests-reveal-huge-decline-number-insects">The Guardian on two bug-splat studies, including Møller’s</a>. [h/t <a href="https://cds.nyu.edu/communitynewsletter/">Laura Norén and Brad Stenger</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send splattered feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dip-2020-03-04</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
