<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</id>
  <title>Data Is Plural</title>
  <updated>2020-08-12T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Singer-Vine</name>
    <email>jsvine@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-08-12</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.12 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-08-12T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus humanitarian funding.</strong> The <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/">Centre for Disaster Protection</a> and <a href="https://devinit.org/">Development Initiatives</a> have been jointly compiling <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/funding-covid-19-response">data</a> on the <a href="https://www.disasterprotection.org/latest-news/funding-covid-19-response-tracking-global-humanitarian-and-development-flows-to-meet-crisis-needs">billions of dollars of humanitarian and development aid</a> that the IMF, World Bank, and other agencies have allocated in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. For each “flow” of funds, the dataset specifies the funding source, amount, approval date, purpose, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: The UN’s provides a <a href="https://pfbi.unocha.org/COVID19/">downloadable and explorable dataset</a> of its coronavirus–related humanitarian funding, and <a href="https://centre.humdata.org/covid-19-map-explorer-whats-included-and-how-we-built-it/">has built</a> an <a href="https://data.humdata.org/visualization/covid19-humanitarian-operations/">interactive map based on these and related datasets</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US climate change.</strong> On Friday, the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2020/08/07/how-use-posts-climate-data-analysis/">released</a> several <a href="https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-2C-beyond-the-limit-usa/">datasets and computer scripts</a> from its <a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/staff-washington-post">Pulitzer Prize–winning</a> series, “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/climate-environment/climate-change-america/">2°C: Beyond the Limit</a>,” which examined how “extreme climate change has arrived in America.” The data files — derived from NOAA’s <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00005">nClimDiv</a> and <a href="https://data.nodc.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/iso?id=gov.noaa.ncdc:C00332">nClimGrid</a> climate datasets — contain the annual average temperatures and seasonal temperature changes for each state and county in the contiguous US.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>International banking statistics.</strong> The <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/index.htm">Bank for International Settlements</a>, established in 1930 and run by <a href="https://www.bis.org/about/member_cb.htm">a group of central banks</a>, publishes a <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/index.htm">range of statistical datasets</a> “designed to inform analysis of financial stability, international monetary spillovers and global liquidity.” The datasets are available to <a href="https://stats.bis.org/statx/toc/LBS.html">explore online</a> and to <a href="https://www.bis.org/statistics/full_data_sets.htm">download</a>; they cover exchange rates, cross-border liabilities, consumer prices, debt service ratios, and more. [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/a09133e2c4343415c6d6cbdc81f88da3748265a5">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electric vehicle charging.</strong> A team led by public policy professor <a href="https://spp.gatech.edu/people/person/omar-isaac-asensio">Omar Asensio</a> used a field experiment to collect <a href="https://github.com/asensio-lab/workplace-charging-experiment">data on 3,395 electric vehicle charging sessions</a>. The <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/NFPQLW">dataset</a> “contains sessions from 85 EV drivers with repeat usage at 105 stations across 25 sites at a workplace charging program”; it indicates the date and length of each session, total energy used, cost, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>44 million Reddit votes.</strong> On Reddit, users can choose to publicize their history of upvoting and downvoting other users’ posts. Software engineer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joey-leake-83229b1/">Joey Leake</a> recently <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/hzdkbp/a_huge_collection_of_reddit_voting_data/">collected</a> and <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/josephleake/huge-collection-of-reddit-votes/">published</a> data on more than 44 million of these votes. For each, Leake’s dataset lists the post ID, relevant subreddit, the vote’s timestamp (in most cases), and the voter’s username.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send thumbs-up/down feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-12-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Coronavirus humanitarian funding, US climate change, international banking statistics, electric vehicle charging, and 44 million Reddit votes.</summary>
    <published>2020-08-12T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-08-05</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.08.05 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-08-05T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cabinet members.</strong> <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/">WhoGov</a>, a new project <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/people/">led by two graduate students at Oxford</a>, provides “bibliographic information, such as gender and party affiliation, on cabinet members in July every year in the period 1966-2016 in all countries with a population of more than 400,000 citizens.” In all, <a href="https://www.nuffield.ox.ac.uk/our-research/research-centres/nuffield-politics-research-centre/whogov/download-dataset/">the dataset</a> covers more than 50,000 officials and “makes it possible to answer questions such as; what is the share of female cabinet members globally, which type of regime has the highest cabinet turnover, and have cabinets increased in size over time?” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/YJuliaJung/status/1285598237068582912">Yujin Julia Jung</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/MaxGroemping/status/1285641311677231106">Max Grömping</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Values and beliefs.</strong> The <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSContents.jsp">World Values Survey</a>, first fielded in 1981, “is the largest non-commercial, cross-national, time series investigation of human beliefs and values ever executed, currently including interviews with almost 400,000 respondents.” Last month, the project <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSEventsShow.jsp?ID=413">began releasing</a> data <a href="http://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSDocumentationWV7.jsp">from its seventh wave of interviews</a>, conducted in 77 countries and covering hundreds of questions about religion, migration, stereotypes, trust, and more. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/howlettm/status/1285279256906395648">Michael Howlett</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/SethJMeyer/status/1287439947209879552">Seth J. Meyer</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Software supply chain attacks.</strong> <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/breaking-trust-shades-of-crisis-across-an-insecure-software-supply-chain/">Breaking Trust</a>, a new project from the <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/">Atlantic Council</a>, provides <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/resources/breaking-trust-the-dataset/">a dataset</a> of 115 “software supply chain” attacks and disclosures in the past decaude. These vulnerabilities occur “when an attacker accesses and edits software somewhere in the complex software development supply chain to compromise a target farther up the chain by inserting their own malicious code.” The dataset’s examples include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuxnet">Stuxnet</a>, <a href="https://threatpost.com/500-malicious-chrome-extensions-millions/152918/">malicious browswer extensions</a>, and various attacks on software package registries. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/MayaKaczorowski/status/1288231258422575105">Maya Kaczorowski</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/LilyZimeng/status/1290331849928118272">Lily Liu</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Animals with SARS-CoV-2.</strong> The USDA has been <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/sa_one_health/sars-cov-2-animals-us">publishing basic information</a> about animals that its <a href="https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/lab-info-services/sa_about_nvsl/ct_about_nvsl">National Veterinary Services Laboratories</a> have confirmed contracted the novel coronvirus. The simple table — unavailable to download, but easy enough to copy-paste into a spreadsheet — lists the types of animals (mostly “Cat” and “Dog,” but also a lion and a tiger), the states they lived in, the dates confirmed, and the methods of diagnosis.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A lot of CAD sketches.</strong> <a href="https://github.com/PrincetonLIPS/SketchGraphs/">SketchGraphs</a> characterizes 15 million computer-aided design (CAD) sketches, “extracted from real-world CAD models” and obtained from a popular online CAD platform. Each of the dataset’s sketches “is represented as a geometric constraint graph where edges denote designer-imposed geometric relationships between primitives, the nodes of the graph.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send impactful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-08-05-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Cabinet members, the World Values Survey, software supply chain attacks, animals with SARS-CoV-2, and 15 million CAD sketches.</summary>
    <published>2020-08-05T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-07-29</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.29 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-07-29T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>COVID-19 vaccines and treatments, NYPD officer misconduct, thousands of political polls, territorial self-governance, and meteorite landings.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 treatments and vaccines.</strong> The Milken Institute’s <a href="https://milkeninstitute.org/centers/fastercures">FasterCures project</a> is tracking <a href="https://covid-19tracker.milkeninstitute.org/">hundreds of potential COVID-19 treatments and vaccines</a>. For each candidate, <a href="https://airtable.com/shrSAi6t5WFwqo3GM/tblEzPQS5fnc0FHYR/viweyymxOAtNvo7yH?blocks=bipZFzhJ7wHPv7x9z">the project’s database</a> lists its category (e.g., DNA-based vaccines, cell-based therapies, et cetera), a brief description, its stage of development, “anticipated next steps,” funders, and more. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.covid-19vaccinetracker.org/">The project’s interactive graphic exploring the vaccines</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>NYPD officer misconduct.</strong> ProPublica <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/nypd-civilian-complaint-review-board-editors-note">has published</a> a dataset of <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nypd-ccrb/">more than 12,000 civilian complaints against nearly 4,000 NYPD officers</a>. The reporters obtained <a href="https://www.propublica.org/datastore/dataset/civilian-complaints-against-new-york-city-police-officers">the data</a> through a freedom-of-information request to New York City’s Civilian Complaint Review Board, after state lawmakers overturned a decades-old statute that had shielded the records. ProPublica’s database “lists the name of each officer, the race of the complainant and the officer, a category describing the alleged misconduct, and whether the CCRB concluded the officers’ conduct violated NYPD rules.” <strong>Related</strong>: In 2018, my colleagues <a href="https://twitter.com/KendallTTaggart">Kendall Taggart</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/michaelhayes">Mike Hayes</a> obtained <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/nypd-police-misconduct-database">thousands of NYPD disciplinary records</a> from a source who requested anonymity — <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/nypd-police-misconduct-database-explainer">giving the public access to this closely-guarded information for the first time</a> and demonstrating how the department had <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/kendalltaggart/secret-nypd-files-hundreds-of-officers-committed-serious">let hundreds of officers keep their jobs after committing fireable offenses</a>. (Soon after, the NYPD <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/mikehayes/nypd-disciplinary-review-board-created">announced an independent panel</a> to review its disciplinary program.) [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JanWillemTulp">Jan Willem Tulp</a> + <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ed-vine-a480347">Ed Vine</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>US political polls.</strong> FiveThirtyEight’s frequently-updated <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/">polling database</a> provides results from thousands of polls (and hundreds of pollsters) on the current presidential, congressional, and gubernatorial elections. Those datasets — plus historical polling averages for presidential elections since 1980 — are <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/data/tree/master/polls">available to download</a>. The files list each poll’s sample size, methods, timeframe, <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/pollster-ratings/">FiveThirtyEight pollster rating</a>, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Territorial self-governance.</strong> <a href="https://www.uni-heidelberg.de/politikwissenschaften/personal/croissant/trinn_en.html">Christoph Trinn</a> and <a href="https://www.uni-heidelberg.de/politikwissenschaften/personal/croissant/schulte_en.html">Felix Schulte</a>’s <a href="https://territorial-governance.com/">TERRGO</a> dataset presents “a fresh look at territorial self-governance in more than 2,200 second-level regions in 96 Western and non-Western democracies, semi-democracies, and a selection of autocratic regimes between 2000 and 2018.” For each region (for instance, Guam or Greenland), TERRGO provides several self-governance metrics, such as whether the national constitution protects the its status and to what degree it can set taxes.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Meteorite landings.</strong> <a href="https://meteoritical.org/">The Meteoritical Society</a>’s <a href="https://www.lpi.usra.edu/meteor/">Meteoritical Bulletin Database</a> “is a clearinghouse for <em>basic</em> information about each meteorite, including the classification, place and year of discovery, whether if was observed to fall, references to catalogues in which the meteorite is described, and known synonyms that may be encountered in the literature.” The society doesn’t provide an easy way to download the full database, but NASA’s open data portal hosts a key slice of it — <a href="https://data.nasa.gov/Space-Science/Meteorite-Landings/gh4g-9sfh">45,000+ landings recorded through mid-2013</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/CraigTaylorViz">Craig Taylor</a>’s <a href="https://twitter.com/CraigTaylorViz/status/1287007372053970945">animated, 3-D rendering of the data</a>. [h/t EwanP]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send impactful feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-29-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>COVID-19 vaccines and treatments, NYPD officer misconduct, thousands of political polls, territorial self-governance, and meteorite landings.</summary>
    <published>2020-07-29T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-07-22</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.22 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-07-22T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Police surveillance tech, COVID-related behavior, the Mexican Migration Project, the Arctic seafloor, and the Big Mac Index.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police surveillance tech.</strong> The <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/">Atlas of Surveillance</a>, a new project from the <a href="https://www.eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation</a>, documents various types of surveillance technology used by 3,500 law enforcement agencies around the US. The <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/search">5,300 data-points</a>, <a href="https://atlasofsurveillance.org/methodology">crowdsourced with the help of hundreds of students and volunteers</a>, cover a dozen categories of technology, such as automated license plate readers, facial recognition systems, and partnerships with doorbell camera–companies. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23824845">anigbrowl</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-related behavior.</strong> Since early April, Imperial College London and YouGov have been <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/global-health-innovation/our-research/covid-19-response/covid-19-behaviour-tracker/">surveying people in 29 countries</a> about their coronavirus-related behaviors and opinions. Topics include mask usage, self-isolation, working from home, vaccinations, and economic activity; the 230,000+ (anonymized) responses <a href="https://github.com/YouGov-Data/covid-19-tracker">are available to download</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AkinUnver/status/1282815737288183810">Akin Unver</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mexican migration to the US.</strong> The <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/">Mexican Migration Project</a> “was created in 1982 by an interdisciplinary team of researchers to further our understanding of the complex process of Mexican migration to the United States.” Since then, the project — co-directed by professors at the University of Guadalajara and Princeton University — has interviewed <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/dataoverview-en.aspx">more than 176,000 people</a> from <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/research/maps-en.aspx">170 communities in Mexico</a>, some who migrated and others who did not. <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/instructions-en.aspx">The datasets</a> (registration required) record <a href="https://mmp.opr.princeton.edu/databases/codebooks-en.aspx">various facets of their lives and migrations</a>: demographic, health, and economic attributes; migration timings, circumstances, and destinations; community characteristics; and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w26790">Brian K. Kovak and Rebecca Lessem</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Arctic seafloor.</strong> The <a href="https://www.gebco.net/about_us/overview/">General Bathymetric Chart of the Ocean</a> project <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-0520-9">has published</a> a new version of <a href="https://www.gebco.net/data_and_products/gridded_bathymetry_data/arctic_ocean/">its Arctic Ocean depth chart</a>, which was first released in 1997 and last updated in 2012. The latest dataset incorporates new sources, has “more than twice the resolution” as the previous version, and is more precise. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://nsidc.org/data/seaice_index/">Arctic (and Antarctic) ice coverage</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-09-14-edition">DIP 2016.09.14</a>), <a href="https://twitter.com/paldhous/status/1283049748614848528">which is hitting year-over-year lows</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Big Mac Index.</strong> The Economist’s <a href="https://www.economist.com/news/2020/07/15/the-big-mac-index">Big Mac Index</a>, which the magazine invented in 1986, compares the cost of the signature McDonald’s hamburger around the world. “Burgernomics was never intended as a precise gauge of currency misalignment, merely a tool to make exchange-rate theory more digestible,” it says. “Yet the Big Mac index has become a global standard, included in several economic textbooks and the subject of dozens of academic studies.” The index is updated twice a year (including last week) and now covers 55 countries; both the data (going back to April 2000) and calculation code are <a href="https://github.com/TheEconomist/big-mac-data">available to download</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send double-patty feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-22-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Police surveillance tech, COVID-related behavior, the Mexican Migration Project, the Arctic seafloor, and the Big Mac Index.</summary>
    <published>2020-07-22T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-07-15</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.15 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-07-15T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>1.75 million US COVID patients, more goverment responses to the coronavirus, COVID cases in migrant worker dorms, 43 million court case citations, and old British lighthouses.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>1.75 million US COVID patients.</strong> The US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has published a <a href="https://data.cdc.gov/Case-Surveillance/COVID-19-Case-Surveillance-Public-Use-Data/vbim-akqf">dataset containing demographic and medical information on 1.75 million deidentified COVID-19 patients</a>. For each confirmed or probable case, the dataset report reports the patient’s age group and race/ethnicity, the date of their initial symptoms, whether they were hospitalized, whether they had an “underlying morbidity or disease,” and more — although several of the fields contain high percentages of “unknown” values. The dataset is similar to the one The New York Times got from the CDC <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/08/podcasts/the-daily/coronavirus-data-united-states.html">through a Freedom of Information Act lawsuit</a> (see: “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/07/05/us/coronavirus-latinos-african-americans-cdc-data.html">The Fullest Look Yet at the Racial Inequity of Coronavirus</a>”), but it does not specify the patient’s county. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/zorinaq/status/1282139606905786369">Marc Bevand</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/stevenmosher/status/1282136596628688896">Steven Mosher</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More government responses to the coronavirus.</strong> The <a href="https://www.coronanet-project.org/">CoronaNet Research Project</a> aims “to collect as much information as we can about the various fine-grained actions governments are taking to defeat the coronavirus.” The project, which has drawn contributions from more than 400 researchers around the world, published its <a href="https://www.coronanet-project.org/download.html">initial release</a> a few weeks ago, and now details nearly 16,000 policy events in nearly 200 countries. <strong>Related</strong>: The nonprofit <a href="https://www.hikmahealth.org/">Hikma Health</a> says <a href="https://www.hikmahealth.org/map">it has compiled</a> “the largest county-level COVID-19 policy dataset in the nation,” covering 1,200 US counties and more than 120 Native American communities. <a href="https://github.com/hikmahealth/covid19countymap/tree/gh-pages">The dataset</a> indicates the dates on which each jurisdiction undertook various responses, such as closing schools and restricting large gatherings. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexPashanov/status/1275441552324612102">Alex Pashanov</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID cases in migrant worker dorms.</strong> The anonymous author of <a href="https://squirrellingdata.wixsite.com/home/">Squirrelling Data</a> has been <a href="https://squirrellingdata.wixsite.com/home/post/singapore-covid-19-data">collating information</a> from the Singapore Ministry of Health’s <a href="https://www.moh.gov.sg/news-highlights/">coronavirus press releases</a>. Among the datasets: <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1NcoRQkvlPTiXh1_CWtjQFyyGXNTY5enbRPNLf4cHuhc/edit#gid=0">daily case counts in dozens of migrant worker dormitories</a>, which <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/23/singapore-million-migrant-workers-suffer-as-covid-19-surges-back">have been hit hard</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.josesho.com/">Joses Ho</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Case citations.</strong> The <a href="https://case.law/about/">Caselaw Access Project</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2018-11-07-edition">DIP 2018.11.07</a>) has begun publishing a <a href="https://case.law/download/citation_graph/">citation graph</a>, a dataset listing the previous cases that each court decision cites. The <a href="https://case.law/download/citation_graph/2020-05-08/">latest release</a> covers 43 million citations. The project also provides aggregated versions of the data, plus <a href="https://case.law/exhibits/cite-grid">interactive graphics</a> showing the frequency of citations to and from courts in each state.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Old British lighthouses.</strong> The <a href="https://reshare.ukdataservice.ac.uk/854172/">Historical Light Aids to Navigation</a> dataset “shows the development of historical lighthouses, lightships, harbour lights and beacons in England and Wales for several benchmark years between 1514-1911,” <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340920308854">drawn from</a> navigational charts, government publications, and other sources. For each of the 600+ entries, the dataset provides the light aid’s name, geocoordinates, and (when available) its visibility range, height, and number of lights.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send illuminating feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-15-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>1.75 million US COVID patients, more goverment responses to the coronavirus, COVID cases in migrant worker dorms, 43 million court case citations, and old British lighthouses.</summary>
    <published>2020-07-15T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-07-08</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.08 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-07-08T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>The Paycheck Protection Program, women in office, programmer surveys, UK land parcels, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Paycheck Protection Program.</strong> On Monday, the US Treasury Department and Small Business Administration <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm1052">released detailed data</a> on the financial assistance given to businesses through the government’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paycheck_Protection_Program">Paycheck Protection Program</a>. For the 660,000+ loans of at least $150,000, <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/cares-act/assistance-for-small-businesses/sba-paycheck-protection-program-loan-level-data">the dataset</a> includes each recipient’s name, address, industry classification, and business type, plus the name of lender, the number of jobs the business said would be supported, loan amount (grouped into several ranges), and more. For aid less than $150,000, the dataset contains similar information, but without names or addresses. <strong>Related</strong>: Efforts to make the data more accessible are already underway. <a href="https://simonwillison.net">Simon Willison</a>, for instance, <a href="https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1280283053726691329">generated</a> a <a href="https://sba-loans-covid-19.datasettes.com/loans_150k_plus/foia_150k_plus">searchable database of all loans of $150,000+</a>, and The Washington Post has published an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/business/sba-ppp-data/">interactive database of the $1,000,000+ loans</a>. <strong>Also related</strong>: <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/07/06/ppp-small-business-coroniavirus-loan-database-contains-errors.html">There are some errors in the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Women in office.</strong> Rutgers University’s <a href="https://cawp.rutgers.edu">Center for American Women and Politics</a> has made public its <a href="https://cawpdata.rutgers.edu">Women Elected Officials Database</a>, which “represents the most complete collection of information anywhere in the world about women elected officials in the United States.” It covers all “women who have held office at the congressional, statewide elected executive, and state legislative levels nationwide,” going back to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_J._Eisenhuth">the 1890s</a>. For each of the 11,540 officeholders, “the database includes their geographic information, party identification, and race identification where available.” You can <a href="https://cawpdata.rutgers.edu/women-elected-officials">explore the data online</a> and also (with a free registration) download it. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/CFPBRI">Women candidates for the US House, 1972–2010</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-07-26-edition">DIP 2017.07.26</a>) .</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Programmer surveys.</strong> For the past decade, programming Q&amp;A site <a href="https://stackoverflow.com">StackOverflow</a> has run an annual survey, asking developers about the languages they use, their workplaces, learning goals, salaries, and more. The site provides <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/">anonymized, respondent-level data</a> for each survey, including the 2020 edition, which received 64,000+ responses. Between 2016 and 2018, the not-for-profit <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org">FreeCodeCamp</a> ran an <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-2018-new-coder-survey-31-000-people-told-us-how-theyre-learning-to-code-and-getting-dev-jobs-e10feb9ed419/">annual “new coder” survey</a>, which attracted more than 31,000 responses in its most recent year; those datasets are also <a href="https://github.com/freeCodeCamp?q=new-coder-survey">available to download</a>. [h/t <a href="https://nakeddata.org/2020/06/12/the-most-loved-and-dreaded-computing-languages/">Jason Norwood-Young</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>UK land parcels.</strong> Last week, the UK <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/inspire-data-to-be-shared-under-open-terms">expanded access</a> to its <a href="https://use-land-property-data.service.gov.uk/datasets/inspire">datasets defining the geographical boundaries</a> of 23 million “title extents” in England, Wales, and <a href="https://ros.locationcentre.co.uk/inspire/">Scotland</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/price-paid-data">UK property sales</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-03-23-edition">DIP 2016.03.23</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</strong> Microsoft researchers <a href="https://twitter.com/rev_rameshkumar">Revanth Rameshkumar</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/peter_r_bailey">Peter Bailey</a> have assembled the <a href="https://github.com/RevanthRameshkumar/CRD3">Critical Role Dungeons and Dragons Dataset</a>, converting 159 transcripts of <a href="https://critrole.com">a popular, live-streamed role-playing show</a> into structured information about 398,682 bits of dialogue. [h/t <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:arnicas/">Lynn Cherny</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send monstrous feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-08-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Paycheck Protection Program, women in office, programmer surveys, UK land parcels, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons dialogue.</summary>
    <published>2020-07-08T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-07-01</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.07.01 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-07-01T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>The coronavirus economy, early voting registrations, COVID clusters, subway accessibility, and twelve men using computers.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The coronavirus economy.</strong> Opportunity Insights’ <a href="https://tracktherecovery.org/">Economic Tracker</a> “combines anonymized data from leading private companies – from credit card processors to payroll firms – to provide a real-time picture of indicators such as employment rates, consumer spending, and job postings across counties, industries, and income groups.” Small business revenue, for instance, appears to be down about 55% in Boston, compared to the beginning of the year. The <a href="https://github.com/Opportunitylab/EconomicTracker">project’s GitHub page</a> provides aggregated data corresponding to each of the charts and graphs. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://opportunityinsights.org/data/">Opportunity Insights’ extensive datasets on economic mobility</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-06-12-edition">DIP 2019.06.12</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/matteoferroni93/status/1273312600793714689">Matteo Ferroni</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/DanStein_econ/status/1273301012091035648">Dan Stein</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Voter registration.</strong> At least three states publish monthly, machine-readable statistics on new voter registrations: <a href="https://dos.myflorida.com/elections/data-statistics/voter-registration-statistics/voter-registration-reportsxlsx/">Florida</a>, <a href="https://www.elections.virginia.gov/resultsreports/registration-statistics/">Virginia</a>, and <a href="https://dl.ncsbe.gov/?prefix=data/voterstats/">North Carolina</a>. <a href="https://elections.maryland.gov/voter_registration/stats.html">Maryland</a> and the <a href="https://www.dcboe.org/Data-Resources-Forms/Voter-Registration-Stats">District of Columbia</a> publish similar data as PDF tables. A <a href="https://electioninnovation.org/new-voter-registrations-in-2020/">recent report</a> by <a href="https://electioninnovation.org/">Center for Election Innovation &amp; Research</a> analyzed pandemic-era registrations, using that data plus numbers obtained from Arizona, California, Colorado, Delaware, Georgia, Illinois, and Texas. The analysis found a “steep decline in new registrations,” largely attributable to social distancing measures and DMV closures. To accompany <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/voter-registrations-are-way-way-down-during-the-pandemic/">an article on the topic</a>, FiveThirtyEight has compiled CEIR’s counts for those 12 states, for the first five months of 2016 and 2020, <a href="https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/data/tree/master/voter-registration">into a simple CSV</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID clusters.</strong> A <a href="https://wellcomeopenresearch.org/articles/5-83">team of researchers in the UK</a> has been gathering <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/16wtnHe4hM6I7TFHXVpLXY8R4GAUzAJ-7NWbKIVvsVuA/edit">data on COVID-19 “transmission events”</a> that have resulted in clusters of cases, based on various official, scholarly, and news reports. For each of the 250+ events listed so far, the dataset specifies the setting (e.g., “work,” “household,” “religious,” “elderly care”), whether it was indoors or outdoors, geographical location, number of cases involved, and more. The New York Times has also been tracking <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/us/coronavirus-us-cases.html#clusters">the location and size of COVID-19 clusters in the US</a> — so far, more than 1,700 clusters with at least 50 cases. The NYT doesn’t provide a download button, but its webpage loads the data from a JSON file. [h/t <a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2020/05/why-do-some-covid-19-patients-infect-many-others-whereas-most-don-t-spread-virus-all">Kai Kupferschmidt</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Subway accessibility.</strong> <a href="https://medium.com/dataclinic/open-tools-to-analyze-accessibility-within-the-nyc-subway-system-383fb111b4ad">To better understand accessibility issues</a> in the NYC subway, the <a href="https://dataclinic.twosigma.com/">Two Sigma Data Clinic</a> has <a href="https://github.com/tsdataclinic/mta">constructed</a> a series of <a href="https://github.com/tsdataclinic/mta/tree/master/data/processed/stationgraph">datasets</a> and <a href="https://github.com/tsdataclinic/mta/tree/master/figures/elevator_maps">diagrams</a> describing each station’s elevator connections — from the street to the station, and between various points and platforms within it. <strong>Related</strong>: The subway system’s <a href="http://advisory.mtanyct.info/eedevwebsvc/allequipments.aspx">official list of elevators and escalators</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: Turnstile data from <a href="http://web.mta.info/developers/turnstile.html">NYC</a> and <a href="https://data.cityofchicago.org/Transportation/CTA-Ridership-L-Station-Entries-Daily-Totals/5neh-572f">Chicago</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2017-02-08-edition">DIP 2017.02.08</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/eeeestein/status/1271539959632211971">Erin Stein</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Humans using computers.</strong> <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340920306612">BEHACOM</a> is a <a href="https://data.mendeley.com/datasets/cg4br62535/2">dataset</a> that details minute-by-minute usage statistics for 12 Spanish and Italian men “interacting for fifty-five consecutive days with their personal computers in their own way and without restrictions.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send keyboard-and-mousey feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-01-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The coronavirus economy, early voting registrations, COVID clusters, subway accessibility, and twelve men using computers.</summary>
    <published>2020-07-01T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-06-24</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.06.24 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-06-24T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>New policing bills, Indigenous lands, The Gay Guides, coronavirus-era child care, and Ancient Rome.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>New policing bills.</strong> The <a href="https://www.ncsl.org">National Conference of State Legislatures</a> has built a <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/civil-and-criminal-justice/legislative-responses-for-policing.aspx">database of state-level policing bills and executive orders</a> introduced since May 25, the day George Floyd was killed. The database covers proposed bills on “oversight and data, training, standards and certification, use of force, technology, policing alternatives and collaboration, [...] and other timely issues.” So far, it contains brief descriptions, author information, statuses, and last-activity dates for more than 250 pieces of legislation in 25 states and DC. Although the database does not provide downloads, its HTML output is highly structured. <strong>Related</strong>: Last week, The Marshall Project’s <a href="https://twitter.com/Weihua_Li1">Weihua Li</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/HumeraLodhi">Humera Lodhi</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/sharmad23">Damini Sharma</a> <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/06/18/which-states-are-taking-on-police-reform-after-george-floyd">analyzed the database and put the bills in context</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Indigenous lands.</strong> <a href="https://native-land.ca/">Native-Land.ca</a> maps the historical geographic extents of Indigenous territories in North America, Australia, New Zealand, parts of South America, and elsewhere. The <a href="https://native-land.ca/api-docs/">project’s datasets</a> cover 1,400+ territories, 900+ languages, and 800+ related treaties, drawn from <a href="https://native-land.ca/resources/">a wide range of resources</a>. It was launched in 2015 by programmer <a href="http://victortemprano.com">Victor Temprano</a> and is <a href="https://native-land.ca/about/">now run by a not-for-profit organization with a board of directors</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: Earlier this year, High Country News published <a href="https://www.landgrabu.org">Land-Grab Universities</a>, a “two-year inquiry into the origin of wealth that undergirds the nation’s system of higher education,” accompanied by a <a href="https://www.hcn.org/articles/indigenous-affairs-education-how-we-investigated-the-land-grant-university-system">detailed methodology</a> and <a href="https://github.com/HCN-Digital-Projects/landgrabu-data">dataset</a> spanning nearly 11 million acres of expropriated Indigenous land.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Gay Guides.</strong> <a href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org">Mapping the Gay Guides</a> “aims to understand often ignored queer geographies using the Damron Address Books, an early but longstanding travel guide aimed at gay men since the early 1960s.” The project — <a href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/2020/02/announcing-the-launch-of-mapping-the-gay-guides/">launched earlier this year</a> and <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/about/">led by</a> historians <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/regan/">Amanda Regan</a> and <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/gonzaba/">Eric Gonzaba</a> — includes an <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/map/">interactive map</a>, <a href="https://github.com/MappingtheGayGuides/MGG-Data">downloadable dataset</a>, <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/methodology/">methodology</a>, and <a href="https://mappingthegayguides.org/ethics/">ethics statement</a>. It already covers more than 22,000 entries in more than 30 states, with plans for further expansion. [h/t <a href="https://mailchi.mp/42557319b05d/preview-222-in-other-news-3837485">Giuseppe Sollazzo</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Coronavirus-era child care.</strong> Economist and parenting book–author <a href="https://emilyoster.net/">Emily Oster</a> has been <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeYIy0Dc9PW9sWCSWNXypw36FLoMiSx9jDalgDPcccK4T7ezQ/viewform">collecting</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ProfEmilyOster/status/1275044876133044225">publishing</a> “preliminary, unscientific data on child care centers which were open in the pandemic.” The <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1L45r63t8hpYfGLpT6gWKjYMscu8Wut6jtlxO-1FAW9c/edit">dataset</a> currently includes more than 900 centers, their locations, age ranges served, whether they were open the whole time or just part of it, the number of students and staff, and the number of COVID-19 cases in students and staff. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/LauraALibby/status/1274084844817940480">Laura Libby</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>These datasets lead to Rome.</strong> The <a href="https://darmc.harvard.edu/">Digital Atlas of Roman and Medieval Civilizations</a> at Harvard University “makes freely available on the internet the best available materials for [...] mapping and spatial analysis of the Roman and medieval worlds.” The project’s <a href="https://darmc.harvard.edu/data-availability">datasets</a> include economic indicators, climate records, ports and harbors, shipwrecks, roads, and more. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/h0702y/has_anyone_put_together_a_document_listing_all/">Pier Rolla</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send ancient feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-06-24-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>New policing bills, Indigenous lands, The Gay Guides, coronavirus-era child care, and Ancient Rome.</summary>
    <published>2020-06-24T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-06-17</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.06.17 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-06-17T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Confederate monuments, more protest data, the Green Books, sentences for measuring bias, and a few hundred penguins.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Confederate monuments.</strong> For several years, the <a href="https://www.splcenter.org/">Southern Poverty Law Center</a>’s “<a href="https://www.splcenter.org/data-projects/whose-heritage">Whose Heritage?</a>” project has been gathering and mapping information on “<a href="https://www.splcenter.org/20190201/whose-heritage-public-symbols-confederacy">public symbols of the Confederacy</a>,” such as monuments, place names, official holidays, commemorative license plates, and municipal seals. For each of the 1,800+ entries, the project’s <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/17ps4aqRyaIfpu7KdGsy2HRZaaQiXUfLrpUbaR9yS51E/edit">dataset</a> indicates the type of monument/symbol, its location, sponsor, year dedicated, and (if applicable) year removed. [h/t <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/wxqnjy/is-there-a-racist-monument-in-your-town-check-this-map-to-find-out">Gita Jackson</a> + <a href="https://danjbrady.com">Dan Brady</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More protest data.</strong> <a href="https://countlove.org/">CountLove.org</a> has been using news reports to quantify protest events in the US since 2017. Its <a href="https://countlove.org/faq.html">downloadable dataset</a> currently contains more than 27,000 events and provides each event’s date, location, and approximate number of attendees. The events are also tagged with one or more topics, such as <em>civil rights</em>, <em>healthcare,</em> <em>for racial justice</em>, and <em>against regulation</em>. The site’s <a href="https://countlove.org/search.html">search/mapping tool</a> lets you to filter by those tags, and also for “curated protest data for a more compassionate country.” <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.tommyleung.com/about.htm">Tommy Leung</a> and <a href="https://www.nathanntg.com/">Nathan Perkins</a> <a href="https://www.tommyleung.com/countLove/index.htm">describe how they built the project</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/abscribe/status/1272169075662376960">Audra Burch et al.</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Green Books.</strong> The New York Public Library has digitized <a href="https://digitalcollections.nypl.org/collections/the-green-book#/?tab=about">more than 20 volumes of the Green Book</a> —  a series of travelers’ guides, <a href="https://www.nypl.org/blog/2015/03/24/schomburg-treasures-green-book">published from the 1930s to 1960s by US postal worker Victor Green</a>, that listed hotels, restaurants, gas stations, and other establishments where Black visitors would be safe and welcome. The library has <a href="https://github.com/NYPL-publicdomain/greenbooks">converted its digital copies into semi-structured text</a> and <a href="https://github.com/NYPL-publicdomain/greenbooks/tree/master/geojson">turned the 1947 edition into a fully-structured dataset</a>. The University of South Carolina has built a <a href="https://digital.library.sc.edu/collections/the-negro-travelers-green-book-1956/">dataset of the 1,500+ listings in the 1956 edition</a>. Inn 2015, NYPL Labs combined both years’ datasets into a <a href="https://publicdomain.nypl.org/greenbook-map/">tool to map the locations and plan routes with them</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Sentences for measuring bias.</strong> <a href="https://stereoset.mit.edu/">StereoSet</a> aims to measure biases toward stereotypes — as they relate to profession, gender, race, and religion — in statistical language models, using <a href="https://github.com/moinnadeem/StereoSet">a dataset containing thousands of sentences</a>, each with several variations. Through the project’s <a href="https://stereoset.mit.edu/explore/dev/">online data explorer</a>, you can examine the sentences and see how some popular language models perform. [h/t <a href="https://www.datainnovation.org/2020/05/measuring-bias-in-natural-language-models/">Michael McLaughlin</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>A few hundred penguins.</strong> Data educator <a href="https://www.allisonhorst.com/">Allison Horst</a> earlier this month <a href="https://twitter.com/allison_horst/status/1270046399418138625">released</a> a <a href="https://github.com/allisonhorst/palmerpenguins/blob/master/data-raw/penguins_raw.csv">dataset describing the physical characteristics of 344 Antarctic penguins</a>, derived from data collected by marine biologist <a href="https://www.uaf.edu/cfos/people/faculty/detail/kristen-gorman.php">Kristen Gorman</a> and the <a href="https://pal.lternet.edu/">Palmer Station</a>. With <a href="https://allisonhorst.github.io/palmerpenguins/">palmerpenguins</a>, Horst aims to provide a data-exploration alternative to the ubiquitous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iris_flower_data_set"><em>iris</em> dataset</a>, which was first published, in 1936, in the Annals of Eugenics. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="http://www.penguinmap.com/mapppd">Thousands of penguins</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-03-11-edition">DIP 2020.03.11</a>). [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/alexcookson/status/1270073380792872962">Alex Cookson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-06-17-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Confederate monuments, more protest data, the Green Books, sentences for measuring bias, and a few hundred penguins.</summary>
    <published>2020-06-17T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-06-10</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.06.10 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-06-10T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Black Lives Matter protests, police violence at the protests, police reforms and union contracts, police militarization, and tech’s response.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Black Lives Matter protests.</strong> An unnamed geospatial analyst <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gis/comments/gx8uoa/mapping_george_floyd_black_lives_matter_protests/">has been mapping</a> “every town or city I can find where a George Floyd / Black Lives Matter protest, action, or vigil has occurred since May 25” — <a href="https://www.creosotemaps.com/blm2020/">more than 2,600 so far</a>. The <a href="https://www.creosotemaps.com/blm2020/json/">data files powering the map</a> include each city’s name, state/region, country, coordinates, and the date it was added. <strong>Related</strong>: For <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/perspectives-on-politics/article/black-lives-matter-evidence-that-policecaused-deaths-predict-protest-activity/BFA2E74F4BCB25C3C222807E8B1111D4/share/53d6d67c798695fc19688bd571777e433fca550d">a study of the relationship between police-caused deaths and demonstrations</a>, Williamson et al. built <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L2GSK6">a dataset of Black Lives Matter protests in 2014 and 2015</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police violence at the BLM protests.</strong> Several groups are collecting examples of disproportionate police responses to the protests against police brutality. <a href="https://watchwatch.org/">One such collection</a>, <a href="https://time.com/5849839/police-brutality-george-floyd-protests-spreadsheet/">spurred by criminal defense attorney T. Greg Doucette</a>, has compiled hundreds of instances of “unnecessary violence by law enforcement officers against civilians”; for each one, the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1YmZeSxpz52qT-10tkCjWOwOGkQqle7Wd1P7ZM1wMW0E/edit">underlying spreadsheet</a> provides the city and state of the incident, links to visual documentation on Twitter and YouTube, and a short description. <a href="https://github.com/2020PB/police-brutality">Another collection</a>, which emerged from the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/2020PoliceBrutality/">/r/2020PoliceBrutality subreddit</a> and seeks “to accumulate and contextualize evidence of police brutality during the 2020 George Floyd protests,” also includes incident dates, an <a href="https://846policebrutality.com/">interactive map</a>, and APIs. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/americas/2020/06/05/visualizing-police-violence-against-journalists-at-protests-across-the-us/">Bellingcat</a> and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2020/jun/05/im-getting-shot-attacks-on-journalists-surge-in-us-protests">The Guardian</a> have compiled <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1F7Q-XoCoHzb_cX28ARCL4BMsuxp3EpkouUDJ2cRSjOQ/edit">a spreadsheet</a> of 140+ “reports of arrests, violence, and intimidation against journalists” at the protests. [h/t <a href="https://anja.kefala.info">anjakefala</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/AricToler/status/1268892644941447168">Aric Toler</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police reforms and union contracts.</strong> <a href="https://www.joincampaignzero.org/">Campaign Zero</a>’s <a href="https://8cantwait.org/">8cantwait.org</a> advocates for eight specific reforms to curtail police officers’ use of force, including bans on chokeholds, requiring de-escalation tactics, and establishing comprehensive reporting. The organization has compiled <a href="https://useofforceproject.org/database">the use of force policies for 100 large police departments</a>, and <a href="https://8cantwait.org/compare/">determined whether they’ve instituted these reforms</a>. (<a href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/campaign-zero-use-of-force/data/force.csv">Direct CSV download here</a>.) And at <a href="https://www.checkthepolice.org/">checkthepolice.org</a>, the organization has gathered <a href="https://www.checkthepolice.org/database">police union contracts</a> in major cities and assessed whether they contain language makes it harder to hold officers accountable for misconduct. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/samswey/status/1180655721052020737">Samuel Sinyangwe</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Police militarization.</strong> The US Defense Logistic Agency’s <a href="https://www.dla.mil/DispositionServices/Offers/Reutilization/LawEnforcement/">Law Enforcement Support Office</a> sends surplus Department of Defense equipment to local law enforcement agencies, through an arrangement known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1033_program">1033 program</a>. The Pentagon publishes <a href="https://www.dla.mil/DispositionServices/Offers/Reutilization/LawEnforcement/PublicInformation/">quarterly updates of the equipment transferred</a> — which can range from coffee makers to rifles to entire aircraft — but only began doing so <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2014/12/03/the-pentagon-finally-details-its-weapons-for-cops-giveaway">after the program came under intense scrutiny</a> for its role in the <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jimdalrympleii/war-zone-in-ferguson-how-billions-in-military-weapons-ended">militarized police response to the 2014 Ferguson protests</a> and police militarization in general. <strong>Related</strong>: Despite the criticisms, the 1033 program has sent police departments hundreds of millions of dollars in military equipment since Ferguson, including more than 490 mine-resistant vehicles, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/johntemplon/police-departments-military-gear-1033-program">my colleague John Templon reports</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Tech’s BLM statements.</strong> <a href="https://tpinsights.com/">The Plug</a>, a news site that focuses on the Black innovation economy, <a href="https://tpinsights.com/2020/05/31/twilio-box-spotify-and-other-tech-ceos-speak-out-against-racism-and-police-brutality-others-stay-silent/">has been assembling</a> a dataset of <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1OZx-_tm3PPyx6-ZJAST1xxOJRfn7KfYDjDT6JedrTfs/edit#gid=0">statements made by tech companies on racial justice, Black Lives Matter, and George Floyd</a>. The dataset links to more than 200 statements so far and includes each company’s name, the timing of the statement, and other relevant context, such as the URL of their most recent diversity report and the percentage of employees and/or leaders who identify as Black. [h/t <a href="https://www.sherrelldorsey.com/">Sherrell Dorsey</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-06-10-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Black Lives Matter protests, police violence at the protests, police reforms and union contracts, police militarization, and tech’s response.</summary>
    <published>2020-06-10T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
