<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural</id>
  <title>Data Is Plural</title>
  <updated>2021-01-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jeremy Singer-Vine</name>
    <email>jsvine@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator>https://github.com/data-is-plural/newsletter-archive</generator>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter of useful/curious datasets.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-01-13</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.01.13 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-01-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Electoral attitudes, fishing activity, Bundestag writings, innovation licensing, and chess puzzles.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Electoral attitudes.</strong> The <a href="https://u.osu.edu/cnep/">Comparative National Elections Project</a> “is a partnership among scholars who have conducted election surveys on five continents,” with a focus on understanding the factors that shape voters’ decisions. The project’s <a href="https://u.osu.edu/cnep/surveys/surveys-through-2012/">publicly-available datasets</a> include 48 of the surveys, which use a combination of country-specific questions and <a href="https://u.osu.edu/cnep/common-core-questionnaire/">shared questionnaire</a> — asking about political news consumption, attitudes towards democracy, interpersonal communications, and other topics. <strong>Related</strong>: The <a href="https://cses.org/">Comparative Study of Electoral Systems</a>, a similar collaboration with “a special emphasis on voting and turnout.” [h/t <a href="https://github.com/erikgahner/PolData/commit/26ff4d1932024d71b29a1195597d5e5a64367cca">Erik Gahner Larsen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Fishing activity.</strong> <a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/">Global Fishing Watch</a> — initially organized as <a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/about-us/">a collaboration</a> between conservationists and Google — uses satellite imagery, ship signals, and other sources “to visualise, track and share data about global fishing activity in near real-time and for free.” The project’s <a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/datasets-and-code/">public datasets</a> (free registration required) examine various aspects of the industry, including the <a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/datasets-and-code/fishing-effort/">geography of “fishing effort”</a> (2012–16) and <a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/transshipment-success/report-first-global-view-transshipment-sea/">transshipment between vessels</a>. <strong>As seen in</strong>: “<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2020-brexit-eu-fisheries/">Why the U.K. and EU Are Fighting Over Fish</a>” (Bloomberg). [h/t <a href="https://flowingdata.com/2020/12/21/who-catches-the-most-fish/">Nathan Yau</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bundestag writings.</strong> Political scientists <a href="https://corinna-kroeber.jimdofree.com/">Corinna Kroeber</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/tremsch">Tobias Remschel</a> have <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/government-and-opposition/article/every-single-word-a-new-data-set-including-all-parliamentary-materials-published-in-germany/34D424C406687F7446C6F32980A4FE84">compiled</a> a <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/7EJ1KI">dataset</a> of “all written communication published by the German Bundestag between 1949 and 2017,” unifying <a href="https://www.bundestag.de/services/opendata">datasets released by Germany’s parliament</a> “in a manner easily accessible to researchers applying text analysis.” For each of the 131,835 reports, requests, bills, and other documents, the dataset provides the full text, date, author information, and more. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/L4OAKN">Six million parliamentary speeches from nine countries</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-04-29-edition">DIP 2020.04.29</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Innovation licensing.</strong> Government agencies often commercialize their innovations through “<a href="https://federallabs.org/learning-center/what-is-t2">technology transfer</a>” programs, which strike collaboration and licensing agreements with outside parties. NASA provides a <a href="https://technology.nasa.gov/api/">technology transfer API</a> for accessing data about its patent portfolio and software catalog; the National Institutes of Health offers a <a href="https://www.ott.nih.gov/nih-ott-api">similar API</a> for querying its licensing opportunities. [h/t <a href="https://alexlib.info/">Tom Folkes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Chess puzzles.</strong> <a href="https://lichess.org/about">Lichess</a> is a free, open-source, donation-supported chess server. Its team publishes a <a href="https://database.lichess.org/">database of the rated matches</a> played on its platform (more than 1.7 billion so far, since 2013), which it recently used <a href="https://lichess.org/blog/X-S6gRUAAGjNX4ki/new-puzzles-are-here">to revamp</a> its <a href="https://database.lichess.org/#puzzles">dataset of original chess puzzles</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="http://www.pgnmentor.com/files.html">Chess games from high-level players and tournaments</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-02-17-edition">DIP 2016.02.17</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send strategic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2021-01-13-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Electoral attitudes, fishing activity, Bundestag writings, innovation licensing, and chess puzzles.</summary>
    <published>2021-01-13T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2021-01-06</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2021.01.06 edition</title>
    <updated>2021-01-06T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Megascale coronavirus surveys, commodity-transportation costs, more college sports financing, ten million Jupyter notebooks, and 2020 in haiku.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Megascale coronavirus surveys.</strong> Carnegie Mellon University’s <a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/about/">epidemiological forecasting group</a> and Facebook have partnered to field a <a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/covidcast/surveys/">large-scale coronavirus survey in the US</a>; they’ve collected <a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/covidcast/survey-results/">more than 15 million responses since April 2020</a>. The University of Maryland has <a href="https://covidmap.umd.edu/">formed a similar partnership</a> for an international survey, in which “a representative sample of Facebook users is invited on a daily basis to report on symptoms, social distancing behavior, mental health issues, and financial constraints”; <a href="https://ischool.umd.edu/news/university-maryland-carnegie-mellon-and-facebook-team-forecast-coronavirus-spread">millions have also participated</a>. Geographically-aggregated results of the US survey can be downloaded via an <a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/covidcast/export/">online interface</a> or <a href="https://cmu-delphi.github.io/delphi-epidata/api/covidcast.html">Delphi’s API</a>; the international results are also <a href="https://covidmap.umd.edu/api.html">available via API</a>. <strong>Practical example</strong>: <a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/blog/2020/12/13/are-masks-widely-used-in-public/">An analysis of state-by-state mask usage, with code</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.refsmmat.com/">Alex Reinhart</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Commodity-transportation costs.</strong> The UN and the World Bank have <a href="https://unctad.org/news/why-and-how-measure-international-transport-costs">launched</a> a new <a href="https://unctadstat.unctad.org/EN/TransportCost.html">interactive map</a> and <a href="https://unctadstat.unctad.org/wds/ReportFolders/reportFolders.aspx?IF_ActivePath=P%2C207045">dataset</a> that quantify the transportation costs for international trade — country-by-country and broken down by mode of transportation (sea, air, rail, road), trading partner, and commodity. The numbers, based both on directly-reported figures and statistical modelling, include costs overall, per unit, and per unit per kilometer. The project currently covers only 2016, but has plans to expand. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JanHoffmann_gva/status/1341414753567186947">Jan Hoffmann</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More college sports financing.</strong> The <a href="http://cafidatabase.knightcommission.org">College Athletics Financial Information Database</a>, run by the privately-funded <a href="https://www.knightcommission.org">Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics</a>, details the annual sources of revenue (such as ticket sales) and expenses (such as coaches’ compensation) for hundreds of schools, based on information self-reported to the NCAA and federal government. Many of the records <a href="http://cafidatabase.knightcommission.org/about-the-data">were obtained</a> via freedom-of-information requests by <a href="https://sports.usatoday.com/2020/07/05/methodology-for-2019-ncaa-athletic-department-revenue-database/">USA Today and Syracuse University students</a>. [h/t <a href="https://www.ipr.northwestern.edu/our-work/working-papers/2020/wp-20-42.html">Craig Garthwaite et al.</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Millions of computational notebooks.</strong> In 2017, a team of researchers <a href="https://github.com/activityhistory/jupyter_on_github">downloaded and analyzed</a> 1.25 million publicly-available Jupyter notebooks — <a href="https://jupyter.org/">documents</a> that weave computational code, output, and text. They also <a href="https://library.ucsd.edu/dc/collection/bb6931851t">published</a> the notebooks and their related metadata. Inspired by that project, a team at JetBrains recently did a follow-up scan, <a href="https://blog.jetbrains.com/datalore/2020/12/17/we-downloaded-10-000-000-jupyter-notebooks-from-github-this-is-what-we-learned/">analyzing and publishing data on nearly 10 million notebooks</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>2020 in haiku.</strong> Over the course of 2020, <a href="https://twitter.com/elibryan">Eli Holder</a> paid workers on Mechanical Turk to turn news headlines into 5/7/5-syllable poems. The result: 2,760 “Doom Haikus,” which you can <a href="https://doomhaikus.3iap.co/">browse on a timeline</a> or <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/newshaikus/dataset">download in bulk</a>. For each poem, the dataset also includes the original article URL, date processed, headline, and SEO snippet. [h/t <a href="http://ksaj.inlisp.org">Karsten Johansson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send journo-poetic feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2021-01-06-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Megascale coronavirus surveys, commodity-transportation costs, more college sports financing, ten million Jupyter notebooks, and 2020 in haiku.</summary>
    <published>2021-01-06T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-12-23</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.12.23 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-12-23T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Vaccine doses, county-level coronavirus tests, social scientists testifying, permafrost, and meat-washing.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Vaccine doses.</strong> <a href="https://ourworldindata.org">Our World in Data</a> is tracking the <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/covid-vaccinations">number of COVID-19 vaccine doses administered</a> per country, compiling <a href="https://github.com/owid/covid-19-data/tree/master/public/data/vaccinations">their dataset</a> from a range of government sources, including <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/departments/news/22122020-01">press releases</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nadhimzahawi/status/1339143635586207744">ministers’ tweets</a>. In addition to <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations">listing the total doses administered</a>, the US Department of Health and Human Services is also <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/coronavirus/covid-19-vaccines/distribution/index.html">publishing datasets</a> that tally how many <a href="https://data.cdc.gov/Vaccinations/COVID-19-Vaccine-Distribution-Allocations-by-Juris/saz5-9hgg">Pfizer-BioNTech</a> and <a href="https://data.cdc.gov/Vaccinations/COVID-19-Vaccine-Distribution-Allocations-by-Juris/b7pe-5nws">Moderna</a> vaccine doses have been <em>allocated</em> and <em>shipped</em> to each state and territory.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>County-level coronavirus tests.</strong> The US federal government has finally begun publishing county-level data on COVID-19 test counts, positivity rates, and delays. And that’s just a slice of <a href="https://github.com/CareSet/COVID_Community_Profile_Report_FAQ">the information now available</a> through the daily-updated, multi-agency <a href="https://beta.healthdata.gov/National/COVID-19-Community-Profile-Report/gqxm-d9w9">Community Profile Reports</a>, which also assign each county to a “concern category” and aggregate the metrics to the CBSA, state, and regional levels. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/rypan/status/1340012957321728001">Ryan Panchadsaram’s enthusiastic Twitter thread</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Social scientists testifying.</strong> In a <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0230104">paper published this spring</a>, Mahler et al. describe their dataset of <a href="https://osf.io/e3h98/">social scientists’ appearances in US congressional hearings</a> — more than 15,000 instances in all, at more than 10,000 hearings between 1946 and 2016. For each testimony, the dataset indicates the expert’s name, discipline, title, and professional affiliations, as well as the hearing’s date, title, and committee. Economists predominate, followed by political scientists, psychologists, sociologists, and then anthropologists. [h/t <a href="https://deblina.net/">Deblina Mukherjee</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Permafrost.</strong> The European Space Agency <a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Observing_the_Earth/Space_for_our_climate/Long-term_permafrost_record_details_Arctic_thaw">has released</a> new <a href="https://catalogue.ceda.ac.uk/uuid/1f88068e86304b0fbd34456115b6606f">longitudinal data on the Northern Hemisphere’s permafrost</a> — ground that remains 0°C/32°F or colder for at least two years. Through a combination of satellite detection and on-the-ground measurements, the datasets quantify the permafrost’s thickness, extent, and temperature between 1997 and 2017. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/simon_sat/status/1339167494720937989">Simon Proud</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Who washes meat?</strong> YouTuber (and former public radio reporter) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/aragusea/about">Adam Ragusea</a> recently <a href="https://youtu.be/U_PMnCpaJiQ?t=742">asked his viewers</a> to answer a detailed survey about whether (and why, and how) they wash meat before cooking it. He received more than 13,000 responses. He then made a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=90Nd_vh3yk8">video about what he found</a> and published a <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1eygYpBJQGFd4wHH8iYsLoy3PR8PmHN0O/view">spreadsheet of the anonymized answers</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send uncontaminated feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-12-23-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Vaccine doses, county-level coronavirus tests, social scientists testifying, permafrost, and meat-washing.</summary>
    <published>2020-12-23T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-12-16</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.12.16 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-12-16T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Enslaved.org, more PPP details, more on travel/immigration bans, Third-Republic France, and cyber wargames.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>People of slavery.</strong> <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/sweeping-new-digital-database-emphasizes-enslaved-peoples-individuality-180976513/">Recently launched</a>, <a href="https://enslaved.org/">Enslaved.org</a> allows the public to “explore or reconstruct the lives of individuals who were enslaved, owned slaves, or participated in the historical trade.” Its interactive database contains 600,000+ records, with plans to expand. The <a href="https://enslaved.org/about">collaborative, schlolar-led project</a> also includes <a href="https://jsdp.enslaved.org/">The Journal of Slavery and Data Preservation</a>, which “publishes original, peer-reviewed datasets about the lives of enslaved Africans and their descendants.” The <a href="https://jsdp.enslaved.org/fullIssue/volume1-issue1">first issue</a> features three datasets <a href="http://slavebiographies.org/databases.php">originally published</a> through a <a href="https://enslaved.org/projectHistory">precursor</a> to Enslaved.org — <a href="http://slavebiographies.org/about.php">Slave Biographies: The Atlantic Database Network</a>. Those <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/jsdp">datasets</a> focus on <a href="https://jsdp.enslaved.org/fullDataArticle/volume1-issue1-louisiana-slave-database">Louisiana slaves</a> (1719–1820), <a href="https://jsdp.enslaved.org/fullDataArticle/volume1-issue1-free-blacks-database">New Orleans “Free Blacks”</a> (1840–1860), and <a href="https://jsdp.enslaved.org/fullDataArticle/volume1-issue1-maranhao-inventories-slave-database">enslaved Africans in Maranhão, Brazil</a> (1767–1831).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More PPP details.</strong> Thanks to a FOIA lawsuit by a group of news organizations, the US Small Business Administration has <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/sba-releases-detailed-information-on-more-small-business-borrowers-under-ppp-pandemic-relief-effort-11606874820">released additional data</a> about the financial assistance distributed through its Paycheck Protection Program. Previously (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-07-08-edition">DIP 2020.07.08</a>), the SBA’s public data withheld the specific amounts for all loans (instead listing only a broad range), as well as names and addresses for loans below $150,000. <a href="https://sba.app.box.com/s/5myd1nxutoq8wxecx2562baruz774si6">The new datasets</a> include those amounts, names, and addresses for all loans.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More on travel/immigration bans.</strong> The <a href="https://covidborderaccountability.org">COVID Border Accountability Project</a> is tracking countries’ pandemic-related travel and immigration restrictions, on a weekly basis. The <a href="https://covidborderaccountability.org/about.html">project’s team</a> categorizes various aspects of the restrictions — whether they hinge on citizenship, halt new visa applications, et cetera — and turns them into <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/U6DJAC">a longitudinal dataset</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/covid-19-global-travel-restrictions-and-airline-information">The UN World Food Program’s travel-restrictions dataset</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-12-09-edition">DIP 2020.12.09</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Third-Republic France.</strong> Economist <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/victorgayeco/">Victor Gay</a> has built <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataverse/TRF-GIS">a geographic dataset</a> that traces, year by year, the administrative boundaries of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Third_Republic">France’s Third Republic</a>, which governed from 1870 to 1940, when the Vichy Regime took power. The dataset <a href="https://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/hal-02951461">provides</a> annual shapefiles delineating the country’s départements, arrondissements, and cantons; as well as for its “most significant special administrative constituencies: military, judicial and penitentiary, electoral, academic, labor inspection, and ecclesiastical.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Cyber wargames.</strong> <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352340920306788">This</a> is, “to the best of our knowledge, [...] the first dataset providing network traffic traces and corresponding event logs from a complex cyber defense exercise” — a two-day <a href="https://csirt.muni.cz/projects/cyber-czech">Cyber Czech</a> event in March 2019.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send cyber feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-12-16-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Enslaved.org, more PPP details, more on travel/immigration bans, Third-Republic France, and cyber wargames.</summary>
    <published>2020-12-16T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-12-09</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.12.09 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-12-09T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Hospital capacity, travel restrictions, the World Factbook, La Pola and her compatriots, and Bob Ross paintings.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 hospital capacity.</strong> On Monday, the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2020/12/07/hhs-publishes-covid-19-hospital-facility-level-data.html">released</a> a <a href="https://healthdata.gov/dataset/covid-19-reported-patient-impact-and-hospital-capacity-facility?">dataset on coronavirus-related capacity at thousands of US hospitals</a> — information the agency previously only published <a href="https://healthdata.gov/dataset/covid-19-reported-patient-impact-and-hospital-capacity-state">as state-level metrics</a>. The self-reported, weekly-updated dataset quantifies various aspects of capacity, such as the number of staffed ICU beds and the number of beds occupied by patients with COVID-19. “This data is tremendously complex and is the result of substantial ongoing efforts,” notes an <a href="https://healthdata.gov/hhs-publishes-covid-19-hospital-facility-level-data">accompanying blog post</a>. “We opted not to have perfect be the enemy of good, so these datasets will have imperfections.” <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/CareSet/COVID_Hospital_PUF">An FAQ</a> “developed in collaboration with a group of data journalists, data scientists, and healthcare system researchers who have reviewed the data.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/rypan/status/1336095555852767233">Ryan Panchadsaram</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pandemic travel restrictions.</strong> The UN World Food Program has been tracking <a href="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/covid-19-global-travel-restrictions-and-airline-information">countries’ and airlines’ travel restrictions during the COVID-19 pandemic</a>, based on official communications, media reports, and other sources. The country-level dataset indicates whether travelers must obtain a recent negative test and what type of quarantine or self-isolation is required. [h/t <a href="https://datainnovation.org/2020/12/documenting-global-travel-restrictions-and-airline-policies/">Cassidy Chansirik</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Country facts.</strong> The CIA’s <a href="https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/">World Factbook</a> “provides information on the history, people and society, government, economy, energy, geography, communications, transportation, military, and transnational issues for 267 world entities.” The details are extensive and fairly standardized. Open data–enthusiast <a href="https://github.com/geraldb">Gerald Bauer</a> has <a href="https://github.com/factbook/factbook.json">converted the publication into a series of JSON files</a>. <strong>Now you know</strong>: The physical areas of five countries (Georgia, Ireland, Latvia, Lithuania, and Sri Lanka) are all described as “slightly larger than West Virginia.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>La Pola and her compatriots.</strong> During Colombia’s struggle for independence, Royalists executed scores of women by shooting squad, the most famous of whom was the seamstress and spy known as “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Policarpa_Salavarrieta">La Pola</a>.” Writing last year for the <a href="https://www.banrepcultural.org/boletin-cultural/">cultural journal</a> of Colombia’s central bank, historian Pablo Rodríguez Jiménez <a href="https://publicaciones.banrepcultural.org/index.php/boletin_cultural/article/view/20880/21278">presented a list of 76 women known to have suffered this fate</a> — their names, locations, and dates of death. Colombia-based Datasketch has <a href="https://www.datasketch.co/datasketch/mujeres-fusiladas-durante-la-independencia-colombiana">converted that list into a spreadsheet</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz">Juan Pablo Marín Díaz</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bob Ross paintings.</strong> Data scientist <a href="https://www.jwilber.me">Jared Wilber</a> has built a dataset of all paintings in Bob Ross’s 31 seasons of “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Joy_of_Painting">The Joy of Painting</a>,” scraped from the <a href="https://www.twoinchbrush.com">searchable database at TwoInchBrush.com</a>. For each painting, the dataset lists the title, season, episode, YouTube link, and list of colors used. For <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/a-statistical-analysis-of-the-work-of-bob-ross/">a 2014 article at FiveThirtyEight</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/WaltHickey">Walt Hickey</a> created a <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/a-statistical-analysis-of-the-work-of-bob-ross/">dataset categorizing the types of things Ross depicted in each episode</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rDs3o1uLEdU">Where Are All the Bob Ross Paintings? We Found Them</a>,” a video from the New York Times. [h/t <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/k2wqax/i_once_found_a_dataset_of_every_paint_used_in/">u/palpitations</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send happy little bits of feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-12-09-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Hospital capacity, travel restrictions, the World Factbook, La Pola and her compatriots, and Bob Ross paintings.</summary>
    <published>2020-12-09T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-12-02</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.12.02 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-12-02T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Student loans, rural facilities in India, more coups, Jefferson’s weather, and integer sequences.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Student loans.</strong> The US Department of Education publishes a range of <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student">aggregate datasets on federal student loans</a>, including the <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student/portfolio">amounts outstanding</a> ($1.5+ trillion overall, from 43 million students), volumes of financial aid <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student/application-volume">requested</a> and <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student/title-iv">awarded</a> (by student demographic and by school), <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student/default">default rates</a>, and <a href="https://studentaid.gov/data-center/student/loan-forgiveness">forgiveness</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Rural facilities in India.</strong> As part of its <a href="http://omms.nic.in/">Pradhan Mantri Gram Sadak Yojana</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pradhan_Mantri_Gram_Sadak_Yojana">road-development program</a>, India’s Ministry of Rural Development has gathered data on 700,000+ rural facilities, which data-science engineer <a href="https://pratapvardhan.com">Pratap Vardhan</a> has <a href="https://github.com/pratapvardhan/rural-facilities-pmgsy">organized into state-level CSV files</a>. The information includes each facility’s name, category (e.g., education, medical, etc.), subcategory, state, district, block, address, and geocoordinates. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/PratapVardhan/status/1332174593877020673">An exploratory Twitter thread by Vardhan</a>, who says, “This is probably the largest open indian geo-tagged dataset I’ve seen!? It’s mostly great!?”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>More coups.</strong> Last month, the University of Illinois’ <a href="https://clinecenter.illinois.edu">Cline Center for Advanced Social Research</a> published version 2.0 of its <a href="https://clinecenter.illinois.edu/project/research-themes/democracy-and-development/coup-detat-project-cdp">Coup D’état Project</a>, a <a href="https://databank.illinois.edu/datasets/IDB-9651987">dataset</a> detailing more than 900 coups, attempted coups, and coup conspiracies from 1945 to 2019. Each entry indicates the country and date, plus the “type of actor who initiated the coup (i.e. military, palace, rebel, etc.) as well as the fate of the deposed executive (killed, injured, exiled, etc.).” <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.jonathanmpowell.com/coup-detat-dataset.html">Powell and Thyne’s coup dataset</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-07-20-edition">DIP 2016.07.20</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Jefferson’s weather.</strong> From July 1776 to June 1826, Thomas Jefferson <a href="https://jefferson-weather-records.org/node/40574">recorded</a> thousands of nearly-daily weather observations — temperatures, precipitations, humidities, wind speeds — at Monticello, Paris, Milan, and scores of other locations. Now <a href="https://jefferson-weather-records.org/node/41011">a UVA/Princeton collaboration</a> has <a href="https://jefferson-weather-records.org/node/40566">turned those handwritten records</a> into an <a href="https://jefferson-weather-records.org/node/40568">explorable</a> and <a href="https://jefferson-weather-records.org/node/41009">downloadable</a> database. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/ecava12/status/1329503730706866179">Erica Cavanaugh</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Integer sequences.</strong> The <a href="https://oeis.org/wiki/Welcome#OEIS:_Brief_History">decades-old</a>, frequently-updated, and <a href="https://oeis.org/wiki/Welcome#Compressed_Versions">downloadable</a> <a href="https://oeis.org/">On-Line Encyclopedia of Integer Sequences</a> contains more than 338,000 lists of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integer_sequence">those things</a>. Each has some particular significance, ranging from the famous (<a href="https://oeis.org/A000045">the Fibonacci numbers</a>) to the intriguing (<a href="https://oeis.org/A007456">“days required to spread gossip to n people”</a>) to the obscure (<a href="https://oeis.org/A056561">“numbers n such that 2^n + 35 is prime”</a>) to the super-obscure. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://xkcd.com/2016/">This xkcd comic</a> and <a href="https://oeis.org/A316600">its impact</a>. [h/t <a href="https://danjbrady.com">Dan Brady</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send sequential feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-12-02-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Student loans, rural facilities in India, more coups, Jefferson’s weather, and integer sequences.</summary>
    <published>2020-12-02T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-11-18</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.11.18 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-11-18T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Global inequality, urban traffic, education and civil rights, state spending on kids, and more urban trees.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Global inequality.</strong> The <a href="https://wid.world/wid-world/">World Inequality Database</a> “aims to provide open and convenient access to the most extensive available database on the historical evolution of the world distribution of income and wealth, both within countries and between countries.” The project, <a href="https://wid.world/team/">co-directed</a> by Thomas Piketty, <a href="https://wid.world/news-article/2020-regional-updates/">published a major update last week</a>, expanding its geographic and temporal coverage. The data points <a href="https://wid.world/summary-table/">vary by country</a>; you can <a href="https://wid.world/data/">download them interactively or in bulk</a>. <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://fsolt.org/">Frederick Solt</a>’s <a href="https://fsolt.org/swiid/">Standardized World Income Inequality Database</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2019-12-04-edition">DIP 2019.12.04</a>) and the United Nations University’s <a href="https://www.wider.unu.edu/project/wiid-world-income-inequality-database">World Income Inequality Database</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-06-01-edition">DIP 2016.06.01</a>).</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Urban traffic.</strong> Researchers from ETH Zurich’s <a href="https://www.ivt.ethz.ch/en/">Institute for Transport Planning and Systems</a> have assembled <a href="https://utd19.ethz.ch/">170 million observations of traffic intensity on urban roads</a>, registered by 23,000+ detection points in 40 cities, “making it the largest multi-city traffic dataset publically available.” The cities are mostly in Western Europe, but also include Tokyo, Taipei, Melbourne, Vilnius, Los Angeles, and Toronto. [h/t <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24405632">ddechamb</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Education and civil rights.</strong> For decades, the US Department of Education’s <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/data.html">Civil Rights Data Collection</a> has compiled “data on key education and civil rights issues in our nation’s public schools,” including “student enrollment and educational programs and services, most of which is disaggregated by race/ethnicity, sex, limited English proficiency, and disability.” Last month, the department <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-releases-2017-18-civil-rights-data-collection">released</a> the <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/crdc-2017-18.html">CRDC for the 2017–18 school year</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: ProPublica has used CRDC data to investigate <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/miseducation/methodology">racial inequality</a> and <a href="https://www.propublica.org/getinvolved/reporting-recipe-investigating-restraint-and-seclusion-in-us-schools">the use of restraints and seclusions</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/wouldeye125">Andrew McCartney</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>State spending on kids.</strong> A <a href="https://datacatalog.urban.org/dataset/state-state-spending-kids-dataset">new dataset</a> from the <a href="https://www.urban.org/">Urban Institute</a> “provides a comprehensive accounting of public spending on children from 1997 through 2016.” Drawing on the US Census Bureau’s <a href="https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/gov-finances.html">Annual Survey of State and Local Government Finances</a> and other sources, the dataset summarizes “state-by-state spending on education, income security, health, and other areas.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/EricaHGreenberg/status/1300540133427613701">Erica Greenberg</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Yet more urban trees.</strong> DIP editions <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-11-16-edition">2016.11.16</a> and <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2018-08-08-edition">2018.08.08</a> featured datasets of trees in NYC and other cities. But wait, there's more: millions of trees in <a href="http://especiales.datasketch.co/arboles-bogota/metodologia.html">Bogotá</a>, <a href="https://opendata.paris.fr/explore/dataset/les-arbres/information/">Paris</a>, <a href="https://www.data.gv.at/katalog/dataset/stadt-wien_baumkatasterderstadtwien">Vienna</a>, <a href="https://maps.amsterdam.nl/bomen/?LANG=en">Amsterdam</a>, <a href="https://hri.fi/data/en_GB/dataset/helsingin-kaupungin-puurekisteri">Helsinki</a>, and <a href="https://data.smartdublin.ie/dataset/trees">Dublin</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jpmarindiaz/status/1324000258452541440">Juan Pablo Marín Díaz</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/anlugonz/status/1323991925708492800">Ana Lucía González</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/ocaoimh/status/1093494467351449600">Cormac O’Keeffe</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/tjukanov/status/1130481172151177217">Topi Tjukanov</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/ttso/status/1192730262993620992">Tuija Sonkkila</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/MartinBangratz/status/1130489730234236929">Martin Bangratz</a> + <a href="https://twitter.com/sannehombroek/status/1130545212386873345">Sanne Hombroek</a> + <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/datasets/comments/br8b32/tree_gps/">u/cavedave</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send leafy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-11-18-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Global inequality, urban traffic, education and civil rights, state spending on kids, and more urban trees.</summary>
    <published>2020-11-18T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-11-11</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.11.11 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-11-11T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Child detention, USPS performance, transit costs, the early Islamic world, and the opera.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Child detention.</strong> The Marshall Project has <a href="https://github.com/themarshallproject/cbp-migrantchildren-detention-data">obtained and published</a> official data from US Customs and Border Protection listing 580,000+ times that the agency detained migrant children since early 2017. For each detention, the dataset <a href="https://observablehq.com/@themarshallproject/cbp-child-detentions-2017-to-2020">includes</a> the date and time the child entered and left CBP custody, as well as the child’s age, gender, and citizenship. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/2020/10/30/500-000-kids-30-million-hours-trump-s-vast-expansion-of-child-detention">The Marshall Project’s report on the data</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>USPS performance.</strong> As part of <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/17449832/jones-v-united-states-postal-service/"><em>Jones v. United States Postal Service</em></a>, a federal lawsuit filed in August, USPS must submit weekly performance reports that indicate, at a national and district level, the percentage of mail that was processed (though not necessarily delivered) on time. The agency files these reports as PDFs; <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/">Save the Post Office</a>, a <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/about/">decade-old website run by a retired English professor</a>, has been <a href="https://www.savethepostoffice.com/updates-on-the-service-performance-reports/">collecting those PDFs</a> and converting them <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1WIiUIu0PP_5D1j8R_-T7IN7kVWk9lvuj">into spreadsheets</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://themail.substack.com/p/crunch-time">Aaron Gordon’s pre-election analysis of the USPS data</a>, from <a href="https://themail.substack.com/">Gordon’s (limited-run) newsletter about the postal service</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Transit costs.</strong> “Why do transit-infrastructure projects in New York cost 20 times more on a per kilometer basis than in Seoul?” With the aim of answering questions like these, the NYU-based <a href="https://transitcosts.com/about/">Transit Costs Project</a> is building <a href="https://transitcosts.com/data/">a dataset</a> that already spans <a href="https://transitcosts.com/projects/">more than 500 urban rail projects</a> around the world. For each project, the dataset specifies the city, start year, end year, rail length, number of stations, total cost, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The early Islamic world.</strong> The <a href="https://althurayya.github.io/">al-Ṯurayyā Project</a> features an interactive map of the early Islamic world, with 2,000 named locations — from Damascus to Baghdad and beyond — and historical routes between them. The <a href="https://github.com/althurayya/althurayya.github.io/tree/master/master">underlying dataset</a> includes geocoordinates, Arabic spellings, transliterations, primary sources, and other details. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/JajRK/status/1299889379817775106">Jajwalya Karajgikar</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The opera.</strong> <a href="https://www.operabase.com/">Operabase</a> has gathered information about more than 500,000 opera performances staged since 1996. The website doesn’t provide direct downloads but you can access <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/8LUFN8">a dataset on six full seasons of stagings</a>, covering thousands of runs in hundreds of cities, thanks to a “data donation” to support <a href="https://ideas.repec.org/e/pcu83.html">Alexander N. Cuntz</a>’s <a href="https://www.wipo.int/publications/en/details.jsp?id=4521">study of how copyright affects performance frequency</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send glass-shattering feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-11-11-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Child detention, USPS performance, transit costs, the early Islamic world, and the opera.</summary>
    <published>2020-11-11T08:00:00-05:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-10-28</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.10.28 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-10-28T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Pregnancy/birth/abortion rates, COVID-19 in ICE facilities, mining areas, e-bike/scooter laws, and witch trials.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Pregnancy, birth, and abortion.</strong> Last month the Guttmacher Institute, a “research and policy organization committed to advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights,” <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/report/pregnancies-births-abortions-in-united-states-1973-2016#">released</a> its <a href="https://osf.io/kthnf/">latest estimates of annual pregnancies, births, and abortions</a> among women in the US — overall, and also by <a href="https://guttinst.github.io/National-State-Pregnancy-Codebook/">age-group and state</a>. The national statistics cover 1973 to 2016, while the state-level numbers go from 1988 to 2016; both sets of estimates are derived from a combination of government data and the institute’s own <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/report/abortion-incidence-service-availability-us-2017">Abortion Provider Census</a>. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/Imaddowzimet/status/1313501719406555138">An introductory Twitter thread</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/Imaddowzimet">Isaac Maddow-Zimet</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>COVID-19 in ICE facilities.</strong> Since late March, US Immigration and Customs Enforcement has been <a href="https://www.ice.gov/coronavirus">updating a webpage</a> that tallies coronavirus cases and deaths at each of its detention facilities. But the site doesn’t provide any historical numbers; it’s just a snapshot. To fill that gap, the <a href="https://www.vera.org/">Vera Institute of Justice</a> has been continually downloading the webpage, parsing it, and <a href="https://github.com/vera-institute/ice-detention-covid">turning the information into structured, longitudinal data</a>. <strong>Related:</strong> Over the summer, <a href="https://www.vera.org/the-hidden-curve-covid-19-in-ice-detention">Vera used the data to estimate “the true scope” of COVID-19 in ICE detention</a>, and called on the agency to provide more detailed statistics.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Mining areas.</strong> A team of academics has built a <a href="https://doi.pangaea.de/10.1594/PANGAEA.910894">dataset</a> and <a href="https://www.fineprint.global/visualisations/viewer/">map</a> indicating the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-020-00624-w">geographic extents of 6,000+ mining sites around the world</a>. The project traces out 21,000+ polygons covering 57,000+ square kilometers, with boundaries based on experts’ visual interpretation of satellite imagery. It focuses on “above-ground features,” such as “open cuts, tailings dams, waste rock dumps, water ponds, and processing infrastructure.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>E-bike and e-scooter laws.</strong> A dataset of <a href="https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/W9NGI2">state regulations pertaining to standard bicycles, electric bicycles, and electric scooters</a> accompanies <a href="https://repository.law.umich.edu/jlm/vol2020/iss1/2/">a recent paper in the Journal of Law and Mobility</a>. It includes various classifications for each state — indicating, for instance, whether riders can use the sidewalk, whether adults must wear helmets, and whether DUI laws apply.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Witch trials.</strong> Some years ago, economists <a href="https://economics.gmu.edu/people/pleeson">Peter T. Leeson</a> and <a href="https://www.jakeruss.com/">Jake Russ</a> compiled a <a href="https://github.com/JakeRuss/witch-trials">dataset of 10,000+ witch trials in Europe</a>. Over the course of 550 years, the trials accused more than 43,000 people and led to 16,000 deaths. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.peterleeson.com/Witch_Trials.pdf">Leeson and Russ’s academic paper analyzing the data</a> (PDF). <strong>Previously</strong>: <a href="https://www.shca.ed.ac.uk/Research/witches/">The Survey of Scottish Witchcraft</a> (<a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2016-01-27-edition">DIP 2016.01.27</a>). [h/t <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/FairWarning/issues/fair-warning-blasts-birdwatchers-and-battleground-states-272882">Sophie Warnes</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send allegedly-wicked feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-10-28-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Pregnancy/birth/abortion rates, COVID-19 in ICE facilities, mining areas, e-bike/scooter laws, and witch trials.</summary>
    <published>2020-10-28T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>dip-2020-10-21</id>
    <title>Data Is Plural — 2020.10.21 edition</title>
    <updated>2020-10-21T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="CDATA"><![CDATA[<p><em>Voting equipment, jail deaths, college athletics, bug bounties, and shrinking salmon.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Voting equipment.</strong> <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/">Verified Voting</a> is “a non-partisan organization focused exclusively on the critical role technology plays in election administration," and its <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/verifier/">Verifier project</a> provides “the only comprehensive data set of voting equipment down to the precinct level of the United States, going back to 2006.” For each election year and jurisdiction, the database indicates the type of technology in use (ranging from hand-counted paper ballots to touchscreen systems), equipment brands and models, and other details, such as whether there is a “voter-verified paper audit trail.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/jonpcohen">Jonathan Cohen</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Jail deaths.</strong> Last week, Reuters published an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-deaths/">investigation into deaths in US jails</a>. Because the federal government doesn’t publish jail-by-jail mortality data, reporters “filed more than 1,500 records requests to obtain information about deaths in 523 U.S. jails – every jail with an average population of 750 or more inmates, and the 10 largest jails or jail systems in nearly every state.” The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-jails-graphic/">resulting dataset</a> contains details about more than 7,500 inmate deaths between 2008 and 2019, including the cause of death, custody status, and demographic information. <strong>Among the findings</strong>: “At least two-thirds of the dead inmates identified by Reuters, 4,998 people, were never convicted of the charges on which they were being held.” [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/grantmeaccess">Grant Smith</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>College athletics.</strong> The <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/finaid/prof/resources/athletics/eada.html">Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act</a> requires thousands of US colleges to provide annual data on athletic particpation, staffing, and finances by team gender and sport. <a href="https://ope.ed.gov/athletics/">School- and team-level datasets</a> are available through the Department of Education for the academic years ending 2003–19. <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/coronavirus-college-football-profit-sec-acc-pac-12-big-ten-millions-fall-2020/">USAFacts recently used the data to examine college football finances</a>. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/sashananderson">Sasha Anderson</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Bug bounties.</strong> Technology companies often offer “bug bounties” — rewards to people who tell them about vulnerabilities in their websites and apps, often coordinated through online platforms. For the past few years, security engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/arkadiyt">Arkadiy Tetelman</a> has been scraping and publishing data about <a href="https://github.com/arkadiyt/bounty-targets-data">the bug bounty “targets” listed on several platforms</a>, including the eligible domains, maximum payouts, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Shrinking salmon.</strong> Scientists <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-17726-z">recently documented</a> “widespread declines in Pacific salmon size based on 60 years of measurements from 12.5 million fish across Alaska,” collected by state officials from more than 1,000 sampling locations. The <a href="https://knb.ecoinformatics.org/view/doi:10.5063/F1707ZTM">underlying dataset</a> lists each salmon’s age, sex, length, and other details where available. [h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/HollyKindsvater/status/1298960157876027394">Holly Kindsvater</a>]</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Dataset suggestions? Criticism? Praise? Send fishy feedback to jsvine@gmail.com, or just reply to this email. Looking for past datasets? <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1wZhPLMCHKJvwOkP4juclhjFgqIY8fQFMemwKL2c64vk">This spreadsheet contains them all</a>. Did a friend forward you this email? <a href="https://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural">Click here to subscribe</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
    <link href="http://tinyletter.com/data-is-plural/letters/data-is-plural-2020-10-21-edition" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Voting equipment, jail deaths, college athletics, bug bounties, and shrinking salmon.</summary>
    <published>2020-10-21T08:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
